[音乐响起--字幕精校中--By Persisan]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
这是CS50，这是第7周。
This is CS50, and this is week 7.
而今天的焦点将完全集中在数据上
And today's focus is going to be entirely on data--
收集过程，存储过程，
the process of collecting it, the process of storing it,
搜索过程等等。
the process of searching it, and so much more.
您会记得，上周我们开始玩耍
You'll recall that last week we started off by playing around
相对较小的数据集。
with the relatively small data set.
我们询问了每个人在霍格沃茨的偏爱之屋可能是什么。
We asked everyone for what their preferred house at Hogwarts might be.
然后我们继续使用一些Python分析该数据
And then we proceeded to analyze that data a little bit using some Python
算出有多少人想要格兰芬多，斯莱特林或其他人，
and counting up how many people wanted Gryffindor or Slytherin or the others,
也一样
as well.
最终，我们通过使用Google表单进行了收集。
And we ultimately did that by using a Google form to collect it.
然后我们将所有数据存储在Google电子表格中，然后
And we stored all of the data in a Google spreadsheet, which we then
导出为CSV文件。
exported, of course, as a CSV file.
因此，本周，我们认为我们将收集更多数据
So this week, we thought we'd collect a little more data
看看什么时候出现什么问题
and see what kinds of problems arise when
我们开始仅使用电子表格或CSV文件
we start using only a spreadsheet or, in turn, a CSV file
存储我们关心的数据。
to store the data that we care about.
因此，事实上，如果您可以继续浏览此网址，您会看到，
So in fact, if you could go ahead and go to this URL here that you see,
您应该会看到另一张Google表单，该表单会询问您
you should see another Google form, this one asking you
一些不同的问题。
some different questions.
现在，我们所有人可能比以往任何时候都拥有一些喜欢的电视节目。
All of us probably have some preferred TV shows, now more than ever, perhaps.
我们想做的就是请大家输入
And what we'd like to do is ask everyone to input
变成他们最喜欢的电视节目，然后是流派
into that form their favorite TV show followed by the genre
或特定电视节目所属的流派。
or genres into which that particular TV show falls.
因此，花点时间来做。
So go ahead and take a moment to do that.
如果您无法在家中跟随，人们正在看什么
And if you're unable to follow along at home, what folks are looking at
是一种很像这里的表格，我们只是问他们
is a form quite like this one here, whereby we're just asking them
他们喜欢的电视节目的标题和类型
for the title of their preferred TV show and the genre
或特定电视节目的类型。
or genres of that specific TV show.
好的。
All right.
因此，让我们继续来看一下其中的一些数据。
So let's go ahead and start to look at some of this data that's come in.
这是Google表单为我们创建的结果Google电子表格。
Here is the resulting Google spreadsheet that Google Forms has created for us.
而且您会注意到，默认情况下，Google表单，此特定工具，
And you'll notice that by default, Google Forms, this particular tool,
至少在此表单中具有三个不同的列。
has three different columns, at least for this form.
一个是时间戳记，Google会自动
One is a timestamp, and Google automatically
根据每个人在哪个日期和时间嗡嗡作响，向我们提供信息
gives us that based on what day and time everyone was buzzing in
与回应。
with the responses.
然后，他们的标题行超出了标题和流派。
Then they have a header row beyond that for title and genres.
为了使它脱颖而出，我已经对其进行了手动粗体标记。
I've manually boldfaced it in advance just to make it stand out.
但您会注意到这里的标题，标题和流派，
But you'll notice that the headings here, Title and Genres,
与我们在Google表单中提出的问题完全匹配。
perfectly matches the question that we asked in the Google form.
因此，我们可以将您的回答与我们的问题保持一致。
That allows us to therefore line up your responses with our questions.
您可以在这里看到Punisher是第一部最喜欢的电视
And you can see here Punisher was the first favorite TV
待输入的节目，接着是The Office，Breaking Bad，New Girl，Archer，
show to be inputted followed by The Office, Breaking Bad, New Girl, Archer,
另一个办公室，依此类推。
another Office, and so forth.
在第三栏的“类型”下，您将
And in the third column, under Genres, you'll
看到这里有些奇怪。
see that there's something curious here.
虽然某些单元格-
While some of the cells--
也就是说，一小盒文字-
that is, the little boxes of text--
只有一个单词，例如“喜剧”或“戏剧”，
have just single words like "comedy" or "drama,"
您会注意到其中有些列表以逗号分隔。
you'll notice that some of them have a comma-separated list.
这个逗号分隔的列表是因为你们中的一些人尽可能地检查了一下，
And that comma-separated list is because some of you checked, as you could,
多个复选框以表明Breaking Bad是犯罪类型
multiple check boxes to indicate that Breaking Bad is a crime genre
戏剧和惊悚片。
drama and also thriller.
因此，在某种意义上，Google表单处理此问题的方式有点偷偷摸摸
And so the way Google Forms handles this is a bit sleazily in the sense
他们只是将所有这些值作为逗号分隔的列表
that they just drop all of those values as a comma-separated list
在电子表格本身中。
inside of the spreadsheet itself.
如果我们最终下载，那将是一个潜在的问题
And that's potentially a problem if we ultimately download
此为CSV文件，逗号分隔的值，
this as a CSV file, comma-separated values,
因为现在您在逗号之间有逗号。
because now you have commas in between the commas.
幸运的是，我们最终将看到一个解决方案。
Fortunately, there's a solution to that that we'll ultimately see.
因此，这里有大量数据。
So we've got a good amount of data here.
实际上，如果我继续向下滚动，我们现在将看到数百个响应。
In fact, if I keep scrolling down, we'll see a few hundred responses now.
并以某种方式分析这些数据将是很好的
And it would be nice to analyze this data in some way
找出最流行的电视节目是什么，也许搜索新节目
and figure out what the most popular TV show is, maybe search for new shows
我可能喜欢通过他们的类型。
I might like via their genre.
因此，您可以想象一些查询可以
So you can imagine some number of queries that could
通过此数据集进行回答。
be answered by way of this data set.
但首先让我们考虑保留此数据的局限性
But let's first consider the limitations of leaving this data
在这样的电子表格中。
in just a spreadsheet like this.
我们所有人都可能养成偶尔使用的习惯
All of us are probably in the habit of using occasionally
Google Spreadsheets，Apple Numbers，Microsoft Excel或其他工具。
Google Spreadsheets, Apple Numbers, Microsoft Excel, or some other tool.
因此，让我们考虑一下哪些电子表格擅长，哪些擅长。
So let's consider what spreadsheets are good at and what they are bad at.
有人愿意自愿回答第一个问题吗？
Would anyone like to volunteer an answer to the first of those?
电子表格的优点是什么？
What is a spreadsheet good at or good for?
是的，安德鲁？
Yeah, Andrew?
您对电子表格有何想法？
What's your thinking on spreadsheets?
观众：[听不清]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
DAVID J. MALAN：好的，非常适合快速排序。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, very good for quickly sorting.
我喜欢。
I like that.
例如，我可以单击“标题”列的顶部，
I could click on the top of the Title column, for instance,
然后立即按字母顺序对所有这些标题进行排序。
and immediately sort all of those titles by alphabetically.
我喜欢。
I like that.
使用电子表格的其他原因-它们可以解决什么问题？
Other reasons to use a spreadsheet-- what problems do they solve?
他们擅长什么？
What are they good at?
有关电子表格的其他想法。
Other thoughts on spreadsheets.
是的，彼得呢？
Yeah, how about Peter?
听众：存储大量数据，以便以后进行分析。
AUDIENCE: Storing large amounts of data that you can later analyze.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的，所以要大量存储
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, so storing large amounts
您以后可以分析的数据。
of data that you can later analyze.
可以这么说，这是一种用于存储大量数据行的好模型。
It's kind of a nice model for storing lots of rows of data, so to speak.
我会说实际上是有限制的。
I will say that there actually is a limit.
实际上，回想过去，这是什么限制。
And in fact, back in the day, I learned what this limit is.
长话短说，在研究生院，我正在使用电子表格
Long story short, in graduate school, I was using a spreadsheet
分析一些研究数据。
to analyze some research data.
有一次，我的数据比Excel支持的行多。
And at one point, I had more data than Excel supported rows for.
具体来说，我有65,536行，
Specifically, I had some 65,536 rows, which
当时对于Excel来说太多了，
was too many at that point for Excel at the time,
因为长话短说，如果您从电子表格程序中回想起
because, long story short, if you recall from a spreadsheet program
像Google Spreadsheets一样，每一行都从1开始编号。
like Google Spreadsheets, every row is numbered from 1 on up.
好吧，不幸的是，在当时，微软
Well, unfortunately, at the time, Microsoft
使用了16位整数，16位或2个字节，
had used a 16-bit integer, 16 bits or 2 bytes,
代表每个数字。
to represent each of those numbers.
结果表明2到16的幂大约为65,000。
And it turns out the 2 to the 16th power is roughly 65,000.
因此，在那一点上，我使行的总数最大化。
So at that point, I maxed out the total number of rows.
现在，以Peter的观点来说，最近几年他们已经增加了这一点。
Now, to Peter's point, they've increased that in recent years.
实际上，您可以存储更多数据。
And you can actually store a lot more data.
因此，电子表格确实擅长于此。
So spreadsheets are indeed good at that.
但是他们不一定在所有方面都擅长，因为在某些时候，
But they're not necessarily good at everything, because at some point,
您将在电子表格中拥有更多数据
you're going to have more data potentially in a spreadsheet
超出Mac或PC所能承受的范围。
than your Mac or PC can handle.
实际上，如果您实际上是在尝试构建应用程序，
In fact, if you're actually trying to build an application, whether it's
Twitter，Instagram或Facebook或任何规模的东西，
Twitter, Instagram, or Facebook or anything of that scale,
这些公司肯定没有存储他们的数据，可以这样说：
those companies are certainly not storing their data, suffice it to say,
在电子表格中，因为只会有太多的数据要使用。
in a spreadsheet, because there would just be way too much data to use.
而且没有人能从他们的计算机上真正打开它。
And no one could literally open it on their computer.
因此，我们需要解决规模问题的方法。
So we'll need a solution to that problem of scale.
但是我认为我们不需要抛弃那些对电子表格有效的方法。
But I don't think we need to throw out what works well about spreadsheets.
因此，您确实可以以行形式存储大量数据。
So you can store indeed a lot of data in row form.
但是似乎您也可以以列的形式存储大量数据。
But it would seem that you can also store a lot of data in column form.
即使我只显示A，B和C列，
And even though I'm only showing columns A, B, and C,
当然，您可能已经使用过电子表格
of course, you've probably used spreadsheets
在其中添加更多列-
where you add more columns--
D，E，F等。
D, E, F, and so forth.
那么如何思考行的正确心智模型是什么
So what's the right mental model for how to think about rows
与电子表格中的列？
versus columns in a spreadsheet?
我觉得我们可能在概念上以某种不同的方式使用它们。
I feel like we probably use them in a somewhat different way conceptually.
我们可能会有所不同。
We might think about them a little differently.
电子表格中的行和列有什么区别？
What's the difference between rows and columns in a spreadsheet?
苏菲亚。
Sofia.
听众：添加更多条目。
AUDIENCE: Adding more entries.
添加更多数据是-
Adding more data is--
这些在行内，但随后是实际属性或特征
those are within the rows, but then the actual attributes or characteristics
的数据应在列中。
of the data should be in columns.
戴维·J·马兰（David J. MALAN）：好的。
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly.
当您向电子表格中添加更多数据时，
When you add more data to the spreadsheet,
您真的应该添加到它的底部，
you should really be adding to the bottom of it,
添加越来越多的行。
adding more and more rows.
所以这些事情在垂直方向上是增长的，尽管那当然是
So these things sort of grow vertically, even though of course that's
只是人类对它的感知。
just a human's perception of it.
它们通过添加越来越多的行从上到下增长。
They grow from top to bottom by adding more and more rows.
但就索非亚而言，您的专栏代表
But to Sofia's point, your columns represent
我们可以称之为属性或字段或其他任何此类特征的东西
what we might call attributes or fields or any other such characteristic that
是您要存储的一种数据。
is a type of data that you're storing.
因此，在我们的表格中，时间戳是第一列。
So in this case of our form, Timestamp is the first column.
标题是第二列。
Title is the second column.
类别是第三列。
Genres is the third column.
那些列确实可以被认为是字段或属性，属性
And those columns can indeed be thought of as fields or attributes, properties
您的数据。
of your data.
这些是您真正应该事先决定的属性
And those are properties that you should really decide on in advance when you're
在我们的情况下，或者在您手动创建表单时，首先创建表单
first creating the form, in our case, or when you're manually creating
在另一种情况下，电子表格。
the spreadsheet in another case.
你不应该真正养成习惯
You should not really be in the habit, when
使用电子表格，从左侧添加数据
using spreadsheets, of adding data from left
在右边，添加越来越多的列，除非您
to right, adding more and more columns, unless you
决定收集更多类型的数据。
decide to collect more types of data.
因此，仅因为有人将新的喜爱的电视节目添加到您的数据集中，
So just because someone adds a new favorite TV show to your data set,
您不应该在新列中从左到右添加该内容。
you shouldn't be adding that from left to right in a new column.
您确实应该从上至下添加它。
You should indeed be adding it from top to bottom.
但是，假设我们实际上决定从每个人那里收集更多信息。
But suppose that we actually decided to collect more information from everyone.
可能是该表格要求您输入姓名或电子邮件地址
Maybe that form had instead asked you for your name or your email address
或其他任何问题。
or any other questions.
这些属性，属性或字段将属于新列。
Those properties or attributes or fields would belong as new columns.
这就是说我们通常决定数据的布局，
So this is to say we generally decide on the layout of our data,
预先显示我们的数据模式。
the schema of our data, in advance.
然后从那开始，我们继续添加，添加，添加更多行，而不是
And then from there on out, we proceed to add, add, add more rows, not
专栏，除非我们改变主意并需要改变
columns, unless we change our mind and need to change
我们特定数据的架构。
the schema of our particular data.
事实证明，电子表格确实非常有用，
So it turns out that spreadsheets are indeed wonderfully useful,
到彼得的观点，无论是大的还是相当大的
to Peter's point, for large or reasonably large
我们可能收集的数据集。
data sets that we might collect.
当然，我们可以每个星期将这些数据集导出为CSV文件。
And we can, of course, per last week, export those data sets as CSV files.
这样我们就可以从电子表格转到简单文本
And so we can go from a spreadsheet to a simple text
通常，以ASCII或Unicode格式存储在您自己的硬盘上的文件
file stored in ASCII or Unicode, more generally, on your own hard drive
或云中的某个地方。
or somewhere in the cloud.
您实际上可以想到该文件，.CSV文件，
And you can actually think of that file, that .CSV file,
就像我们所说的平面文件数据库一样。
as what we might call a flat-file database.
一般来说，数据库是存储数据的文件。
A database is, generally speaking, a file that stores data.
或它是一个为您存储数据的程序。
Or it's a program that stores data for you.
而且我们所有人都可能在某种意义上考虑或使用过数据库。
And all of us have probably thought about or used databases in some sense.
您可能熟悉以下事实：
You're probably familiar with the fact that all
那些大型网站（例如Google，Twitter和Facebook等）使用
of those same big websites, Google and Twitter and Facebook and others, use
数据库来存储我们的数据。
databases to store our data.
好吧，那些数据库或者只是
Well, those databases are either just really
包含大量数据或特殊程序的大文件
big files containing lots of data or special programs
正在为我们存储数据。
that are storing our data for us.
平面文件只是指事实
And a flat file is just referring to the fact
这确实是一个非常简单的设计。
that it really is a very simple design.
实际上，几年前，几十年前，人类决定
In fact, years ago, decades ago, humans decided
当将数据存储在简单的文本文件中时，如果
when storing data in simple text files that if you
想要存储不同类型的数据，例如，索非亚
want to store different types of data, like, to Sofia's point,
不同的属性或属性，让我们保持简单。
different properties or attributes, well, let's keep it simple.
让我们用逗号分隔这些列
Let's just separate those columns with commas
在我们的平面文件数据库中
in our flat-file database, a.k.a.
CSV。
a CSV.
您可以使用其他东西。
You can use other things.
您可以使用标签。
You can use tabs.
对于制表符分隔的值，有一种称为TSV的东西。
There's things called TSVs, for Tab-Separated Values.
坦白说，您可以使用任何您想要的东西。
And frankly, you can use anything you want.
但是有一个极端的情况。
But there is a corner case.
而且我们已经看到了它的预览。
And we've already seen a preview of it.
如果您的实际数据中包含逗号怎么办？
What if your actual data has a comma in it?
如果您喜欢的电视节目的标题带有逗号怎么办？
What if the title of your favorite TV show has a comma?
如果Google假设将类型存储为以逗号分隔的列表怎么办？
What if Google is presuming to store genres as a comma-separated list?
如果将CSV用作平面文件数据库，可能会发生不好的事情。
Bad things can happen if using a CSV as your flat-file database.
但是有解决方案。
But there are solutions to that.
实际上，世界通常会做什么
And in fact, what the world typically does
每当您在CSV文件中包含逗号时，
is whenever you have commas inside of your CSV file,
您只需确保整个字符串是双精度的
you just make sure that the whole string is double
在最左边和最右边引用。
quoted on the far left and far right.
而且双引号内的任何内容都不是
And anything inside of double quotes is not
此后被误认为是描绘一列
mistaken thereafter as delineating a column
就像文件中的其他逗号一样。
as the other commas in the file might.
这就是平面文件数据库的全部含义。
So that's all that's meant by a flat-file database.
CSV可能是最常见，最常见的格式之一
And CSV is perhaps one of the most common, the most common, formats
如果仅仅是因为所有这些程序，
thereof, if only because all of these programs,
例如Google Spreadsheets和Excel and Numbers，
like Google Spreadsheets and Excel and Numbers,
允许您将文件另存为CSV。
allow you to save your files as CSVs.
长话短说，现在
Now, long story short, those of you who have
电子表格的高级功能，例如内置函数和公式
used fancier features of spreadsheets like built-in functions and formulas
那些东西，那些是内置的
and those kinds of things, those are built in
并且是Google Spreadsheets，Excel和Numbers专有的。
and proprietary to Google Spreadsheets and Excel and Numbers.
您不能在CSV文件或TSV文件或平面文件数据库中使用公式，
You cannot use formulas in a CSV file or a TSV file or in a flat-file database,
更普遍。
more generally.
您只能存储静态-
You can only store static--
也就是说，不变的价值观。
that is, unchanging-- values.
因此，当您导出数据时，所见即所得。
So when you export the data, what you see is what you get.
这就是为什么人们使用更高级的程序
And that's why people use fancier programs
例如Excel，Numbers和Google Spreadsheets，
like Excel and Numbers and Google Spreadsheets,
因为您可以获得更多功能。
because you get more functionality.
但是，如果要导出数据，则只能
But if you want to export the data, you can only
确实从中获取原始文本数据。
get indeed the raw textual data out of it.
但是我敢说那会没事的。
But I daresay that's going to be OK.
其实，布莱恩，你介意我继续吗
In fact, Brian, do you mind if I go ahead
并立即以CSV文件格式下载此电子表格？
and download this spreadsheet as a CSV file now?
布莱恩·于：是的，继续。
BRIAN YU: Yep, go ahead.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
我将继续使用Google Spreadsheets，然后转到“文件，下载”。
I'm going to go ahead in Google Spreadsheets and go to File, Download.
您会看到很多选择-
And you can see a whole bunch of options--
PDF，网页，逗号分隔值，这是我想要的值。
PDF, Web Page, Comma-Separated Values, which is the one I want.
所以我确实要继续选择CSV
So I'm going to indeed go ahead and choose CSV
从电子表格中的此下拉菜单中。
from this dropdown in spreadsheets.
那当然是为我下载了该文件。
That, of course, downloaded that file for me.
现在，我将继续进入我们熟悉的CS50 IDE。
And now I'm going to go ahead and go into our familiar CS50 IDE.
您会记得，上周我能够将文件上传到IDE。
You'll recall that last week I was able to upload a file into the IDE.
我也将继续在本周在这里进行相同的操作。
And I'm going to go ahead and do the same here this week, as well.
我将继续获取我的文件，该文件最终在我的下载中
I'm going to go ahead and grab my file, which ended up in my Downloads
我的特定计算机上的文件夹。
folder on my particular computer here.
我将继续将其拖放到IDE中
And I'm going to go ahead and drag and drop this into the IDE
这样它就可以存储在我的主目录中。
such that it ends up in my home directory, so to speak.
所以现在我有了这个文件，“我的最爱电视节目表”。
So now I have this file, Favorite TV Shows Forms.
实际上，如果我在IDE中双击它，
And in fact, if I double click this within the IDE,
您现在将看到熟悉的数据。
you'll see familiar data now.
时间戳逗号标题逗号流派是我们的标题行
Timestamp comma title comma genres is our header row
包含此文件中属性或属性的名称。
that contains the names of the properties or attributes in this file.
然后我们得到了时间戳记逗号最喜欢的标题逗号，然后
Then we've got our timestamps comma favorite title comma and then
以逗号分隔的流派列表。
a comma-separated list of genres.
确实在这里，请注意Google小心了
And here indeed, notice that Google took care
对自己有逗号的任何值使用双引号。
to use double quotes around any values that themselves had commas.
因此，这是一种相对简单的文件格式。
So it's a relatively simple file format.
我当然可以略过这件事，
And I could certainly just kind of skim through this,
找出谁喜欢办公室，谁喜欢Breaking Bad或其他节目。
figuring out who likes The Office, who likes Breaking Bad, or other shows.
但是上周，我们现在有了一种非常有用的编程语言
But per last week, we now have a pretty useful programming language
我们可以使用Python，这可以让我们开始进行操作
at our disposal, Python, that could allow us to start manipulating
并更容易地分析这些数据。
and analyzing this data more readily.
上周，我要讲的是使用正确的工具完成这项工作，
And here to my point last week about using the right tool for the job,
您绝对可以在CS50之前的所有星期中完成我们将要做的所有事情。
you could absolutely do everything we're about to do in all weeks prior of CS50.
我们本来可以用C做的。
We could have used C for what we're about to do.
但是，正如您可能会发现的那样，C在某些方面往往会很痛苦，
But as you can probably glean, C tends to be painful for certain things,
就像涉及字符串操作的任何事物一样，
like anything involving string manipulation,
更改字符串，分析字符串。
changing strings, analyzing strings.
真是痛苦，对吧？
It's just a real pain, right?
上帝禁止您必须将此CSV文件并将其全部加载到内存中，而不是
God forbid you had to take this CSV file and load it all into memory, not
不像您的拼写检查器。
unlike your spell checker.
您将不得不在各处使用malloc或重新分配等。
You would have to be using malloc all over the place or realloc or the like.
仅分析文本文件就涉及很多繁重的工作。
There's just a lot of heavy lifting involved in just analyzing a text file.
因此，Python仅通过给我们提供了所有这些功能
So Python does all of that for us by just giving us
我们可以使用更多功能
more functions at our disposal with which
开始分析和打开数据。
to start analyzing and opening data.
因此，让我继续关闭该文件。
So let me go ahead and close this file.
让我继续创建一个新的文件夹，收藏夹。
And let me go ahead and create a new one called favorites.py,
其中我将开始使用该数据集
wherein I'm going to start playing with this data set
看看我们是否无法开始回答一些有关它的问题。
and see if we can't start answering some questions about it.
坦白说，直到今天，学习了20多年
And frankly, to this day, 20-plus years after learning how
第一次编程，我自己是
to program for the first time, I myself am
编写刚开始的新程序时非常习惯
very much in the habit when writing a new program of just starting simple
并没有解决我最终想要解决的问题，只是简单一些
and not solving the problem I ultimately want to but something simpler just
作为一种概念证明，以确保
as a sort of proof of concept to make sure
我有正确的管道。
I have the right plumbing in place.
因此，我的意思是这个。
So by that, I mean this.
让我们继续编写一个简单的程序，简单地打开该文件CSV
Let's go ahead and write a quick program that simply opens up this file, the CSV
文件，从上到下对其进行迭代，然后仅打印出每个标题，
file, iterates over it top to bottom, and just prints out each of the titles,
就像快速的理智检查一样，我知道我在做什么
just as a quick sanity check that I know what I'm doing
并且我可以访问其中的数据。
and I have access to the data therein.
因此，让我继续导入CSV。
So let me go ahead and import CSV.
然后，我可以通过几种不同的方式来做到这一点。
And then I can do this in a few different ways.
但是到现在为止，您可能已经看到或记住了
But by now, you've probably seen or remembered
我使用诸如open命令和
my using something like the open command and the
用关键字打开，并最终自动为我关闭此文件。
with keyword to open and eventually automatically close this file for me.
此文件称为“喜爱的电视节目-表单响应1.csv”。
This file is called Favorite TV Shows - Form Responses 1.csv.
我将以读取模式打开它。
And I'm going to open this up in read mode.
严格来说，r不是必需的。
Strictly speaking, the r is not required.
您可能会在网上看到一些不包含示例的示例。
You might see examples online not including it.
那是因为read是默认的。但是为了与C和fopen保持一致，
That's because read is the default. But for parity with C and fopen,
我将明确指出并实际执行“ r”。
I'm going to be explicit and actually do "r."
我将继续给这个文件起一个可变的名称。
And I'm going to go ahead and give this a variable name of file.
因此，此处的第3行具有以只读模式打开该CSV文件的效果
So this line 3 here has the effect of opening that CSV file in read-only mode
并创建一个名为file的变量，我可以通过该变量引用它。
and creating a variable called file via which I can reference it.
现在，我将继续使用一些CSV功能。
Now I'm going to go ahead and use some of that CSV functionality.
我要给自己，我们一直在称呼读者，
I'm going to give myself what we keep calling a reader, which
我可以称它为xyz，还有其他任何东西。
I could call it xyz, anything else.
但是“阅读器”类型描述了此变量将要执行的操作。
But "reader" kind of describes what this variable is going to do.
这将是在该文件上调用csv.reader的返回值。
And it's going to be the return value of calling csv.reader on that file.
因此，从本质上讲，上周的CSV库
And so essentially, the CSV library, per last week,
具有很多内置的精美功能。
has a lot of fancy features built in.
输入所需的只是一个已打开的文本文件。
And all it needs as input is an already opened text file.
然后它将包装该文件，可以这么说，
And then it will then wrap that file, so to speak,
还有很多更有用的功能，
with a whole bunch of more useful functionality,
喜欢一次读取列和行的功能。
like the ability to read it column and row at a time.
好的。
All right.
现在，我要继续前进，您知道吗，就目前而言，
Now I'm going to go ahead and, you know what, just for now,
我将跳过第一行。
I'm going to skip the first row.
我将跳过第一行，因为第一行有我的标题-
I'm going to skip the first row, because the first row has my headings--
时间戳，标题和类型。
Timestamp, Title, and Genres.
而且我知道我的专栏是什么，所以我现在暂时忽略该行。
And I know what my columns are, so I'm just going to ignore that line for now.
现在，我要执行此操作。
And now I'm going to do this.
对于排入阅读器，让我继续并简单地打印出排。
For row in reader, let me go ahead and print out, quite simply, row.
我只想要标题，所以我想如果是从左到右的三列，
And I only want title, so I think if it's three columns from left to right,
它是0、1、2
it's 0, 1, 2.
所以我想打印出列支架1
So I want to print out column bracket 1, which
将成为第二列零索引。
is going to be the second column zero indexed.
好的。
All right.
让我继续保存，下至我的终端窗口，
Let me go ahead and save that, go down to my terminal window,
并运行“ favourites.py”的python，然后用手指交叉。
and run python of favorites.py and cross my fingers.
好的。
OK.
瞧。
Voila.
它飞得很快。
It flew by super fast.
但是看起来，确实，这些都是电视
But it looks like, indeed, these are all of the TV
表明人们已经输入了。
shows that folks have inputted.
确实，如果我继续向上滚动，会有几百个。
Indeed, there's a few hundred if I keep scrolling up.
因此，看来我的程序正在运行。
So it looks like my program is working.
但是，让我们对其进行一些改进。
But let's improve it just a little bit.
原来，使用csv.reader并不一定
It turns out that using the csv.reader isn't necessarily
Python中最好的方法。
the best approach in Python.
你们中的许多人已经发现DictReader，字典阅读器，
Many of you have already discovered a DictReader, a dictionary reader,
很好，因为这样您就不必知道或重复检查
which is nice, because then you don't have to know or keep double checking
您的数据在哪个数字列中。
what number column your data is in.
您可以改为通过标头本身来引用它，因此可以通过“标题”来引用它
You can instead refer it to by the header itself, so by "title"
或按“类型”。
or by "genres."
这也很好，因为如果您或您的同事
This is also good, because if you or maybe a colleague
被电子表格弄得乱七八糟
are sort of messing around with the spreadsheet
他们通过向左或向右拖动来重新排列列，
and they rearrange the columns by dragging them left or right,
您在代码中使用的任何数字，0、1、2及以上，
any numbers you have used in your code, 0, 1, 2 on up,
如果您的同事重新排序了这些列，则可能突然不正确。
could suddenly be incorrect if your colleague has reordered those columns.
因此，使用字典阅读器往往会更健壮，因为它
So using a dictionary reader tends to be a little more robust, because it
使用标题，而不是单纯的数字。
uses the titles, not the mere numbers.
如果有人，您自己或其他人仍然会犯错误，
It's still fallible if someone, yourself or someone else,
更改第一行中的值，并重命名标题或体裁。
changes the values in that very first row and renames titles or genres.
然后事情会破裂。
Then things are going to break.
但在那一点上，我们一定要怪你
But at that point, we kind of have to blame you
因为没有跟踪您的代码和数据。
for not having kept track of your code versus your data.
但是仍然有风险。
But still a risk.
因此，我将在这里将其更改为字典阅读器或DictReader。
So I'm going to change this to dictionary reader or DictReader here.
几乎我其余的代码可以相同
And pretty much the rest of my code can be the same
除非我在第5行上不需要此hack。
except I don't need this hack here on line 5.
我不需要一开始就跳到下一行，
I don't need to just skip over to the next row from the get-go,
因为我现在希望字典阅读器处理阅读过程
because I now want the dictionary reader to handle the process of reading
我的第一行。
that first row for me.
但是否则，其他所有东西都保持不变
But otherwise, everything else stays the same
除了最后一行，我现在认为
except for this last line, where now I think
我现在可以将row用作字典，而不能用作列表本身，
I can now use row as a dictionary, not as a list per se,
并从每个给定的行中专门打印出标题。
and print out specifically the title from each given row.
因此，让我继续运行，再次运行python of favorite.py。
So let me go ahead and run python of favorites.py again.
瞧，我得到了相同的结果，其中有数百个。
And voila, it looks like I got the same result, several hundred of them.
但我要指出的是，如果我们实际上
But let me stipulate that it's doing the same thing if we actually
并排比较了两者。
compared both of those side-by-side.
好的。
All right.
在我继续前进之前，先进行实际的扩充
Before I forge ahead now to actually augment this
新功能，对此Python脚本有任何疑问或困惑
with new functionality, any questions or confusion on this Python script
我们只是写了一个打开文件的文件，用阅读器或DictReader包装它，
we just wrote to open a file, wrap it with a reader or DictReader,
然后一次遍历行，打印标题？
and then iterate over the rows one at a time, printing the titles?
有任何疑问，对语法完全困惑吗？
Any questions, confusion on syntax at all?
没关系。
It's OK.
我们只认识或见过Python一个星期。
We've only known or seen Python for a week.
如果还很新，那很好。
It's fine if it's still quite new.
什么，布莱恩，我们应该解决？
Anything, Brian, we should address?
布莱恩·于：是的。
BRIAN YU: Yeah.
那么为什么不需要使用语法关闭文件呢？
So why is it that you don't need to close the file using the syntax
您正在这里使用吗？
that you're using right here?
DAVID J. MALAN：很好的问题。
DAVID J. MALAN: Really good question.
上周，我更自学地使用了open。
Last week, I more pedantically used open on its own.
然后我后来使用了与文件关联的关闭函数
And then I later used a close function that was associated with the file
我刚打开的。
that I had just opened.
现在，如果您愿意，可以使用更Python化的方式来做事，
Now, the more Pythonic way to do things, if you will,
实际上是将它与关键字一起使用，这在C语言中是不存在的。
is actually to use this with keyword, which didn't exist in C.
而且它只是在Python中往往是有用的功能
And it just tends to be a useful feature in Python
这样，如果您以打开的句点表示，它将为您打开文件。
whereby if you say with open, dot dot dot, it will open the file for you.
然后，只要您的代码缩进其中，它就会保持打开状态
Then it will remain open so long as your code is indented inside
与关键字块。
of that with keywords block.
程序结束后，
And as soon as you get to the end of your program,
它将自动为您关闭。
it will automatically be closed for you.
因此，这是Python在某种意义上的其中一项功能
So this is one of these features where Python in some sense
试图保护我们免受自己的伤害。
is trying to protect us from ourselves.
对于我本人来说，这可能很常见
It's probably pretty common for humans, myself
包括，忘记关闭文件。
included, to forget to close your file.
这可能会带来永久保存问题。
That can create problems with saving things permanently.
正如我们从C中了解到的那样，它可能导致内存泄漏。
It can create memory leaks, as we know from C.
所以with关键字只是假设我不会成为白痴
So the with keyword just assumes that I'm not going to be an idiot
忘记关闭文件了。
and forget to close the file.
Python会自动为我完成此操作。
Python is going to do it for me automatically.
其他问题或困惑，布莱恩？
Other questions or confusions, Brian?
布莱恩·于（Brian Yu）：DictReader如何知道该标题
BRIAN YU: How does DictReader know that Title
里面的键名是什么？
is the name of the key inside of the dictionary?
DAVID J. MALAN：真的是一个很好的问题。
DAVID J. MALAN: Really good question, too.
因此它是由Python语言的作者设计的
So it is designed by the authors of the Python language
看文件的第一行，
to look at the very first row in the file,
在第一行的逗号中将其拆分，
split it on the commas in that very first row,
并假设第一个逗号之前的第一个单词或短语
and just assume that the first word or phrase before the first comma
是第一列的名称，第二个单词
is the name of the first column, that the second word
第一个逗号之后的词组或短语是第二列的名称，
or phrase after the first comma is the name of the second column,
等等。
and so forth.
因此，就像CSV的惯例一样，DictReader只是一种假设，
So a DictReader just presumes, as is the convention with CSVs,
您的第一行将包含您的标题
that your first row is going to contain the headings that you
想使用来引用那些列。
want to use to refer to those columns.
如果您的CSV恰好没有这样的标题，
If your CSV happens not to have such a heading whereby it just
在第一行跳到真实数据，
jumps right in on the first row to real data,
那么至少您将无法正确使用DictReader
then you're not going to be able to use a DictReader correctly, at least
并非没有一些手动配置。
not without some manual configuration.
好的。
All right.
所以，让我们继续-
So let's go ahead and--
现在我觉得这里真是一团糟。
now I feel like there's a whole mess here.
其中一些节目非常受欢迎。
And some of these shows are pretty popular.
当我浏览此内容时，我肯定会看到一些重复。
And as I'm glancing over this, I definitely see some duplication.
一大群人喜欢The Office。
A whole bunch of you like The Office.
你们所有人都喜欢《绝命毒师》，《权力的游戏》，
A whole bunch of you like Breaking Bad, Game of Thrones,
还有很多其他节目
and a whole bunch of other shows, as well.
我想，如果我们做些更好的话，那会更好
So it would be nicer, I think, if we kind of
仅查看唯一值即可缩小我们查看此数据的范围。
narrow the scope of our look at this data by just looking at unique values.
您正在寻找独特的价值。
You're looking at unique value.
因此，不只是从头到尾遍历文件，
So rather than just iterate over the file top to bottom,
逐个打印一个标题，为什么
printing out one title after another, why
我们不继续收集所有这些数据
don't we go ahead and sort of accumulate all of this data
在某种数据结构中，这样我们就可以丢弃重复的值
in some kind of data structure so that we can throw away duplicate values
然后只打印出我们累积的唯一标题？
and then only print out the unique titles that we've accumulated?
所以我敢打赌，我们可以通过几种方式做到这一点。
So I bet we can do this in a few ways.
但是，如果我们回想一下上周对字典的演示，
But if we think back to last week's demonstration of our dictionary,
您会记得我使用了所谓的集合。
you'll recall that I used what was called a set.
我将继续创建一个名为title的变量
And I'm going to go ahead and create a variable called titles
并将其设置为等于“ set”的值。
and set it equal to something called set.
集合只是价值的集合。
And a set is just a collection of values.
有点像清单。
It's kind of like a list.
但这为我消除了重复。
But it eliminates duplicates for me.
这似乎恰好是特征
And that would seem to be exactly the characteristic
我想要这个程序。
that I want for this program.
现在，而不是打印每个标题，现在为时过早
Now, instead of printing each title, which is now premature
如果我想先过滤掉重复项，
if I want to first filter out duplicates,
我将继续执行此操作。
I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我将继续使用添加功能将其添加到标题集中
I'm going to go ahead and add to the titles set using the add function
当前行的标题。
the current row's title.
再说一次，我现在不打印它。
So again, I'm not printing it now.
我改为在标题集中添加该特定标题。
I'm instead adding to the title set that particular title.
如果已经存在，没什么大不了的。
And if it's there already, no big deal.
Python中的设置数据结构正在发展
The set data structure in Python is going
为我扔掉重复的东西。
to throw away the duplicates for me.
而且只会继续保持唯一性。
And it's only going to go ahead and keep the uniques.
现在，诚然，在文件的底部，我需要做更多的工作。
Now, at the bottom of my file, I need to do a little more work, admittedly.
现在，我必须遍历该集合以仅打印那些唯一的标题。
Now I have to iterate over the set to print out only those unique titles.
因此，让我这样做。
So let me do this.
对于标题中的标题，请继续并打印标题。
For title in titles, go ahead and print out title.
这就是Python真正变得易于使用的地方了吧？
And this is where Python just gets really user-friendly, right?
你不必做int我得到0，我小于n，或其他。
You don't have to do int i get 0, i less than n, or whatever.
您只能在标题中说出标题。
You can just say for title in titles.
如果标题的变量是数据结构的类型
And if the title's variable is the type of data structure
您可以遍历的列表（如果是列表或集合）
that you can iterate over, which it will be if it's a list or if it's a set
甚至是字典，也可以是另一种数据结构
or even if it's a dictionary, another data structure
我们上周在Python中看到过，Python中的for循环只会知道该怎么做。
we saw last week in Python, the for loop in Python will just know what to do.
这将遍历标题集中的所有标题。
This will loop over all of the titles in the titles set.
因此，让我继续保存该文件并立即进行
So let me go ahead and save this file and go ahead now
并运行“ favourites.py”的python。
and run python of favorites.py.
看起来，列表在某些方面有所不同。
And it looks like, yeah, the list is different in some way.
但是我向上滚动时看到的结果更少，肯定比以前少，
But I'm seeing fewer results as I scroll up, definitely fewer than before,
因为我的滚动条没有跳得那么远。
because my scrollbar didn't jump nearly as far down.
但老实说，这有点混乱。
But honestly, this is kind of a mess.
让我们继续进行排序。
Let's go ahead and sort this.
现在，在C语言中，对事物进行排序会有些痛苦。
Now, in C, it would have been kind of a pain to sort things.
我们可能必须清除伪代码，
We'd have to whip out the pseudocode, probably,
对于气泡排序，选择排序，或者，上帝禁止，
for bubble sort, selection sort, or, god forbid,
合并排序，然后自己实现。
merge sort and then implement it ourselves.
但是，没有，Python确实带来了众所周知的厨房功能库。
But no, with Python comes, really, the proverbial kitchen sink of functions.
因此，如果您想对这个集合进行排序，您知道吗？
So if you want to sort this set, you know what?
只是说您想对它进行排序。
Just say you want it sorted.
Python中有一个称为sorted的函数
There is a function in Python called sorted
它将使用那些更好的算法之一-也许是合并排序。
that will use one of those better algorithms-- maybe it's merge sort.
也许这就是所谓的quicksort。
Maybe it's something called quicksort.
也许完全是另外一回事。
Maybe it's something else altogether.
它不会使用n平方大的O。
It's not going to use a big O of n squared sort.
Python的某个人可能已经花了一些时间为我们实现更好的排序。
Someone at Python probably has spent the time implementing a better sort for us.
但是它将继续进行，并为我整理场景。
But it will go ahead and sort the set for me.
现在，让我继续并再次执行此操作。
Now let me go ahead and do this again.
让我增加终端窗口的大小并重新运行python
Let me increase the size of my terminal window and rerun python
的收藏夹。
of favorites.py.
好的。
OK.
现在我们有一个有趣的分类
And now we have an interesting assortment
对我来说，更容易让我的想法包罗万象，
of shows that's easier for me to wrap my mind around,
因为我现在把它整理在这里了。
because I have it now sorted here.
确实，如果我一直向上滚动，我们应该看所有的节目
And indeed, if I scroll all the way up, we should see all of the shows
以数字或句号开头，
beginning with numbers or a period, which
可能只是有人在玩耍，
might have just been someone playing around,
其次是A字，B字，依此类推。
followed by the A words, the B words, and so forth.
因此，现在我们可以更轻松地将精力集中在这一点上了。
So now it's a little easier to wrap our minds around this.
但是出事了。
But something's up.
我觉得你们很多人都喜欢《阿凡达：最后的气宗》。
I feel like a lot of you like Avatar: The Last Airbender.
但是我确实看到了四个不同的时间。
And yet I'm seeing it, indeed, four different times.
但我认为我们正在对此进行过滤
But I thought we were filtering this down
通过使用该set结构来获得唯一性。
to uniques by using that set structure.
发生什么了？
So what's going on?
实际上，如果我继续滚动，我会很漂亮
And in fact, if I keep scrolling, I'm pretty
我肯定在这里看到了更多的重复。
sure I saw more duplicates in here.
BoJack骑士，坏蛋，坏蛋，
BoJack Horseman, Breaking Bad, Breaking Bad,
布鲁克林九号，布鲁克林九号，CS50有几种不同的口味。
Brooklyn Nine-Nine, Brooklyn Nine-Nine, CS50 in several different flavors.
是的，它一直在继续。
And yes, it keeps going.
朋友们。
Friends.
因此，我看到了很多重复的值。
So I see a lot of duplicate values.
发生什么了？
So what's going on?
是的， [？加达纳？ ？]
Yeah, [? Gadana? ?]
听众：是的，所以您当前的排序方式不区分大小写-抱歉，
AUDIENCE: Yeah, so your current sort is case insensitive-- sorry,
区分大小写，这意味着如果有人用大写字母拼写了化身
is case sensitive, meaning that if someone spells avatar with capital
A在某些地方，那么每次都会得到不同的结果。
A's in some places, then it's going to be a different result each time.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的，是的。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, exactly.
在大写方面，你们中有些人并不勤奋。
Some of you weren't quite diligent when it came to capitalization.
因此，实际上，现实是[[？加达纳（Gadana？）笔记，
And so in fact, the reality is, as [? Gadana ?] notes,
大写字母存在差异。
that there's differences in capitalization.
现在，我们已经解决了这个问题。
Now, we've addressed this before.
实际上，当您实施拼写检查器时，
In fact, when you implemented your spell checker,
当你当你已经要解决这个问题的时候
you had to deal with this already when you
拼写检查任意文本。
were spell checking an arbitrary text.
有些词可能大写。
Some words might be capitalized.
有些可能全部为小写，全部为大写。
Some might be all lowercase, all uppercase.
您想容忍不同的机壳。
And you wanted to tolerate different casings.
因此，我们可能通过强制执行所有操作来解决此问题
And so we probably solved this by just forcing everything
大写或小写的所有东西，
to uppercase or everything to lowercase and doing things,
因此，不区分大小写。
therefore, case insensitively.
所以在这里给我一点时间。
So give me just a moment here.
我将继续在这里快速更改我的表单。
And I'm going to go ahead and make a quick change to my form here.
让我们继续以这种方式更改它
Let's go ahead and change this in such a way
实际上我们将所有内容都强制为大写或小写。
that we actually force everything to uppercase or lowercase.
哪一个都没关系，但是我们需要规范化事情，
Doesn't really matter which, but we need to canonicalize things,
可以这么说。
so to speak, in some way.
规范化事物只是意味着格式化所有数据
And to canonicalize things just means to format all of your data
以某种标准的方式。
in some standard way.
所以[加达纳（Gadana）的观点，让我们标准化
So to [? Gadana's ?] point, let's just standardize
事物的大写。
the capitalization of things.
也许全部大写，全部小写。
Maybe all uppercase, all lowercase.
我们只需要作出判断即可。
We just need to make a judgment call.
因此，我将继续进行一些调整。
So I'm going to go ahead and make a few tweaks here.
我仍然要使用一套。
I'm still going to use a set.
我仍将像以前一样阅读CSV。
I'm still going to read the CSV as before.
但是，不只是添加带有行括号标题的标题，
But instead of just adding the title with row bracket title,
我将继续将其强制为大写，只是
I'm going to go ahead and force it to uppercase, just
只是为了统一起见，是任意的。
arbitrarily, just for the sake of uniformity.
然后，让我们继续检查此处到底发生了什么。
And then let's go ahead and check what exactly has happened here.
我不会更改任何其他内容。
I'm not going to change anything else.
但是，让我继续前进，增加终端的大小
But let me go ahead and increase the size of my terminal
窗口中，重新运行“ favourites.py”的python。
window, rerun python of favorites.py.
和瞧。
And voila.
只是因为我不懂，所以阅读起来有点困难
It's a little harder to read, just because I'm not
习惯于阅读所有大写字母。
used to reading all caps.
有点像我们在大喊大叫。
Kind of looks like we're yelling at ourselves.
但我看不到-等一下。
But I don't see-- wait a minute.
我仍然在这里两次看到办公室。
I still see The Office over here twice.
如果我一直在这里滚动，那么到目前为止，我会看到“陌生人事物”和“ Strainger Things”。
If I keep scrolling here, so far, I see Stranger Things and Strainger Things.
看起来像是一个错字。
That just looks like a typo.
不过，我看到了两个夏洛克。
I see two Sherlocks, though.
这有点可疑。
This is a little suspicious.
所以 [？加达纳，？]您和我似乎还没有完全解决问题。
So [? Gadana, ?] you and I don't seem to have solved things fully.
而且这个还有些微妙。
And this one's a little more subtle.
我可能还要对我的数据做些什么以确保我们删除重复项？
What more should I perhaps do to my data to ensure we get duplicates removed?
奥利维亚？
Olivia?
听众：可能在边缘处修剪。
AUDIENCE: Maybe trim around the edges.
DAVID J. MALAN：修剪边缘。
DAVID J. MALAN: Trim around the edges.
我喜欢这样的声音，但是你是什么意思呢？
I like the sound of that, but what do you mean?
那是做什么的？
What does that do?
听众：哦，像这样，剪掉多余的空间，以防有人
AUDIENCE: Oh, like, trim off the extra spaces in case someone
在单词之前或之后放置一个空格。
put a space before or after the words.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的，是的。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, exactly.
对于人类而言，有意或无意间，
It's pretty common for humans, intentionally or accidentally,
打他们不应该去的空格键。
to hit the Space bar where they shouldn't.
实际上，我有点推断我打赌一个或多个
And in fact, I'm kind of inferring that I bet one or more
你们中的人不小心输入了Sherlock，空格键，然后决定，
of you accidentally typed Sherlock, space, and then decided,
不，就是这样。
nope, that's it.
我没有输入其他任何内容。
I'm not typing anything else.
但是，即使我们不能很清楚地看到它，该空间还是存在的。
But that space, even though we can't quite see it obviously, is there.
当我们进行字符串比较或设置数据结构进行字符串比较时，
And when we do a string comparison or when the set data structure does that,
在进行这些比较时实际上会注意到它。
it's actually going to be noticed when doing those comparisons.
因此，它们将不会是相同的。
And therefore they're not going to be the same.
因此，我可以通过几种不同的方式来做到这一点。
So I can do this in a few different ways.
但是事实证明，在Python中，您可以将函数链接在一起，
But it turns out, in Python, you can chain functions together,
这也是一种花哨的功能。
which is also, too, kind of a fancy feature.
注意我在这里做什么。
Notice what I'm doing here.
我仍在访问标题集。
I'm still accessing the titles set.
我正在为其添加以下值。
I'm adding the following value to it.
我要添加值行括号标题，但不完全是。
I'm adding the value row bracket title, but not quite.
用Python来说，这是一个字符串或一个str。
That is a string or an str, in Python speak.
我要去掉它，
I'm going to go ahead and strip it, which
意味着，如果我们查看此功能的文档，就Olivia而言，
means if we look up the documentation for this function, to Olivia's point,
它会剥离或修剪所有空白区域
it's going to strip off or trim all of the white space
左边，右边的所有空白，
to the left, all of the white space to the right,
是空格键还是Enter键
whether that's the Space bar or the Enter key
或Tab字符或其他一些东西。
or the Tab character or a few other things, as well.
它只是要摆脱前导和尾随的空白。
It's just going to get rid of leading and trailing white space.
然后，剩下的东西，我将继续执行，并强制执行所有操作
And then whatever's left over, I'm going to go ahead and force everything
以[？加达纳（Gadana）的建议。
to uppercase in the spirit of [? Gadana's ?] suggestion, too.
因此，我们现在结合了两个好主意，以对数据进行真正的处理，
So we're sort of combining two good ideas now to really massage the data,
如果可以的话，将其转换为更干净的格式。
if you will, into a cleaner format.
这是一个现实世界的现实。
And this is such a real-world reality.
不能相信您和我的人类以我们应有的方式输入数据。
Humans, you and I, cannot be trusted to input data the way we are supposed to.
有时候都是小写，因为我们
Sometimes it's all lowercase, because we're
有点懒惰或像社交媒体一样，
being a little lazy or a little social media-like,
即使我们正在从亚马逊退房并尝试
even if we're checking out from Amazon and trying
输入有效的邮政地址。
to input a valid postal address.
有时都是首都，因为我可以想到一生中的一些人
Sometimes it's all capitals, because I can think of a few people in my life
那些还不太了解Caps Lock的人。
who don't quite understand the Caps Lock thing just yet.
因此，事情可能全部全部大写了。
And so things might be all capitalized instead.
这对要求精度的计算机系统不利，
This is not good for computer systems that require precision,
我们在第0周的重点。
to our emphasis in week 0.
因此，按摩数据意味着要清理数据，
And so massaging data means cleaning it up,
做一些不会真正改变数据含义的变异
doing some mutations that don't really change the meaning of the data
但将其规范化，标准化，以便您
but canonicalize it, standardize it, so that you're
比较苹果和苹果，可以这么说，不是苹果和橙子。
comparing apples and apples, so to speak, not apples and oranges.
好吧，让我继续在更大的终端上再次运行
Well, let me go ahead and run this again in my bigger terminal
窗口，favourites.py的python。
window, python of favorites.py.
瞧。
Voila.
在向上滚动，向上滚动，向上滚动时，我认为我们处于一个更好的位置。
In scrolling up, up, up, I think we're in a better place.
我现在只看到一个办公室。
I only see one Office now.
如果我不断向上滚动，我仍然看到错别字，
And if I keep scrolling up and up and up, I'm seeing typos still,
但与空白无关。
but nothing related to white space.
而且我认为目前我们拥有更清晰的唯一标题列表。
And I think we have a much cleaner unique list of titles at this point.
当然，如果我们向上滚动，我将不得不
Of course, if we scroll up, I would have to be
如果我想检测印刷错误，那就聪明多了。
a lot more clever if I want to detect things like typographical errors.
你们中的一位似乎非常努力地把FRI
It looks like one of you was very diligent about putting F.R.I.
依此类推，但最后却感到无聊，而在最后一个时期就不再做。
and so forth but then got bored at the end and left off the last period.
但这将在您接受用户输入时发生。
But that's going to happen when you're taking in user input.
我们当然拥有CS50的所有这些变体。
We've, of course, got all these variants of CS50.
这将是一团糟清理，因为现在你
That's going to be a mess to clean up, because now you
可以想象必须添加一大堆if条件，else和else ifs
can imagine having to add a whole bunch of if conditions and elses and else ifs
如果我们想规范化，请清理所有这些
to clean all of that up if we do want to canonicalize
将CS50的所有不同口味都引用为“ CS50”。
all different flavors of CS50 as, quote unquote, "CS50."
因此，这是一个非常湿滑的斜坡。
So this is a very slippery slope.
您和我可能会开始编写大量数据以清除此问题。
You and I could start writing a huge amount of data just to clean this up.
但这是处理现实世界数据时的现实。
But that's the reality when dealing with real-world data.
好吧，让我们现在继续并进一步改进该程序，
Well, let's go ahead now and improve this program further,
做一些更奇特的事情，因为我现在
do something a little fancier, because I now
可以相信我的数据已经规范化
can trust that my data has been canonicalized
除了实际的错别字或CS50之类的怪异变体。
except for the actual typos or the weird variants of CS50 and the like.
让我们继续前进，找出最受欢迎的电视
Let's go ahead and figure out what's the most popular favorite TV
在这里的观众中展示。
show among the audience here.
所以我要从以前的地方开始
So I'm going to start where I have before,
用我当前的代码，因为我认为我有
with my current code, because I think I have
大部分构建块都已就位。
most of the building blocks in place.
我将继续在这里清理我的代码。
I'm going to go ahead and clean up my code a little bit in here.
我要继续给自己一个单独的变量，现在称为title
I'm going to go ahead and give myself a separate variable now called title
只是为了让我可以更有条理地思考事情。
just so that I can think about things in a little more orderly fashion.
但我不会再开始在此集合中添加内容。
But I'm not going to start adding things to this set anymore.
实际上，我认为没有一套
In fact, a set, I don't think, is really going
足以跟踪电视节目的受欢迎程度，
to be sufficient to keep track of the popularity of TV shows,
因为根据定义，该集合会丢弃重复项。
because by definition, the set is throwing away duplicates.
但是现在的目标是相反的。
But the goal now is kind of the opposite.
我想知道哪些是重复的，以便我可以告诉你
I want to know which are the duplicates so that I can tell you
这么多人喜欢The Office。
that this many people like The Office.
这很多人都喜欢Breaking Bad等。
This many people like Breaking Bad and the like.
那么我们在Python的工具包中拥有哪些工具，我们可以通过这些工具来积累
So what tools do we have in Python's toolkit via which we could accumulate
或找出该信息？
or figure out that information?
关于什么数据结构的任何想法都可以在这里帮助我们
Any thoughts on what data structure might help us here
如果我们想弄清楚节目，受欢迎程度，节目，受欢迎程度？
if we want to figure out show, popularity, show, popularity?
在流行度上，我只是指的是CSV文件中它的出现频率。
And by popularity, I just mean the frequency of it in the CSV file.
圣地亚哥？
Santiago?
听众：我猜一个选择是使用词典
AUDIENCE: I guess one option could be to use dictionaries
这样你就可以拥有The Office，我不知道，
so that you can have The Office, I don't know,
20票，然后是《权力的游戏》，另一票，
20 votes, and then Game of Thrones, another one,
这样一本字典就可以真正帮助您形象地看到它。
so that a dictionary could really help you visualize that.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，完美的直觉。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, perfect instincts.
回想一下，无论如何，一本字典在一天结束时
Recall that a dictionary, at the end of the day, no matter how
它是在引擎盖下实现的
sophisticated it's implemented underneath the hood,
就像您的拼写检查器一样-
like your spell checker--
它只是键值对的集合。
It's just a collection of key value pairs.
实际上，它可能是任何语言中最有用的数据结构之一，
And indeed, it's maybe one of the most useful data structures in any language,
因为这种将一个数据与另一个数据关联的能力
because this ability to associate one piece of data with another
仅仅是解决问题的通用解决方案。
is just a very general purpose solution to problems.
确实，就圣地亚哥而言，如果眼前的问题
And indeed, to Santiago's point, if the problem at hand
是为了找出节目的受欢迎程度，
is to figure out the popularity of shows,
好吧，让我们将按键命名为节目的标题及其频率-
well, let's make the keys the titles of our shows and the frequencies thereof--
选票，可以这么说-
the votes, so to speak--
这些键的值。
the values of those keys.
我们将标题映射为投票，标题映射为投票，标题映射为等等。
We're going to map title to votes, title to vote, title to vote, and so forth.
因此，字典就是这样。
So a dictionary is exactly that.
因此，让我继续向上滚动。
So let me go ahead and scroll up.
我可以在这里进行一些调整。
And I can make a little tweak here.
而不是一组，我可以说字典并给我自己
Instead of a set, I can instead say dict and give myself
只是一个空字典。
just an empty dictionary.
实际上，有一种简写形式，这种说法更为普遍。
There's actually shorthand notation for that that's a little more common.
因此，您使用两个空的花括号。
So you use two empty curly braces.
那只意味着完全相同的事情。
That just means the exact same thing.
给我一本最初是空的字典。
Give me a dictionary that's initially empty.
一套没有花哨的捷径。
There's no fancy shortcut for a set.
您必须逐字输入SET，打开paren和关闭paren。
You have to literally type out S-E-T, open paren and closed paren.
但是字典是如此普遍，如此流行，如此强大，
But dictionaries are so common, so popular, so powerful,
他们只有两个花括号，这是语法上的小捷径，
they have this little syntactic shortcut of just two curly braces,
打开和关闭。
open and closed.
现在我有了，让我继续进行。
So now that I have that, let me go ahead and do this.
在我的for循环中，而不是打印
Inside of my for loop, instead of printing
标题，我不想做，而不是将其添加到集合中，
the title, which I don't want to do, and instead of adding it to the set,
我现在要将其添加到字典中。
I now want to add it to the dictionary.
那我该怎么做呢？
So how do I do that?
好吧，如果我的字典叫做书名，我想我基本上可以做点什么
Well, if my dictionary is called titles, I think I can essentially do something
像这样，标题括号title =或+ = 1。
like this, titles bracket title = or maybe += 1.
也许我可以将字典用作一些备忘单
Maybe I can kind of use the dictionary as just a little cheat sheet
的计数，数字从0开始，然后仅加1，在2处加3。
of counts, numbers, that start at 0 and then just add 1, at 2, add 3.
因此，每当我看到办公室，办公室，办公室时，都会+ = 1，+ = 1。
So every time I see The Office, The Office, The Office, do += 1, += 1.
我们不能做++，因为在Python中这不是问题。
We can't do ++, because that's not a thing in Python.
它仅存在于C中。但这似乎进入了名为
It only exists in C. But this would seem to go into the dictionary called
标题，查找与该特定标题匹配的键，
titles, look up the key that matches this specific title,
然后将其中的任何值加1。
and then increment whatever value is there by 1.
但是，我将继续在这里天真地运行它。
But I'm going to go ahead and run this a little naively here.
让我继续运行python的收藏夹.py。
Let me go ahead and run python of favorites.py.
哇，它已经在第9行破裂了。
And wow, it broke already on line 9.
因此，首先要选择合适的节目，
So sort of an apt choice of show to begin with,
我们在Punisher中遇到了一个关键错误。
we have a key error with Punisher.
所以惩罚者是坏的。
So Punisher is bad.
刚刚发生了一件坏事。
Something bad has just happened.
但是，这是什么意思？
But what does that mean?
一个关键错误是指我
A key error is referring to the fact that I
试图访问字典中的无效键。
tried to access an invalid key in a dictionary.
这就是说在这行代码中
This is saying that literally in this line of code
在这里，即使标题是一本字典，甚至
here, even though titles is a dictionary and even
虽然title的值是单引号
though the value of title, singular, is, quote
取消引号“ PUNISHER”，我收到一个关键错误，
unquote, "PUNISHER," I'm getting a key error,
因为该标题尚不存在。
because that title does not yet exist.
因此，即使您不确定用于解决此问题的Python语法，
So even if you're not sure of the Python syntax for fixing this problem,
这里有什么直观的解决方案？
what's the intuitive solution here?
我不能增加惩罚者的频率，
I cannot increment the frequency of the Punisher,
因为惩罚者不在字典中。
because Punisher is not in the dictionary.
几乎感觉像是一个22。
It almost feels like a catch-22.
[？格雷格？ ？]
[? Greg? ?]
听众：我认为您首先需要创建一个for循环
AUDIENCE: I think that you need, first of all, to create a for loop
并可能为字典中的所有内容分配一个值。
and maybe assign a value to everything in the dictionary.
例如对于一个值0，然后加1。
For example, a value 0, and then add 1.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，很好的直觉。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, so good instincts.
在这里，我可以使用另一个隐喻。
And here, I can use another metaphor.
我担心那里可能有鸡肉和鸡蛋的问题，
I worry we might have a chicken and the egg problem there,
因为我认为我无法进入代码的顶部，
because I don't think I can go to the top of my code,
添加一个将字典中所有值初始化为0的循环，
add a loop that initializes all of the values in the dictionary to 0,
因为那时我需要知道所有的演出名称。
because I would need to know all of the names of the shows at that point.
现在，很好。
Now, that's fine.
我想我也许可以更确切地说带你，[？格雷格，？]
I think I could take you maybe more literally, [? Greg, ?]
并打开CSV文件，从上到下对其进行迭代，
and open up the CSV file, iterate over it top to bottom,
而且，只要我看到标题，就将其初始化
and, any time I see a title, just initialize it
在字典中的值为0、0、0。
in the dictionary as having a value of 0, 0, 0.
然后进行另一个for循环，也许重新打开文件，然后执行相同的操作。
Then have another for loop, maybe reopen the file, and do the same.
那会起作用。
And that would work.
但这可以说不是很有效。
But it's arguably not very efficient.
就大O而言，这是渐近的。但是那会
It is asymptotically, in terms of big O. But that would
似乎在做两倍的工作。
seem to be doing twice as much work.
遍历文件一次，仅将所有内容初始化为0。
Iterate over the file once just to initialize everything to 0.
然后第二次遍历文件只是为了增加计数。
Then iterate over the file a second time just to increment the counts.
我认为我们可以做些更有效率的事情。
I think we can do things a little more efficiently.
我认为我们不仅可以实现正确性，而且可以实现更好的设计。
I think we can achieve not only correctness but better design.
关于我们如何仍然可以解决这个问题的任何想法
Any thoughts on how we can still solve this problem without having
遍历整个事情两次？
to iterate over the whole thing twice?
是的， [？西摩威特？ ？]
Yeah, [? Semowit? ?]
听众：我认为我们可以添加一个if语句
AUDIENCE: I think we can add in an if statement
检查该键是否在字典中。
to check if that key is in the dictionary.
如果不是，则添加它，然后继续，然后增加值。
And if it's not, then add it and then go ahead and increment the value after.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice.
我们可以做到这一点。
And we can do exactly that.
因此，让我们直接运用这种直觉。
So let's just apply that intuition.
如果问题是我正在尝试访问尚不存在的密钥，
If the problem is that I'm trying to access a key that does not yet exist,
好吧，让我们稍微聪明一点。
well, let's just be a little smarter about it.
并 [？ Semowit的？]点，让我们检查该密钥是否存在。
And to [? Semowit's ?] point, let's check whether the key exists.
如果确实如此，则将其递增。
And if it does, then increment it.
但是，如果没有，那么，只有然后，[？格雷格（Greg）的建议]，
But if it does not, then and only then, [? to Greg's ?] advice,
将其初始化为0。
initialize it to 0.
所以，让我这样做。
So let me do that.
让我继续说一下标题是否为标题，
Let me go ahead and say if title in titles,
这是问问题的非常Pythonic的，优美的方式
which is the very Pythonic, beautiful way of asking a question
这样，比C语言更干净
like that, way cleaner than in C--
那么，让我继续，准确说出之前的界线。
let me go ahead, then, and say exactly the line from before.
不过，如果其他标题还没有出现在名为“标题”的字典中，
Else, though, if that title is not yet in the dictionary called titles,
好，那也没关系。
well, that's OK, too.
我可以说标题支架title = 0。
I can go ahead and say titles bracket title = 0.
所以这里的区别是我当然可以索引
So the difference here is that I can certainly index
如果我当时计划的话，使用不存在的键将其放入字典中
into a dictionary using a key that doesn't exist if I plan at that moment
给它一个价值。
to give it a value.
没关系，自上周以来一直都是这样。
That's OK, and that has always been OK since last week.
但是，但是，如果我想继续增加那里的价值，
But, however, if I want to go ahead and increment the value that's there,
我将继续在单独的一行中进行操作。
I'm going to go ahead and do that in this separate line.
但是我确实引入了一个错误。
But I did introduce a bug.
我确实在这里介绍了一个错误。
I did introduce a bug here.
我认为我需要在逻辑上更进一步。
I think I need to go one step further logically.
我不希望自己将其初始化为0。
I don't think I want to initialize this to 0 per se.
有人在这里看到我逻辑中的细微错误吗？
Does anyone see a subtle bug in my logic here?
如果标题已经在字典中，则将其递增1。
If the title is already in the dictionary, I'm incrementing it by 1.
否则，我将其初始化为0。
Otherwise, I'm initializing it to 0.
这里有什么妙招吗？
Any subtle catches here?
是的，Olivia，您看到了什么？
Yeah, Olivia, what do you see?
听众：我认为您应该将其初始化为1，因为它是第一个实例。
AUDIENCE: I think you should initialize it to 1, since it's the first instance.
戴维·J·马兰（David J. MALAN）：好的。
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly.
我应该将其初始化为1。
I should initialize it to 1.
否则，我会无意间忽略了这个特定的标题，
Otherwise, I'm accidentally overlooking this particular title,
我将继续进行下去，并低估它。
and I'm going to go ahead and undercount it.
因此，我可以通过执行此操作来解决此问题。
So I can fix this either by doing this.
或坦率地说，如果您愿意，从技术上讲，我不需要使用if。
Or frankly, if you prefer, I don't technically need to use an if else.
我可以通过执行类似这样的操作来使用if。
I can use just an if by doing something like this instead.
我可以说如果标题中没有标题，那么我可以继续
I could say if title not in titles, then I could go ahead
并说title括号title得到0。
and say titles bracket title gets 0.
然后在那之后，我可以盲目地说，就是这样做。
And then after that, I can blindly, so to speak, just do this.
那么哪一个更好呢？
So which one is better?
我认为第二个也许更好
I think the second one is maybe a little better
因为我节省了一行代码。
in that I'm saving one line of code.
但这可以确保条件
But it's ensuring with that if condition,
到 [？ Semowit的？]建议，即我不将其编入标题词典
to [? Semowit's ?] advice, that I'm not indexing into the titles dictionary
直到我确定标题在那里。
until I'm sure that the title is in there.
因此，让我继续并立即运行此命令，收藏夹python的python，输入。
So let me go ahead and run this now, python of favorites.py, Enter.
好吧，它没有崩溃，所以很好。
And OK, it didn't crash, so that's good.
但是我还没有看到任何有用的信息。
But I'm not yet seeing any useful information.
但是我现在可以使用更多了。
But I now have access to a bit more.
现在，我向下滚动到该程序的底部
Let me scroll down now to the bottom of this program, where
我现在有这个循环。
I have now this loop.
让我继续打印并不仅仅是标题
Let me go ahead and print out not just the title
但是该键在字典中的值只是通过索引
but the value of that key in the dictionary by just indexing
在这里。
into it here.
而且您以前可能没有看过这种语法。
And you might not have seen this syntax before.
但是使用print时，您实际上可以传递多个参数。
But with print, you can actually pass in multiple arguments.
默认情况下，打印将只为它们隔开一个空格。
And by default, print will just separate them with a space for you.
您可以覆盖该行为并将其与任何内容分开。
You can override that behavior and separate them with anything.
但这只是一个快速而又肮脏的程序，可以打印出来
But this is just meant to be a quick and dirty program that prints out
标题以及现在的流行度。
titles and now the popularity thereof.
因此，让我再次运行此命令，收藏夹python的python。
So let me run this again, python of favorites.py.
和瞧。
And voila.
到处都是。
It's kind of all over the place.
办公室，那里以26票的超人气。
Office, super popular with 26 votes there.
这里有很多单票。
A lot of single votes here.
大爆炸理论有九个。
Big Bang Theory has nine.
你知道，这一切都很好。
You know, this is all nice and good.
但是我觉得这将带我永远思考
But I feel like this is going to take me forever to wrap my mind around which
是最受欢迎的节目。
are the most popular shows.
那么，当然，我们将如何做呢？
So of course, how would we do this?
好吧，至此，我的天哪，有了电子表格，
Well, to the point made earlier, with spreadsheets, my god,
在Microsoft Excel或Google Spreadsheets或Apple Numbers中，
in Microsoft Excel or Google Spreadsheets or Apple Numbers,
您只需单击列标题和繁荣，即可对其进行排序。
you just click the column heading and boom, sorted.
除非我们现在在代码中进行操作，否则我们似乎已经失去了这种能力。
We seem to have lost that capability unless we now do it in code.
因此，让我为我们做到这一点。
So let me do that for us.
让我继续并回到我的代码。
Let me go ahead and go back to my code.
尽管它确实适用于字典，但看起来还是经过排序的，
And it looks like sorted, even though it does work on dictionaries,
实际上是按键排序，而不是按值排序。
is actually sorting by key, not by value.
这是我们的Python编程技术需要的地方
And here's where our Python programming techniques need
变得更加复杂。
to get a little more sophisticated.
我们现在想在这里介绍另一个功能
And we want to introduce another feature here now
Python的版本，它将专门解决此问题
of Python which is going to solve this problem specifically
但以一种非常普遍的方式
but in a pretty general way.
因此，如果我们阅读了有关分类的文档，
So if we read the documentation for sorted,
排序的函数实际上是根据其中的值对集合进行排序的。
the sorted function indeed sorts sets by the values therein.
它按其中的值对列表进行排序。
It sorts lists by the values therein.
它通过其中的键对字典进行排序，
It sorts dictionaries by the keys therein,
因为字典每个元素都有两条信息。
because dictionaries have two pieces of information for every element.
它有一个键和一个值，而不仅仅是一个值。
It has a key and a value, not just a value.
因此，默认情况下，按键对排序进行排序。
So by default, sorted sorts by key.
因此，我们必须以某种方式覆盖该行为。
So we somehow have to override that behavior.
那么我们该怎么做呢？
So how can we do this?
好吧，事实证明，排序功能
Well, it turns out that the sorted function
接受另一个可选参数，字面上称为key。
takes another optional argument literally called key.
key参数将函数的名称作为其值。
And the key argument takes as its value the name of a function.
这就是事情变得非常有趣的地方，
And this is where things get really interesting,
如果不引起混淆，那真的很快。
if not confusing, really quickly.
事实证明，在Python中，您可以将函数作为参数传递
It turns out, in Python, you can pass around functions as arguments
以他们的名字
by way of their name.
从技术上讲，您可以使用C进行此操作。这在语法上涉及更多。
And technically, you can do this in C. It's a lot more syntactically involved.
但是在Python中，这很常见。
But in Python, it's very common.
在JavaScript中，这很常见。
In JavaScript, it's very common.
在很多语言中，想到函数是很普遍的
In a lot of languages, it's very common to think of functions
作为一流的对象，这是一种奇妙的说法，您可以将它们传递出去
as first-class objects, which is a fancy way of saying you can pass them around
就像它们本身就是变量一样。
just like they are variables themselves.
我们还没有打电话给他们。
We're not calling them yet.
但是您可以通过他们的名字来传递它们。
But you can pass them around by their name.
那我是什么意思呢？
So what do I mean by this?
好吧，我现在需要一个函数来按其值对字典进行排序。
Well, I need a function now to sort my dictionary by its value.
而且也许只有我知道该怎么做，所以让我继续前进，给自己
And only I know how to do this, perhaps, so let me go ahead and give myself
泛型函数名称，此刻称为f-- f，
a generic function name just for the moment called f-- f for function,
有点像数学
kind of like in math--
因为我们最终将要摆脱它。
because we're going to get rid of it eventually.
但是，让我继续并临时定义一个函数
But let me go ahead and temporarily define a function
被称为f的f以标题为输入。
called f that takes as input a title.
然后它为我返回与该键相对应的值。
And then it returns for me the value corresponding to that key.
因此，我将继续返回标题支架标题。
So I'm going to go ahead and return titles bracket title.
因此，在这里，我们有一个功能，其生活目的非常简单。
So here, we have a function whose purpose in life is super simple.
您给它一个标题。
You give it a title.
它为您提供数量，频率，受欢迎程度，
It gives you the count thereof, the frequency, the popularity thereof,
只需在该全球词典中查找它即可。
by just looking it up in that global dictionary.
因此，它非常简单，但这是生活中唯一的目的。
So it's super simple, but that's its only purpose in life.
但是现在，根据排序的文档，
But now, according to the documentation for sorted,
现在要做什么，因为我传入了第二个参数
what it's now going to do, because I'm passing in a second argument called
键，排序功能，而不只是假设您想对所有内容进行排序
key, the sorted function, rather than just presume you want everything sorted
按字母顺序，相反
alphabetically by key, it's instead going
在字典中的每个元素上调用该函数f。
to call that function f on every one of the elements in your dictionary.
根据您的回答，返回值
And depending on your answer, the return value
你用那个f函数给定，它将代替
you give with that f function, that will be used instead
确定实际订购。
to determine the actual ordering.
因此，默认情况下，排序仅查看键。
So by default, sorted just looks at key.
我正在用这个f函数有效地做什么
What I'm effectively doing with this f function
而是返回与每个键对应的值。
is instead returning the value corresponding to every key.
因此，尽管在语法上有些新，但这样做的逻辑含义是，
And so the logical implication of this, even though the syntax is a little new,
就是这个标题词典现在
is that this dictionary of titles will now
按值而不是键排序。
be sorted by value instead of by key.
因为同样，默认情况下，它是按键排序的。
Because again, by default, it sorts by key.
但是如果我定义自己的键功能并覆盖该行为
But if I define my own key function and override that behavior
返回相应的值，即值，数字，
to return the corresponding value, it's the values, the numbers,
实际上将用于此事物的计数。
the counts that will actually be used to this thing.
好的。
All right.
让我们继续前进，看看在实践中是否如此。
Let's go ahead and see if that's true in practice.
让我继续并重新运行“ favourites.py”的python。
Let me go ahead and rerun python of favorites.py.
我应该看所有的标题。
I should see all the titles.
瞧，这是最受欢迎的节目
And voila, conveniently, the most popular show
似乎是《权力的游戏》，得票33票，其次是朋友，得27票，
seems to be Game of Thrones with 33 votes, followed by Friends with 27,
紧随其后的是Office的26，依此类推。
followed by The Office with 26, and so forth.
但是，当然，该列表有点倒退。
But of course, the list is kind of backwards.
我的意思是，在屏幕底部看到它很方便。
I mean, it's convenient that I can see it at the bottom of my screen.
但是，实际上，如果我们要列出一个列表，那么它应该实际上是最重要的。
But really, if we're making a list, it should really be at the top.
那么，我们如何覆盖这种行为呢？
So how can we override that behavior?
列出排序后的函数，如果您阅读了它的文档，
Turns out the sorted function, if you read its documentation,
还采用了另一个称为反向的可选参数。
also takes another optional parameter called reverse.
如果将反向设置为True，则大写
And if you set reverse equal to True, capital
用Python T，这将继续并给我们
T in Python, that's going to go ahead and give us now
相同顺序的相反顺序。
the reverse order of that same sort.
因此，让我继续操作并最大化我的终端窗口，然后再次运行它。
So let me go ahead and maximize my terminal window, rerun it again.
瞧，如果我向上滚动到顶部，它不是按字母顺序排序的。
And voila, if I scroll back up to the top, it's not alphabetically sorted.
但是如果我继续前进，继续前进，继续前进，继续前进，
But if I keep going, keep going, keep going, keep going,
这个数字越来越大。
the numbers are getting bigger.
瞧，现在《权力的游戏》以33排名第一。
And voila, now Game of Thrones with 33 is all the way at the top.
好吧，太酷了。
All right, so pretty cool.
再说一次，至少在Python中，这是新功能，
And again, the new functionality here in Python, at least,
是我们实际上可以将函数传递给函数
is that we can actually pass in functions to functions
并留给后者打电话给前者。
and leave it to the latter to call the former.
所以这很复杂。
So that's complicated just to say.
但是现在对我们如何使用字典有任何疑问或困惑
But any questions or confusion now on how we are using dictionaries
以及我们如何以这种反向的，基于价值的方式对事物进行分类？
and how we are sorting things in this reverse, value-based way?
有任何疑问或困惑吗？
Any questions or confusion?
聊天中有任何内容或口头上的内容，Brian？
Anything in the chat or verbally, Brian?
布莱恩·于：看来所有问题都在这里回答了。
BRIAN YU: Looks like all questions are answered here.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
然后，在这种情况下，让我指出一个常见的错误。
Then in that case, let me point out a common mistake.
请注意，即使f是一个函数，也请注意我没有在那儿调用它。
Notice that even though f is a function, notice that I did not call it there.
那将是不正确的，原因是我们故意
That would be incorrect, the reason being we deliberately
想要将函数f传递给已排序的函数
want to pass the function f into the sorted function
这样排序后的函数就可以自己一次又一次地调用f
so that the sorted function can take it upon itself to call f again and again
然后再次。
and again.
我们不希望自己使用括号来一次调用它。
We don't want to just call it once by using the parentheses ourselves.
我们只想按名称传递它，以便排序后的函数
We want to just pass it in by name so that the sorted function, which comes
使用Python，反而可以为我们做到这一点。
with Python, can instead do it for us.
圣地亚哥，你有问题吗？
Santiago, did you have a question?
听众：是的，我要问。
AUDIENCE: Yes, I was going to ask.
我们为什么不加标题f？
Why didn't we put f of title?
我要特别问这个问题。
I was going to ask that question specifically.
DAVID J. MALAN：哦，加上括号？
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh, with the parentheses?
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的，完美。
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh, OK, perfect.
因此，因为那样只会调用一次函数。
So because that would call the function once and only once.
我们希望排序能够一次又一次地调用它。
We want sorted to be able to call it again and again.
现在，这实际上是一个示例，如我们所见
Now, here's actually an example, as we've seen
过去的正确解决方案。
in the past, of a correct solution.
正如我所期望的那样，这是从上到下的排序标题列表
This is behaving as I intend, a list of sorted titles from top to bottom
以受欢迎程度排序。
in order of popularity.
但这设计有点糟糕，因为我
But it's a little poorly designed, because I'm
定义此函数f，其名称首先是la脚。
defining this function f, whose name in the first place is kind of lame.
但是我定义一个函数只是在一个地方使用它。
But I'm defining a function only to use it in one place.
我的天哪，功能太小了，感觉就像是在敲击键盘一样
And my god, the function is so tiny, it just feels like a waste of keystrokes
定义了一个新函数然后传递给它。
to have defined a new function just to then pass it in.
事实证明，在Python中，如果您有一个非常短的函数，而该函数的
So it turns out, in Python, if you have a very short function whose
生活的目的是要一次解决一个局部问题，仅此而已
purpose in life is meant to be to solve a local problem just once and that's it
而且它足够短，足以确保您可以将其放在一行代码中
and it's short enough that you're pretty sure you can fit it on one line of code
事实证明，没有东西包裹起来并且开始变得丑陋，
without things wrapping and starting to get ugly stylistically, it turns out
您实际上可以执行此操作。
you can actually do this instead.
您可以像这样复制您想到的代码。
You can copy the code that you had in mind like this.
而不是将f实际定义为函数名称，
And instead of actually defining f as a function name,
您实际上可以在Python中使用一个称为lambda的特殊关键字。
you can actually use a special keyword in Python called lambda.
您可以像以前一样为函数指定参数的名称。
You can specify the name of an argument for your function as before.
然后您可以简单地指定返回值，此后
And then you can simply specify the return value, thereafter
删除函数本身。
deleting the function itself.
需要明确的是，key仍然是已排序函数的参数。
So to be clear, key is still an argument to the sorted function.
它通常期望一个函数的名称作为其值。
It expects as its value typically the name of a function.
但是，如果您决定这样做，这似乎是在浪费精力
But if you've decided that, eh, this seems like a waste of effort
定义一个函数，然后传入该函数，
to define a function, then pass the function in,
特别是当它很短时，您可以在一个衬里中完成。
especially when it's so short, you can do it in a one liner.
Lambda函数是一个匿名函数。
A lambda function is an anonymous function.
Lambda从字面上说，Python，给我一个函数。
Lambda literally says, Python, give me a function.
我不在乎它的名字。
I don't care about its name.
因此，您不必为其选择名称。
Therefore, you don't have to choose a name for it.
但是它仍然关心它的参数和返回值。
But it does care still about its arguments and its return value.
因此，仍然需要您提供零个或多个参数和一个返回值。
So it's still up to you to provide zero or more arguments and a return value.
并注意我已经做到了。
And notice I've done that.
我指定了关键字lambda，后跟参数名称
I've specified the keyword lambda followed by the name of the argument
我希望这个匿名的，无名的函数能够接受。
I want this anonymous, nameless function to accept.
然后我指定返回值。
And then I'm specifying the return value.
对于lambda函数，您无需指定return。
And with lambda functions, you do not need to specify return.
无论您在冒号之后写的是字面上的
Whatever you write after the colon is literally
什么会自动返回。
what will be returned automatically.
再次重申，这是非常Python化的事情。
So again, this is a very Pythonic thing to do.
这是一个非常聪明的班轮，尽管有点神秘
It's kind of a very clever one liner, even though it's a little cryptic
第一次看到。
to see for the very first time.
但这使您可以将自己的思想浓缩为简洁的陈述，
But it allows you to condense your thoughts into a succinct statement that
完成工作，因此您不必开始定义越来越多的功能
gets the job done so you don't have to start defining more and more functions
然后您或其他人需要跟踪。
that you or someone else then need to keep track of.
好的。
All right.
那么，对此有任何疑问吗？
Any questions, then, on this?
而且我很确定这与我们的Python代码一样复杂或复杂
And I am pretty sure this is as complex or sophisticated as our Python code
今天会得到。
today will get.
是的，交给索菲娅。
Yeah, over to Sophia.
听众：我想知道为什么专门使用“ lambda”
AUDIENCE: I was wondering why "lambda" is used specifically
而不是其他一些关键字。
rather than some other keyword.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，所以有很长的历史。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, so there's a long history in this.
实际上，如果您在哈佛上一门关于函数式编程的课程，
And if, in fact, you take a course on functional programming-- at Harvard,
叫做CS51
it's called CS51--
像这样的关键字背后有一个完整的词源。
there's a whole etymology behind keywords like this.
让我再推迟一次。
Let me defer that one for another time.
但是确实，不仅在Python中，而且在其他语言中，
But indeed, not only in Python but in other languages,
同样，这些东西也已经存在，称为lambda函数。
as well, these things have come to exist called lambda functions.
因此，它们实际上在其他语言中也很普遍。
So they're actually quite commonplace in other languages, as well.
因此，Python只是采用了艺术术语。
And so Python just adopted the term of art.
在数学上，lambda通常用作函数的符号。
Mathematically, lambda is often used as a symbol for functions.
因此，他们在编程领域借鉴了相同的想法。
And so they borrowed that same idea in the world of programming.
好的。
All right.
因此，没有其他问题，让我们继续解决相关问题
So seeing no other questions, let's go ahead and solve a related problem still
用一些Python，但这会增加
with some Python but that's going to push up
在将我们的数据存储在CSV文件中时，效率受到限制。
against the limits of efficiency when it comes to storing our data in CSV files.
让我继续，从这个文件“ Favorites.py”中重新开始。
Let me go ahead and start fresh in this file, Favorites.py.
不过，到目前为止，我已经编写了所有代码，
All of the code I've written thus far, though,
事先在课程的网站上，所以您
is on the course's website in advance, so you
可以看到逐步的改善。
can see the incremental improvement.
我要继续，再次在顶部导入csv。
I'm going to go ahead and, again, import csv at the top.
现在让我们编写一次不只是一个程序
And now let's write a program this time that doesn't just
自动打开CSV并对其进行分析
automatically open up the CSV and analyze it looking
节目的整体人气。
for the total popularity of shows.
让我们在CSV中搜索特定的节目，然后
Let's search for a specific show in the CSV and then
继续并输出其受欢迎程度。
go ahead and output the popularity thereof.
我可以通过多种不同的方式来做到这一点。
And I can do this in a bunch of different ways.
但是我将尝试使其尽可能简洁。
But I'm going to try to make this as concise as possible.
我首先要请用户输入标题。
I'm first going to ask the user to input a title.
我可以使用CS50的get_string函数。
I could use CS50's get_string function.
但是请记住，它与Python的输入函数几乎相同，
But recall that it's pretty much the same as Python's input function,
因此，今天我将使用Python的输入函数。
so I'm going to use Python's input function today.
然后，我将继续，和以前一样，
And then I'm going to go ahead and, as before,
打开称为“收藏的电视节目”的相同CSV-
open up that same CSV called Favorite TV Shows -
表单响应1.csv在只读模式下为变量，称为文件。
Form Responses 1.csv in read-only mode as a variable called file.
然后，我要给自己一个读者，然后我将再次使用DictReader
I'm then going to give myself a reader, and I'll use a DictReader again
因此我不必担心知道事物在哪一列中，
so I don't have to worry about knowing which columns things are in,
传入文件。
passing in file.
然后让我们看看。
And then let's see.
如果我只关心一个标题，则可以使该程序更简单。
If I only care about one title, I can keep this program simpler.
我不需要弄清楚每个节目的受欢迎程度。
I don't need to figure out the popularity of every show.
我只需要弄清楚一个节目的受欢迎程度，标题
I just need to figure out the popularity of one show, the title
人类输入的内容。
that the human has typed in.
所以我要继续给自己一个很简单的int叫做counter
So I'm going to go ahead and give myself a very simple int called counter
并将其设置为0。
and set it equal to 0.
我不需要一本完整的字典。
I don't need a whole dictionary.
现在只有一个变量就足够了。
Just one variable suffices now.
我将像以前一样继续遍历阅读器中的行。
And I'm going to go ahead and iterate over the rows in the reader, as before.
然后我要说的是当前行的标题是否为人类的标题
And then I'm going to say if the current row's title == the title the human
输入，让我们继续前进，将计数器加1。
typed in, let's go ahead and increment counter by 1.
并且它已经初始化，因为我在第7行上执行了该操作。
And it's already initialized, because I did that on line 7.
所以我认为我很好。
So I think I'm good.
然后在该程序结束时，让我们
And then at the end of this program, let's
非常简单地打印出计数器的值。
very simply print out the value of counter.
因此，该程序的目的是提示用户显示节目的标题
So the purpose of this program is to prompt the user for a title of a show
然后只报告其受欢迎程度
and then just report the popularity thereof
通过计算它在文件中的实例数。
by counting the number of instances of it in the file.
因此，让我继续并使用favorite.py的python运行它。
So let me go ahead and run this with python of favorites.py.
进入。
Enter.
我继续输入“办公室”，然后按Enter，然后输入19。
Let me go ahead and type in "The Office," Enter, and 19.
现在，我不记得确切的数字了。
Now, I don't remember exactly what the number was.
但是我记得办公室比这更受欢迎。
But I remember The Office was more popular than that.
我很确定那不是19岁。
I'm pretty sure it was not 19.
关于为什么该程序有错误或看起来如此直观的任何直觉？
Any intuition as to why this program is buggy or so it would seem?
布莱恩·于：聊天中的几个人在说
BRIAN YU: A few people in the chat are saying
您需要记住再次处理大写和空白。
you need to remember to deal with capitalization and white space again.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
因此，我们需要实践从以前学到的相同的经验教训。
So we need to practice those same lessons learned from before.
因此，我应该真正规范化我刚刚输入的人类的输入
So I should really canonicalize the input that the human, I, just typed in
以及来自CSV文件的输入。
and also the input that's coming from the CSV file.
也许最简单的方法是在这里，
Perhaps the simplest way to do this is, up here,
首先去除开头和结尾的空白，以防万一
to first strip off leading and trailing white space in case I get a little
马虎，打我不应该的空格键。
sloppy and hit the Space bar where I shouldn't.
然后，让我们继续将其强制为大写是因为。
And then let's go ahead and force it to uppercase just because.
大小无关紧要
It doesn't matter if it's upper or lower,
但至少我们将以这种方式进行标准化。
but at least we'll standardize things that way.
然后，当我执行此操作时，请查看当前行标题。
And then when I do this, look at the current rows title.
我认为我确实需要做同样的事情。
I think I really need to do the same thing.
如果要规范一个，则需要规范另一个。
If I'm going to canonicalize one, I need to canonical the other.
现在比较全大写，空格分隔的版本
And now compare the all-caps, white-space-stripped versions
这两个字符串。
of both strings.
现在让我重新运行它。
So now let me rerun it.
现在，我要输入“ The Office”，然后按Enter。
Now I'm going to type in "The Office," Enter.
和瞧。
And voila.
现在我已经26岁了，我认为这是我们以前的位置。
Now I'm at 26, which I think is where we were at before.
实际上，现在我（用户）可能有点草率。
And in fact, now I, the user, can be a little sloppy.
我可以说“办公室”。
I can say "the office."
我可以再次运行它并说“办公室”，然后无论出于何种原因，
I can run it again and say "the office" and then, for whatever reason,
打很多空格键，回车。
hit the Space bar a lot, Enter.
它仍然可以正常工作。
It's still going to work.
确实，尽管我们似乎在这里here脚
And indeed, though we seem to be belaboring the pedantic here
修剪空白等等，只是想一想。
with trimming off white space and so forth, just think.
在相对较小的受众群体中，你们中有多少人
In a relatively small audience here, how many of you
不小心碰到了空格键还是大写的东西不一样？
accidentally hit the Space bar or capitalized things differently?
这是大规模发生的。
This happens massively on scale.
您可以想象，在标记时，这一点很重要
And you can imagine this being important when you're tagging
一些社交媒体帐户中的朋友。
friends in some social media account.
你在做@Brian之类的。
You're doing @Brian or the like.
您不需要要求用户输入@，大写B，
You don't want to have to require the user to type @, capital B,
小写的rian，依此类推。
lowercase r-i-a-n, and so forth.
因此可以容忍分散的，混乱的用户输入
So tolerating disparate, messy user input
是要解决的常见问题，包括
is such a common problem to solve, including
在我们大家都使用的当今应用程序中。
in today's apps that we all use.
好的。
All right.
那么，对此程序有什么疑问，我认为是正确的吗？
Any questions, then, on this program, which I think is correct?
然后让我问你一个问题。
Then let me ask a question of you.
在什么意义上该程序设计不佳？
In what sense is this program poorly designed?
这更加微妙。
This is more subtle.
但是从大O角度考虑该程序的运行时间。
But think about the running time of this program in terms of big O.
如果CSV文件有n个不同的节目，该程序的运行时间是多少
What is the running time of this program if the CSV file has n different shows
还是n个不同的提交？
in it or n different submissions?
所以n是有问题的变量。
So n is the variable in question.
是的，那是什么时间，安德鲁？
Yeah, what's the running time, Andrew?
观众：[听不清]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，这是n的大O，因为我实际上是在使用
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, it's big O of n, because I'm literally using
通过for循环进行线性搜索。
linear search by way of the for loop.
就像C中一样，这就是for循环在Python中的工作方式。
That's how a for loop works in Python, just like in C. Starts at the beginning
并可能一路走到尽头。
and potentially goes all the way till the end.
因此，我正在使用隐式线性搜索，
And so I'm using implicitly linear search,
因为我没有使用任何花哨的数据结构，没有集合，没有字典。
because I'm not using any fancy data structures, no sets, no dictionaries.
我只是从上到下循环。
I'm just looping from top to bottom.
因此，您可以想象，如果我们不仅调查了这里的所有学生，
So you can imagine that if we surveyed not just all of the students here
在课堂上，但也许每个人都在校园里或世界上每个人-
in class but maybe everyone on campus or everyone in the world--
也许我们是互联网电影数据库，IMDb。
maybe we're Internet Movie Database, IMDb.
可能会有大量的选票和大量的演出。
There could be a huge number of votes and a huge number of shows.
因此编写程序，无论是在像我这样的终端窗口中
And so writing a program, whether it's in a terminal window like mine
或在移动设备上，或者在笔记本电脑或台式机的网页上，
or maybe on a mobile device or maybe on a webpage for your laptop or desktop,
这可能不是不断循环的最佳设计
it's probably not the best design to constantly loop
从顶部开始浏览数据库中的所有节目
over all of the shows in your database from top
仅仅回答一个问题。
to bottom just to answer a single question.
以n次或以固定时间记录会更好。
It would be much nicer to do things in log of n time or in constant time.
值得庆幸的是，在过去的几周中，无论是在C语言还是Python语言中，
And thankfully, over the past few weeks, both in C and in Python,
我们已经看到了更聪明的方法来做到这一点。
we have seen smarter ways to do this.
但是我没有练习我在这里讲的内容。
But I'm not practicing what I've preached here.
实际上，在某种程度上，这种平面文件数据库的概念
And in fact, at some point, this notion of a flat-file database
对我们来说太原始了。
starts to get too primitive for us.
平面文件数据库（如CSV文件）非常有用
Flat-file databases, like CSV files, are wonderfully useful
当您只想快速做某事时
when you just want to do something quickly
或者当您想从某个第三方下载数据时，
or when you want to download data from some third party,
像Google一样，以一种标准的可移植方式进行。
like Google, in a standard, portable way.
“便携式”意味着它可以由不同的人和不同的系统使用。
"Portable" means that it can be used by different people and different systems.
CSV尽可能简单，因为您
CSV is about as simple as it gets, because you
不需要拥有Microsoft Word或Apple
don't need to own Microsoft Word or Apple
数字或任何特定产品。
Numbers or any particular product.
这只是一个文本文件，因此您可以使用任何文本编辑
It's just a text file, so you can use any text editing
程序或任何编程语言来访问它。
program or any programming language to access it.
但是平面文件数据库不一定是最佳结构
But flat-file databases aren't necessarily the best structure
最终用于较大的数据集，因为它们实际上并没有
to use ultimately for larger data sets, because they don't really
使自己能够进行更有效的查询。
lend themselves to more efficient queries.
因此，CSV文件最多只能搜索到上至下，
So CSV files, pretty much at best, you have to search top to bottom,
左到右。
left to right.
但是事实证明，那里有更好的数据库
But it turns out that there are better databases out there generally known
作为关系数据库，而不是存储数据的文件，
as relational databases that, instead of being files in which you store data,
它们是存储数据的程序。
they are instead programs in which you store data.
现在，公平地说，这些程序会占用大量RAM，内存，
Now, to be fair, those programs use a lot of RAM, memory,
他们实际在哪里存储您的数据。
where they actually store your data.
而且他们的确可以持久保存您的数据。
And they do certainly persist your data.
他们通过将数据也存储在文件中来长期保存数据。
They keep it long term by storing your data also in files.
但是在您和您的数据之间，有这个正在运行的程序。
But between you and your data, there is this running program.
而且，如果您曾经听说过Oracle或MySQL或PostgreSQL或SQL Server
And if you've ever heard of Oracle or MySQL or PostgreSQL or SQL Server
或Microsoft Access或许多其他受欢迎的产品，
or Microsoft Access or bunches of other popular products,
商业，免费和开源都一样，
both commercial and free and open source alike,
关系数据库在本质上与电子表格非常相似。
relational databases are so similar in spirit to spreadsheets.
但是它们是用软件实现的。
But they are implemented in software.
而且它们为我们提供了越来越多的功能。
And they give us more and more features.
而且他们使用越来越多的数据结构
And they use more and more data structures
这样我们就可以搜索数据，插入数据，删除数据，大量更新数据，
so that we can search for data, insert data, delete data, update data much,
比起只使用CSV文件这样的方式，效率要高得多。
much more efficiently than we could if just using something like a CSV file.
因此，让我们继续前进，在这里休息五分钟。
So let's go ahead and take our five-minute break here.
当我们回来时，我们将研究关系数据库，然后，
And when we come back, we'll look at relational databases and, in turn,
一种称为SQL的语言。
a language called SQL.
好的。
All right.
所以我们回来了。
So we are back.
现在的目标是过渡
And the goal at hand now is to transition
从这些相当简单的平面文件数据库中
from these fairly simplistic flat-file databases
到更合适的关系数据库。
to a more proper relational database.
关系数据库的确具有如此强大的功能
And relational databases are indeed what power so many
当今的移动应用程序，Web应用程序等。
of today's mobile applications, web applications, and the like.
现在我们开始过渡到现实世界的软件
Now we're beginning to transition to real-world software
使用现实世界的语言。
with real-world languages, at that.
现在，让我介绍一下我们称之为SQLite的内容。
And so now, let me introduce what we're going to call SQLite.
因此事实证明，一个关系数据库
So it turns out that a relational database
是一个数据库，它以行和列的形式存储所有数据。
is a database that stores all of the data still in rows and columns.
但是，使用电子表格或工作表并不能做到这一点。
But it doesn't do so using spreadsheets or sheets.
相反，它使用我们将要调用的表来实现。
It instead does so using what we're going to call tables.
因此，几乎是相同的想法。
So it's pretty much the same idea.
但是，有了表，我们可以获得一些附加功能。
But with tables, we get some additional functionality.
有了这些表，我们将有能力
With those tables, we'll have the ability
搜索数据，更新数据，删除数据，插入新数据等。
to search for data, update data, delete data, insert new data, and the like.
这些是我们绝对可以使用电子表格完成的事情。
And these are things that we absolutely can do with spreadsheets.
但是在电子表格的世界中，如果您要搜索某些内容，
But in the world of spreadsheets, if you want to search for something,
是您，人类，通过手动单击和滚动来做到这一点，
it's you, the human, doing it by manually clicking and scrolling,
通常。
typically.
如果您要插入数据，就是您，人类，
If you want to insert data, it's you, the human,
添加新行后手动输入。
typing it in manually after adding a new row.
如果要删除某物，就对了
If you want to delete something, it's you right
单击或按住Control单击并删除整行
clicking or Control-clicking and deleting a whole row
或更新它们所在的单个单元格。
or updating the individual cells they're in.
有了SQL，结构化查询语言，我们有了新的编程语言
With SQL, Structured Query Language, we have a new programming language
通常与其他编程语言结合使用。
that is very often used in conjunction with other programming languages.
因此，今天，我们将看到SQL最初是单独使用的。
And so today, we'll see SQL used on its own initially.
但是我们还将在Python程序的上下文中看到它。
But we'll also see it in the context of a Python program.
因此，像Python这样的语言本身就可以使用SQL来完成更强大的功能
So a language like Python can itself use SQL to do more powerful things
比Python独有。
than Python alone could do.
如此说来，SQLite就像是SQL的简易版。
So with that said, SQLite is like a light version of SQL.
这是一个更加用户友好的版本。
It's a more user-friendly version.
更便携。
It's more portable.
它可以在Mac和PCS以及手机，笔记本电脑和台式机上使用
It can be used on Macs and PCS and phones and laptops and desktops
和服务器。
and servers.
但这是非常普遍的。
But it's incredibly common.
实际上，在您的iPhone和Android手机中，许多应用程序
In fact, in your iPhone and your Android phone, many of the applications
您今天在自己的设备上运行，并且在后台使用SQLite。
you are running today on your own device are using SQLite underneath the hood.
因此，它本身不是玩具语言。
So it isn't a toy language per se.
相反，这是一个相对简单的实现
It's instead a relatively simple implementation
一种通常称为SQL的语言。
of a language generally known as SQL.
长话短说，关系数据库还有其他实现
But long story short, there's other implementations of relational databases
在那里。
out there.
我已经吵了几声-
And I rattled off several of them already--
Oracle和MySQL以及PostgreSQL之类。
Oracle and MySQL and PostgreSQL and the like.
这些都具有稍微不同的SQL风格或方言。
Those all have slightly different flavors or dialects of SQL.
因此，SQL是用于与数据库交互的相当标准的语言。
So SQL is a fairly standard language for interacting with databases.
但是不同的公司，不同的社区
But different companies, different communities
有增加或减少自己喜欢的功能。
have kind of added or subtracted their own preferred features.
因此，您使用的语法通常在所有平台上都是不变的。
And so the syntax you use is generally constant across all platforms.
但是我们将针对我们的目的在SQLite上进行标准化。
But we will standardize for our purposes on SQLite.
确实，这就是您最近使用的方式
And indeed, this is what you would use these days
在移动应用程序世界中。
in the world of mobile applications.
因此，那里非常紧密。
So it's very much germane there.
因此，使用SQLite，我们最终将拥有查询数据的功能
So with SQLite, we're going to have ultimately the ability to query data
以及更新数据，删除数据等。
and update data, delete data, and the like.
但是要做到这一点，我们实际上需要一个程序
But to do so, we actually need a program with which
与我们的数据库进行交互。
to interact with our database.
因此，SQLite的工作方式是存储所有数据
So the way SQLite works is that it stores all of your data
仍在文件中。
still in a file.
但这是一个二进制文件。
But it's a binary file now.
也就是说，它是一个包含0和1的文件。
That is, it's a file containing 0's and 1's.
而那些0和1可能代表文本。
And those 0's and 1's might represent text.
它们可能代表数字。
They might represent numbers.
但这是一种更紧凑，更有效的表示
But it's a more compact, efficient representation
而不是仅CSV文件将使用ASCII还是Unicode。
than a mere CSV file would be using ASCII or Unicode.
所以这是第一个区别。
So that's the first difference.
SQLite使用一个文件，一个二进制文件，
SQLite uses a single file, a binary file,
存储所有数据，并通过所有方式将其表示在该文件中
to store all of your data and represent it inside of that file by way of all
我之前提到的那些0和1或表格中的一个，
of those 0's and 1's or the tables to which I alluded before,
这是工作表或电子表格的数据库世界中的类似物
which are the analogue in the database world of sheets or spreadsheets
在电子表格世界中。
in the spreadsheet world.
因此，要与存储所有数据的二进制文件进行交互，
So to interact with that binary file wherein all of your data is stored,
我们需要某种面向用户的程序。
we need some kind of user-facing program.
并且有许多不同的工具可供使用。
And there's many different tools to use.
但是SQLite附带的标准
But the standard one that comes with SQLite
称为sqlite3，本质上是该工具的第3版。
is called sqlite3, essentially version 3 of the tool.
这是一种命令行工具，其实质类似于任何命令
This is a command line tool similar in spirit to any of the commands
到目前为止，您已经在终端窗口中运行了
you've run in a terminal window thus far that
允许您打开该二进制文件并与所有表进行交互。
allows you to open up that binary file and interact with all of your tables.
现在，再次在这里，我们遇到了鸡肉和鸡蛋的问题。
Now, here again, we kind of have a chicken and the egg problem.
如果我想使用数据库但还没有数据库
If I want to use a database but I don't yet have a database
但是我想从数据库中选择数据，
and yet I want to select data from my database,
我如何实际加载东西？
how do I actually load things in?
好了，您可以通过至少两种方式将数据加载到SQLite数据库中。
Well, you can load data into a SQLite database in at least two ways.
一会儿，我会做的，你可以
One, which I'll do in a moment, you can just
导入现有的平面文件数据库，例如CSV。
import an existing flat-file database, like a CSV.
您要做的就是将CSV保存在Mac或PC上的CS50 IDE上。
And what you do is you save the CSV on your Mac or PC on your CS50 IDE.
您可以使用sqlite3运行特殊命令。
You run a special command with sqlite3.
它将仅将CSV加载到内存中。
And it will just load the CSV into memory.
它将找出所有逗号在哪里。
It will figure out where all of the commas are.
它将在该二进制文件内部构造相应的行
And it will construct inside of that binary file the corresponding rows
和使用适当的0和1的列
and columns using the appropriate 0's and 1's
存储所有这些信息。
to store all of that information.
因此，它将自动为您导入。
So it just imports it for you automatically.
方法2是实际使用Python之类的语言编写代码
Approach 2 would be to actually write code in a language like Python
或任何其他实际手动插入所有数据的数据
or any other that actually manually inserts all of the data
到您的数据库中。
into your database.
我们也会这样做。
And we'll do that, as well.
但是，让我们从简单开始。
But let's start simple.
让我继续运行，例如sqlite3。
Let me go ahead and run, for instance, sqlite3.
这是预安装在CS50 IDE上的，安装起来并不难
And this is preinstalled on CS50 IDE, and it's not that hard to get it up
并可以在Mac和PC上运行。
and running on a Mac and PC, as well.
我将继续在此处的终端窗口中运行sqlite3。
I'm going to go ahead and run sqlite3 in my terminal window here.
和瞧。
And voila.
您只看到一些非常简单的输出。
You just see some very simple output.
它告诉我如果要查看一些使用提示，请键入.help。
It's telling me to type .help if I want to see some usage hints.
但是我知道大多数命令，我们通常会
But I know most of the commands, and we'll generally
提供您可能需要的所有命令。
give you all of the commands that you might need.
实际上，我们可以使用的命令之一是.mode，另一个是.import。
In fact, one of the commands that we can use is .mode, and another is .import.
因此，通常来说，您不会经常使用这些内容。
So generally, you won't use these that frequently.
仅当首次创建数据库时，才使用它们
You'll only use them when creating a database for the first time when
您是通过现有CSV文件创建该数据库的。
you are creating that database from an existing CSV file.
确实，这是我目前的目标。
And indeed, that's my goal at the moment.
让我来获取包含您所有喜欢的电视节目的CSV文件
Let me take our CSV file containing all of your favorite TV shows
并将其加载到适当的关系数据库中的SQLite中
and load it into SQLite in a proper relational database
这样我们可以做得比n的大O好
so that we can do better than, for instance, big O of n
当涉及到搜索数据并对其进行其他操作时。
when it comes to searching that data and doing anything else on it.
为此，我必须执行两个命令。
So to do this, I have to execute two commands.
第一，我需要将SQLite置于CSV模式。
One, I need to put SQLite into CSV mode.
这只是将其与其他平面文件格式区分开来，
And that's just to distinguish it from other flat-file formats,
例如用于制表符或其他格式的TSV。
like TSV for tabs or some other format.
现在，我将继续运行.import。
And now I'm going to go ahead and run .import.
然后，我必须指定要导入的文件的名称，即CSV。
Then I have to specify the name of the file to import, which is the CSV.
我将继续打电话给我的桌子秀。
And I'm going to go ahead and call my table shows.
因此，.import需要两个参数，即您要导入的文件的名称。
So .import takes two arguments, the name of the file that you want to import
以及要从该文件中创建的表的名称。
and the name of the table that you want to create out of that file.
同样，表具有行和列。
And again, tables have rows and columns.
文件中的逗号要划定
And the commas in the file are going to delineate
这些列的开始和结束位置。
where those columns begin and end.
我要继续并按Enter。
I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter.
看起来飞起来很快。
It looks like it flew by pretty fast.
似乎什么都没发生。
Nothing seems to have happened.
但我认为可以，因为现在我们要继续前进，并有能力
But I think that's OK, because now we're going to go ahead and have the ability
实际操作该数据。
to actually manipulate that data.
但是，我们如何处理数据？
But how do we manipulate the data?
我们需要一种新的语言。
We need a new language.
SQL，结构化查询语言，是SQLite和Oracle使用的语言
SQL, Structured Query Language, is the language used by SQLites and Oracle
和MySQL和PostgreSQL以及其他一系列产品
and MySQL and PostgreSQL and bunches of other products
您不需要很快就知道或记住其名字。
whose names you don't need to know or remember any time soon.
但是SQL是我们将用于查询数据库以获取信息的语言
But SQL is the language we'll use to query the database for information
并用它做点什么。
and do something with it.
一般而言，是一个关系数据库，然后是
Generally speaking, a relational database and, in turn,
SQL，这是一种您可以与关系数据库进行交互的语言，
SQL, which is a language via which you can interact with relational databases,
支持四个基本操作。
support four fundamental operations.
而且，它们只是一个粗略的缩写，是双关语的意思，
And they're sort of a crude acronym, pun intended,
只是有助于记住那些基本操作是什么
that is just helpful for remembering what those fundamental operations are
关系数据库。
with relational databases.
CRUD代表创建，读取，更新和删除。
CRUD stands for Create, Read, Update, and Delete.
实际上，首字母缩写是CRUD，CRUD。
And indeed, the acronym is CRUD, C-R-U-D.
因此，它可以帮助您记住任何设备支持的四个基本操作
So it helps you remember that the four basic operations supported by any
关系数据库被创建，读取，更新，删除。
relational database are create, read, update, delete.
“创建”是指创建或添加新数据。
"Create" means to create or add new data.
“读取”是指访问新数据并将新数据加载到内存中。
"Read" means to access and load into memory new data.
我们已经阅读过打开文件的内容。
We've seen read before with opening files.
同样，“更新”和“删除”的含义也是如此，
"Update" and "delete" mean exactly that, as well,
如果要操作数据集中的数据。
if you want to manipulate the data in your data set.
现在，这些是任何关系数据库的通用术语。
Now, those are generic terms for any relational database.
这些是任何关系数据库通常支持的四个属性。
Those are the four properties typically supported by any relational database.
在SQL的世界中，有一些非常具体的命令或功能，
In the world of SQL, there are some very specific commands or functions,
如果您愿意，则可以实现这四个功能。
if you will, that implement those four functionalities.
它们是创建并插入-
They are create and insert--
实现与更普遍地创建相同的功能。
achieve the same thing as create more generally.
关键字“选择”是用于从数据库读取数据的关键字。
The keyword "select" is what's used to read data from a database.
更新和删除相同。
Update and delete are the same.
因此，这是一种令人讨厌的不一致。
So it's kind of an annoying inconsistency.
首字母缩略词或术语是CRUD，创建，读取，更新，删除。
The acronym or the term of art is CRUD, Create, Read, Update, Delete.
但是在SQL的世界里，语言的作者
But in the world of SQL, the authors of the language
决定通过方式实施这四个想法
decided to implement those four ideas by way
这五个关键字，功能或命令（如果需要）中的一种
of these five keywords or functions or commands, if you will, in the language
SQL。
SQL.
所以您要看的是其中五个关键字
So what you are looking at are five of the keywords
您可以使用这种称为SQL的新语言来实际执行某项操作
that you can use in this new language called SQL to actually do something
与您的数据库。
with your database.
这是什么意思？
Now, what does that mean?
好吧，假设您想手动创建
Well, suppose that you wanted to manually create
第一次建立数据库。
a database for the very first time.
你做什么工作？
What do you do?
好吧，回到电子表格的世界，这很简单，对吧？
Well, back in the world of spreadsheets, it's pretty straightforward, right?
您将打开Google Spreadsheets。
You'd open up Google Spreadsheets.
您转到“文件”，“新建”或其他内容。
You go to File, New or whatever.
然后，您就可以得到一个新的电子表格
And then you just, voila, get a new spreadsheet
您可以在其中开始创建行和列等。
into which you can start creating rows and columns and the like.
在Microsoft Excel中，Apple Numbers同样是-
In Microsoft Excel, Apple Numbers, same thing--
“文件”菜单，“新建电子表格”或其他任何东西，以及繁荣，您都有一个新的电子表格。
File menu, New Spreadsheet or whatever, and boom, you have a new spreadsheet.
现在，在SQL世界中，SQL数据库通常是
Now, in the world of SQL, SQL databases are generally
旨在与代码进行交互。
meant to be interacted with code.
但是，有图形用户界面，GUI，通过它们
However, there are Graphical User Interfaces, GUIs, by which
您也可以与他们互动。
you can interact with them, as well.
但是，我们今天将使用代码来执行此操作，并在命令行中使用程序。
But we're going to use code today to do so and programs at a command line.
事实证明，您可以通过编程方式创建表
It turns out that you can create tables programmatically
通过运行这样的命令。
by running a command like this.
因此，如果您按照CREATE TABLE的方式逐字输入语法，则
So if you literally type out syntax along the lines of CREATE TABLE, then
表格名称，以小写字母表示，
the name of your table, indicated here in lowercase,
然后是一个括号，然后是您要创建的列的名称
then a parenthesis, then the name of your column that you want to create
以及该列的类型（la C），然后是逗号，点，
and the type of that column, a la C, and then comma, dot,
点，点，更多列，这通常是
dot, dot, some more columns, this is generally
说出您将用这种语言创建的语法，称为
speaking the syntax you'll use to create in this language called
SQL一个新表。
SQL a new table.
现在，这是抽象的。
Now, this is in the abstract.
同样，小写的表代表名称
Again, table in lowercase is meant to represent the name
你想给你的实际表。
you want to give to your actual table.
小写的列是名称
column in lowercase is meant to be the name
您想给自己的专栏。
you want to give to your own column.
也许是标题。
Maybe it's Title.
也许是流派。
Maybe it's Genres.
点，点，点只是意味着，当然，您
And dot, dot, dot just means, of course, you
可以有更多的列。
can have even more columns than that.
但是从字面上看，如果我要键入这种命令
But literally in a moment, if I were to type in this kind of command
运行sqlite3程序后进入终端窗口，
into the terminal window after running the sqlite3 program,
我可以开始为自己创建一个或多个表。
I could start creating one or more tables for myself.
实际上，这就是我已经发生的事情。
And in fact, that's what already happened for me.
此.import命令不是SQL的一部分-
This .import command, which is not part of SQL--
这等效于Excel或Google Spreadsheets中的“菜单”选项。
this is the equivalent of a Menu option in Excel or Google Spreadsheets.
.import只是为我自动化了一个特定的过程。
.import just automates a certain process for me.
它为我所做的就是这个。
And what it did for me is this.
如果我现在输入.schema，这是另一个SQLite特定命令-
If I type now .schema, which is another SQLite-specific command--
以。开头的任何东西。仅针对sqlite3，
anything that starts with a . is specific only to sqlite3,
该终端窗口程序。
this terminal window program.
注意输出的是这个。
Notice what's outputted is this.
通过运行对我自动执行的.import，在数据库中创建了一个表
By running .import that automatically for me created a table in my database
叫做表演。
called shows.
它给了它三列
And it gave it three columns--
时间戳记，标题和流派。
Timestamp, title, and genres.
这些列名称从何而来？
Where did those column names come from?
好吧，它们来自CSV的第一行。
Well, they came from the very first line in the CSV.
它们看起来都像文本，所以这些值的类型
And they all looked like text, so the type of those values
只是假设是文本，文本，文本。
was just assumed to be text, text, text.
现在，要明确一点，我可以手动输入此信息，
Now, to be clear, I could have manually type this out,
在名为shows的新表中创建了这三列。
created these three columns in a new table called shows for me.
但同样，.import命令只是从CSV中自动执行该命令。
But again, the .import command just automated that from a CSV.
但是，SQL是我们在这里看到的，CREATE TABLE显示了等等。
But the SQL is what we see here, CREATE TABLE shows and so forth.
就是说，现在，在这个数据库中，有一个文件-
So that is to say now, in this database, there is a file--
或者更确切地说，里面有一个名为shows的表
or rather, there is a table called shows inside
其中是来自该CSV的所有数据。
of which is all of the data from that CSV.
我实际上如何获得这些数据？
How do I actually get at that data?
好吧，事实证明还有其他命令被调用了。
Well, it turns out there's other commands were called.
事实证明，不仅创建，而且选择。
Not just CREATE, but also SELECT, it turns out.
SELECT相当于读取，从数据库中获取数据。
SELECT is the equivalent of read, getting data from the database.
这个功能非常强大。
And this one is pretty powerful.
以及之所以有如此多的数据科学家和统计学家
And the reason that so many data scientists and statisticians
使用并喜欢使用SQL之类的语言-
use and like using languages like SQL--
他们使得获取数据和过滤数据相对容易
they make it relatively easy to just get data and filter that data
并使用今天适用于我们的新语法分析数据，
and analyze that data using new syntax for us today,
但是相对于我们已经看到的其他东西而言，语法相对简单。
but relatively simple syntax relative to other things we've seen.
SQL中的SELECT命令使您可以选择一列或多列
The SELECT command in SQL lets you select one or more columns
从您的表中按给定的名称。
from your table by the given name.
因此，我们现在将在这里过一会儿。
So we'll see this now in just a moment here.
我该怎么做呢？
How might I go about doing this?
好吧，让我继续，现在，只是在清除窗口后，在我的提示下
Well, let me go ahead and now, at my prompt after just clearing the window
为了保持整洁，让我尝试一下。
to keep things neat, let me try this out.
让我继续进行选择，例如，标题FROM显示;。
Let me go ahead and SELECT, let's say, title FROM shows;.
那我为什么要这样做呢？
So why am I doing this?
嗯，再次，SELECT命令的常规格式
Well, again, the conventional format for the SELECT command
是说SELECT，然后是一列或多列的名称，然后
is to say SELECT, then the name of one or more columns, then
从字面上看是介词FROM，然后是您从中使用的表的名称
literally the preposition FROM, and then the name of the table from which you
要选择该数据。
want to select that data.
因此，如果我的表格称为shows，而该列称为title，
So if my table is called shows and the column is called title,
有理由说SELECT标题FROM节目应该给我
it stands to reason that SELECT title FROM shows should give me
备份我想要的数据。
back the data I want.
现在，请注意几个样式选择
Now, notice a couple of stylistic choices
并不是严格要求的，但是是好的样式。
that aren't strictly required but are good style.
按照惯例，我会大写任何SQL关键字，
Conventionally, I would capitalize any SQL keywords,
在这种情况下包括SELECT和FROM，然后
including SELECT and FROM in this case, and then
将列名或表名都小写，
lowercase anything that's a column name or a table name,
假设您实际上以小写形式创建了这些列和表。
assuming you created those columns and tables in, in fact, lowercase.
那里有不同的约定。
There's different conventions out there.
有些人会大写。
Some people will uppercase.
有些人会使用称为骆驼箱或蛇皮箱之类的东西。
Some people will use something called camel case or snake case or the like.
但总的来说，我会鼓励所有上限
But generally speaking, I would encourage all caps
表示SQL语法，小写表示列和表名。
for SQL syntax and lowercase for the column and table names.
我现在要继续并按Enter。
I'm going to go ahead now and hit Enter.
和瞧。
And voila.
我们迅速看到了从数据库输出的值的完整列表。
We see rapidly a whole list of values outputted from the database.
如果回想起来，您可能会意识到这实际上是
And if you think way back, you might recognize that this actually
恰好与以前的顺序相同，因为CSV
happens to be the same order as before, because the CSV
文件从上到下被加载到同一数据库表中。
file was loaded top to bottom into this same database table.
因此，实际上，我们看到的是所有相同的数据，重复的
And so what we're seeing, in fact, is all of that same data, duplicates
以及资本缩水，怪异的间距等等。
and miscapitalizations and weird spacing and all.
但是，假设我想查看CSV中的所有数据。
But suppose I want to see all of the data from the CSV.
好吧，事实证明您可以选择多个列。
Well, it turns out you can select multiple columns.
您不仅可以选择标题，还可以选择时间戳。
You can select not only title, but maybe timestamp was of interest.
而且这个人当然是大写的，因为那是
And this one admittedly was capitalized, because that's
电子表格中的内容。
what it was in the spreadsheet.
那不是我手动选择的。
That was not something I chose manually.
因此，如果我只使用逗号分隔的列名列表，
So if I just use a comma-separated list of column names,
注意我现在能做什么。
notice what I can do now.
对于我们人类来说，这有点困难，因为现在发生了很多事情。
It's a little hard to see for us humans, because there's a lot going on now.
但是请注意，在左侧用双引号括起来，
But notice that in double quotes on the left,
有所有的时间戳，代表你们所有人的时间
there are all of the timestamps, which represent the time at which you all
提交了您喜欢的节目。
submitted your favorite shows.
在逗号右边，还有另一个带引号的字符串
And on the right of the comma, there's another quoted string
这是您喜欢的节目的标题，尽管使用SQLite
that is the title of the show that you liked, although SQLite
按照惯例，如果只是一个单词（例如“朋友”），则省略引号。
omits the quotes if it's just a single word, like Friends, just by convention.
实际上，如果我想获取所有列，
In fact, if I want to get all of the columns,
原来有一些速记语法。
turns out there's some shorthand syntax for that.
*是所谓的通配符运算符。
* is the so-called wild card operator.
这将使我获得表中从左到右的所有列。
And it will get me all of the columns from left to right in my table.
和瞧。
And voila.
现在，我看到了所有数据，包括所有流派。
Now I see all of the data, including all of the genres, as well.
所以现在我实际上在这里一次输出了三列。
So now I effectively have three columns being outputted all at once here.
好吧，到目前为止，这还没有那么有用。
Well, this is not that useful thus far.
实际上，我一直在做的只是输出
In fact, all I've been doing is really just outputting
CSV的内容。
the contents of the CSV.
但是SQL之所以强大，是因为它具有其他功能，即开即用，
But SQL's powerful because it comes with other features right out of the box,
在精神上与Google Spreadsheets中内置的功能有些相似
somewhat similar in spirit to functions that are built into Google Spreadsheets
和Excel。
and Excel.
但是现在我们可以最终在我们自己的代码中使用它们了。
But now we can use them ultimately in our own code.
因此，像AVG，COUNT，DISTINCT，LOWER，MAX，MIN，
So functions like AVG, COUNT, DISTINCT, LOWER, MAX, MIN,
和UPPER等更多功能，这些都是SQL内置的功能
and UPPER and bunches more, these are all functions built into SQL
您可以将其用作查询的一部分，以在返回数据时更改数据
that you can use as part of your query to alter the data as it's coming back
从数据库中获取-不是永久的，而是
from the database-- not permanently, but as it's
回到您的位置-使其具有您真正关心的格式。
coming back to you-- so that it's in a format you actually care about.
例如，我之前的目标之一
So for instance, one of my goals earlier,
是为了找回独特的，独特的头衔。
was to get back just the distinct, the unique titles.
而且我们必须使用一组代码编写所有烦人的代码
And we had to write all that annoying code using a set
然后将内容添加到集合中，然后再次遍历，对吗？
and then add things to the set and then loop over it again, right?
那不是大量的代码。
That was not a huge amount of code.
但是，至少要花5、10分钟才能完成这项工作。
But it definitely took us, what, 5, 10 minutes to get the job done at least.
在SQL中，您可以一口气完成所有这些工作。
In SQL, you can do all of that in one breath.
我现在要继续执行此操作。
I'm going to go ahead now and do this.
SELECT不仅显示标题FROM。
SELECT not just title FROM shows.
让我继续，并显示SELECT DISTINCT标题FROM。
Let me go ahead and SELECT DISTINCT title FROM shows.
因此，DISTINCT再次是SQL中的可用函数
So DISTINCT, again, is an available function in SQL
顾名思义，那就做到了。
that does what the name says.
它会过滤掉所有标题
It's going to filter out all of the titles
只给我与众不同的东西
to just give me the distinct ones back.
因此，如果我现在按Enter键，您会看到一个类似的混乱列表，但其中包括-
So if I hit Enter now, you'll see a similarly messy list but including--
“不知道，”不看电视的人-
"no idea," someone that doesn't watch TV--
包括这些标题的未排序列表。
including an unsorted list of those titles.
因此，我认为我们可能可以像以前一样开始清理此东西。
So I think we can probably start to clean this thing up as we did before.
让我继续，现在选择不仅是DISTINCT，
Let me go ahead and now SELECT not just DISTINCT,
但让我继续，并将所有内容都大写。
but let me go ahead and uppercase everything as well.
我可以将UPPER用作另一个功能。
And I can use UPPER as another function.
请注意，我只是在嵌套东西。
And notice I'm just nesting things.
正如我们现在在多种语言中所看到的，一个函数的输出，
The output of one function, as we've seen in many languages now,
可以作为另一个的输入。
can be the input to another.
让我现在按Enter键。
Let me hit Enter now.
现在，它变得更加规范了，可以这么说，
And now it's getting a little more canonicalized, so to speak,
因为我对所有内容都使用大写。
because I'm using capitalization for everything.
但是似乎事情仍然没有得到真正的解决。
But it would seem that things still aren't really sorted.
这与您输入的顺序相同
It's just the same order in which you inputted them
但这次没有重复。
but without duplicates this time.
因此事实证明，SQL具有其他语法
So it turns out that SQL has other syntax
我们可以用来使查询更精确，更强大。
that we can use to make our queries more precise and more powerful.
所以除了这些功能
So in addition to these kinds of functions
您可以用来更改显示给您的数据
that you can use to alter the data that's being shown to you
然后回来，您也可以使用这些子句或语法
and coming back, you can also use these kinds of clauses or syntax
在SQL查询中。
in SQL queries.
您可以说WHERE，它相当于一个条件。
You can say WHERE, which is the equivalent of a condition.
您可以说选择所有正确或错误的数据。
You can say select all of this data where something is true or false.
您可以说喜欢，在这里您可以说给我的数据不完全是这样
You can say LIKE, where you can say give me data that isn't exactly this
但是就是这样
but is like this.
您可以按某一列对数据进行排序。
You can order the data by some column.
您可以限制返回的行数。
You can limit the number of rows that come back.
您可以通过某种方式将相同的值分组在一起。
And you can group identical values together in some way.
因此，让我们看一些例子。
So let's see a few examples of this.
让我回到这里，现在和...一起玩
Let me go back here and play around now with--
办公室怎么样？
how about The Office?
那就是我们前面看过的那个。
That was the one we looked at earlier.
因此，让我继续，SELECT title FROM显示WHERE title =“ The Office”;。
So let me go ahead and SELECT title FROM shows WHERE title = "The Office";.
因此，我添加了这个WHERE谓词，可以这么说，WHERE title =“ The Office”。
So I've added this WHERE predicate, so to speak, WHERE title = "The Office."
因此，SQL很不错。
So SQL's nice.
与Python的精神相似，它可能更加用户友好，
Similar in spirit to Python, it's more user friendly, perhaps,
比C的东西都读起来像一个英语句子，
than C where everything kind of sort of reads like an English sentence,
即使更精确。
even though it's a little more precise.
而且更加简洁。
And it's a little more succinct.
让我继续并按Enter。
Let me go ahead and hit Enter.
和瞧。
And voila.
那就是您输入The Office的人数。
That's how many of you inputted The Office.
但是请注意，不是所有人，不是吗？
But notice it's not everyone, is it?
我们仍然缺少一些。
We're missing some still.
看来，我只回覆了那些从字面上输入的人
It seems that I got back only those of you who typed in literally
“办公室”，大写字母T，大写字母O。
"The Office," capital T, capital O.
那么，如果我想变得比以前更有弹性呢？
So what if I want to be a little more resilient than that?
好吧，让我找回所有您在“办公室”中键入的行。
Well, let me get back any rows where you all typed in "office."
也许您省略了文章“ the”。
Maybe you omitted the article "the."
因此，让我继续前进，不要说title =“ Office”。
So let me go ahead and say not title = "Office."
但让我继续说一下标题在哪里，例如“ Office”。
but let me go ahead and say where the title is like "Office."
但是我不希望它只是“办公室”。
But I don't want it to just be "office."
我想在开始时允许一些东西，也许一些东西
I want to allow for maybe some stuff at the beginning, maybe some stuff
在最后。
at the end.
即使那看起来有点矛盾，
And even though that seems like a bit of an inconsistency,
在使用LIKE的情况下，还有另一个通配符。
in the context of using LIKE, there's another wild card character.
百分号表示左侧的零个或多个字符。
The percent sign represents zero or more characters to the left.
这个百分号代表右边的零个或多个字符。
And this percent sign represents zero or more characters to the right.
因此，这种包罗万象的东西现在可以在某个地方找到我的所有标题
So it's kind of this catchall that will now find me all titles that somewhere
在他们里面有办公室。
have O-F-F-I-C-E inside of them.
事实证明，LIKE不区分大小写，
And it turns out LIKE is case insensitive,
因此，我什至不必担心LIKE的大写字母。
so I don't even need to worry about capitalization with LIKE.
现在让我按Enter。
Now let me hit Enter.
和瞧。
And voila.
现在，我得到了更多答案。
Now I get back more answers.
现在您可以真正看到混乱了。
And you can really see the messiness now.
注意这里您使用的是小写字母。
Notice up here one of you used lowercase.
在快速键入内容时，这通常很常见。
That tends to be common when typing things in quickly.
你们中的一个人在这里做了小写，然后还给了
One of you did it lowercase here and then also gave
最后给我们额外的空白。
us an extra white space at the end.
你们其中一位刚刚输入了“办公室”。
One of you just typed in "office."
你们其中一位再次输入“办公室”，并在末尾加一个空格。
One of you typed in "the office" again with a space at the end.
因此，这里有很多变化。
And so there's a lot of variation here.
这就是为什么当我们将所有内容都强制为大写时
And that's why, when we forced everything to uppercase
然后我们开始修剪东西，我们得以摆脱
and we started trimming things, we were able to get rid
这些冗余中的许多。
of a lot of those redundancies.
好吧，事实上，让我们现在就开始订购吧。
Well, in fact, let's go ahead and order this now.
因此，让我回到选择独特的大写标题的过程中，
So let me go back to selecting the distinct uppercase title,
因此显示标题FROM的SELECT DISTINCT UPPER。
so SELECT DISTINCT UPPER of title FROM shows.
现在让我来ORDER BY，这是一个新的子句，大写版本
And let me now ORDER BY, which is a new clause, the uppercased version
头衔。
of title.
现在，请注意这里发生了一些事情。
So now notice there's a few things going on here.
但我只是建立更复杂的查询
But I'm just building up more complicated queries
类似于从头开始，在这里我们开始抛出越来越多的谜题
similar to scratch, where we just started throwing more and more puzzle
出现问题。
pieces at a problem.
我正在从shows表中选择所有不同的大写标题。
I'm selecting all of the distinct uppercase titles from the shows table.
但是这次我要订购结果
But I'm going to order the results this time
标题的大写形式。
by the uppercased version of title.
因此，所有内容都将大写。
So everything is going to be uppercased.
然后将其从A到Z进行排序。点击Enter，
And then it's going to be sorted A through Z. Hit Enter now,
现在事情变得更容易理解了。
and now things are a little easier to make sense of.
请注意，仅当标题中包含多个单词时，引号才会出现。
Notice the quotes are there only when there are multiple words in a title.
否则，sqlite3不会显示给我们。
Otherwise, sqlite3 doesn't bother showing us.
但是请注意，这里是所有“ the”节目。
But notice here's all the "the" shows.
如果我们继续向上滚动，则P，N，M，L等
And if we keep scrolling up, the P's, the N's, the M's, the L's, and so
第四-确实是按字母顺序排列的，这要归功于使用ORDER BY。
forth-- it's indeed alphabetized thanks to using ORDER BY.
好的。
All right.
好吧，让我们现在开始解决更多类似的SQL问题
Well, let's start to solve more similar problems now in SQL
与以前用Python编写的代码相比，编写的代码更少了。
by writing way less code than we did a bit ago in Python.
假设我想实际算出这些最受欢迎节目的数量。
Suppose I want to actually figure out the counts of these most popular shows.
所以我想合并所有相同的节目
So I want to combine all of the identical shows
并找出所有相应的计数。
and figure out all of the corresponding counts.
好吧，让我继续尝试一下。
Well, let me go ahead and try this.
让我继续并再次选择标题的大写版本。
Let me go ahead and SELECT again the uppercased version of title.
但是这次我不会做DISTINCT，因为我
But I'm not going to do DISTINCT this time, because I
想要做一些不同的事情。
want to do that a little differently.
我要选择大写版本
I'm going to SELECT the uppercased version
标题中的COUNT个，
of title, the COUNT of those titles--
因此给定标题出现的次数，因此COUNT
so the number of times a given title appears, so COUNT
现在是一个新关键字-
is a new keyword now--
从节目。
FROM shows.
但是，现在我如何弄清楚计数是多少？
But now how do I figure out what the count is?
好吧，如果您认为这张桌子有很多标题，
Well, if you think about this table as having a lot of titles--
标题，标题，标题，标题，标题-
title, title, title, title, title--
最好将相同的标题归为一组
it would be nice to kind of group the identical titles together
然后实际上算出我们归类了多少个这样的标题。
and then actually count how many such titles we grouped together.
而其语法实际上是说GROUP BY UPPER（title）;。
And the syntax for that is literally to say GROUP BY UPPER(title);.
这告诉SQL将所有大写的标题分组
This tells SQL to group all of the uppercased titles
一起，将多行合拢为一，
together, kind of collapse multiple rows into one,
但要跟踪崩溃后的标题计数。
but keep track of the count of titles after that collapse.
现在让我继续，然后按Enter。
Let me go ahead now and hit Enter.
您会看到，与我们编写的较早的Python程序之一非常相似，
And you'll see, very similar to one of the earlier Python programs we wrote,
左侧的所有标题后面都带有逗号，然后是计数。
all of the titles on the left followed by a comma, followed by the count.
所以你们中的一个真的很喜欢汤姆和杰里。
So one of you really likes Tom and Jerry.
你们当中的一位真的很喜欢Top Gear。
One of you really likes Top Gear.
但是，如果我向上滚动，其中两个人真的很喜欢The Wire。
If I scroll up, though, two of you really liked The Wire.
你们当中有23个人像The Office，尽管我们仍然
23 of you here like The Office, although we still
还没有在这里解决这个问题。
haven't trimmed the issue here.
因此，如果需要，我们仍然可以通过修剪空白将其进一步结合。
So we could still combine that further by trimming whitespace if we want.
但是现在我们得到了这些计数。
But now we're getting these kinds of counts.
好吧，我该像以前一样继续订购吗？
Well, how can I go ahead and order this, as we did before?
让我继续在此处添加标题的“ ORDER BY COUNT”
Let me go ahead here and add ORDER BY COUNT of title
然后立即打分号。
and then hit semicolon now.
现在请注意，就像在Python中一样，
And now notice, just as in Python, everything
从最初的最小到最大，通过《权力的游戏》
is from smallest to largest initially, with Game of Thrones
在这里落在底部。
here down on the bottom.
我怎样才能解决这个问题？
How can I fix this?
好吧，事实证明，如果您可以按降序排序，
Well, it turns out if you can order things in descending order,
简称DESC，而不是ASC，这是默认的升序-
D-E-S-C for short instead of A-S-C, which is the default for ascending--
所以如果我按降序排列，现在我必须一直滚动到上一步
so if I do it in descending order, now I'd have to scroll all the way back up
到A的最上方，以查看线条的起点。
to the A's, the very top, to see where the lines begin.
哎呀
Whoops.
如果我一直滚动回到顶部，我们将看到所有A字在哪里
If I scroll all the way back up to the top, we'll see where all of the A words
在这里开始。
begin up here.
现在，如果我想-
And now if I want to--
哎呀，哎呀，哎呀。
whoops, whoops, whoops.
我做对了吗？
Did I do that right?
对不起。
Sorry.
我不想-
I don't want to--
我们去了，ORDER BY COUNT降序。
there we go, ORDER BY COUNT descending.
现在，让我继续前进-这有点笨拙，看不到。
Now let me go ahead and-- this is just a little too unwieldy to see.
让我将自己限制在前十名并保持简单
Let me just limit myself to the top 10 and keep it simple
并且仅查看此处的前10个值。
and only look at the top 10 values here.
瞧。
Voila.
现在我有33岁的权力游戏，26岁的朋友，23岁的办公室-
Now I have Game of Thrones at 33, Friends at 26, The Office at 23--
尽管我认为我仍然缺少一些。
though I think I'm still missing a few.
Brian，您还记得修剪前导和尾随的SQL函数吗？
Brian, do you recall the SQL function for trimming leading and trailing
空白？
white space?
布莱恩·于：我认为这只是TRIM。
BRIAN YU: I think it's just TRIM.
DAVID J. MALAN：TRIM？
DAVID J. MALAN: TRIM?
好的。
OK.
我自己不记得了。
I myself did not remember.
因此，如有疑问，请谷歌或询问Brian。
So when in doubt, google or ask Brian.
因此，让我继续进行修复。
So let me go ahead and fix this.
让我继续，首先选择大写的标题。
Let me go ahead and SELECT uppercase of trimming the title first.
然后我要进行GROUP BY修剪，然后在上面大写。
And then I'm going to GROUP BY trimming and then uppercasing it there.
现在进入，瞧。
And now Enter, and voila.
谢谢你，布莱恩。
Thank you, Brian.
因此，现在我们在这里拥有26个办事处。
So now we're up to our 26 Offices here.
简而言之，我们花了一些时间才能得到
So in short, it took us a little while to get
到此为止，SQL中的故事。
to this point in the story in SQL.
但是请注意我们所做的。
But notice what we've done.
我们采取了一个程序，这花了我们几分钟
We've taken a program that took us a few minutes
当然还有十几行或更多行代码。
and certainly a dozen or more lines of code.
我们已经将其提炼成一种新语言
And we've distilled it into something that, yes, is a new language
但只是一个班轮。
but is just kind of a one liner.
一旦您熟悉了SQL之类的语言，
And once you get comfortable with a language like SQL,
特别是如果您甚至不是计算机科学家，但也许是数据专家
especially if you're not even a computer scientist but maybe a data
花费大量时间寻找的科学家或某种分析师
scientist or an analyst of some sort who spends a lot of their day looking
在财务信息或医疗信息上
at financial information or medical information
或实际上可以加载到行和列中的任何数据集，
or really any data set that can be loaded into rows and columns,
一旦您开始讲和阅读SQL即可
once you start to speak and read SQL as a human can
您开始相对简洁地表达一些非常强大的查询
you start to express some pretty powerful queries relatively succinctly
繁荣起来，找回你的答案。
and, boom, get back your answer.
通过使用命令行程序（例如sqlite3），
And by using a command line program, like sqlite3,
您可以立即在此处看到结果，尽管它是非常简单的文本。
you can immediately see the results there, albeit as very simplistic text.
但是也如上所述，还有一些图形程序
But as mentioned, too, there's also some graphical programs
既免费又商业的，也支持SQL，您仍然可以在其中
out there, free and commercial, that also support SQL, where you can still
键入这些命令。
type these commands.
然后它将以一种更加用户友好的方式向您显示
And then it will show it to you in a more user friendly way, much
例如在Windows或macOS中默认情况下。
like in Windows or macOS would by default.
那么，现在对SELECT语句的语法或功能有任何疑问吗？
So any questions now on the syntax or capabilities of SELECT statements?
布莱恩·于：一个问题来了。
BRIAN YU: One question came in.
带有此数据的文件实际存储在哪里？
Where is the file with this data actually being stored?
DAVID J. MALAN：好问题。
DAVID J. MALAN: Good question.
文件实际存储在哪里？
Where is the file actually being stored?
因此，在退出之前，我实际上可以将此文件另存为任何文件。
So before quitting, I can actually save this file as anything.
我希望文件扩展名通常是.db。
I want the file extension would typically be .db.
实际上，布莱恩，您介意检查一下吗？
And in fact, Brian, do you mind just checking?
用点东西手动写入文件的语法是什么？
What's the syntax for writing the file manually with dot something?
我认为这将在.help下。
It would be under .help, I think.
BRIAN YU：我认为它是.save，后面跟着文件名。
BRIAN YU: I think it's .save followed by the name of the file.
DAVID J. MALAN：.save，所以我将其命名为shows.db，然后按Enter。
DAVID J. MALAN: .save, so I'll call this shows.db, Enter.
如果我现在继续打开另一个终端窗口，然后键入
If I now go ahead and open up another terminal window and type
我们的老朋友ls，您现在会看到我有一个CSV文件。
our old friend ls, you'll see that now I have a CSV file.
我有以前的Python文件。
I have my Python file from before.
我已经创建了一个名为shows.db的新文件。
And I have a new file called shows.db, which I've created.
那是包含我动态加载的表的二进制文件
That is the binary file that contains the table that I've loaded dynamically
从该CSV文件输入。
in from that CSV file.
关于SELECT查询还有其他问题，或者我们可以如何处理？
Any other questions on SELECT queries or what we can do with them?
布莱恩·于（Brian Yu）：是的，有人在问这是什么时间。
BRIAN YU: Yeah, a few people are asking about what the runtime of this is.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的，这是一个很好的问题。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, really good question.
什么是运行时？
What is the runtime?
如果可以的话，我将稍等一下。
I'm going to come back to that question in just a little bit if that's OK.
现在，公认的是n的大O。
Right now, it's admittedly big O of n.
我实际上没有比我们做得更好
I've not actually done anything better than we did
与我们的CSV文件或我们的Python代码一起使用。
with our CSV file or our Python code.
现在，默认情况下它仍然是n的大O。
Right now, it's still big O of n by default.
但这将有一个更好的答案
But there's going to be a better answer to that
这将使它更具对数性。
that's going to make it something much more logarithmic.
因此，当我要启用该功能时，让我回到该功能。
So let me come back to that feature when it's time to enable it.
但实际上，让我们开始采取一些措施。
But in fact, let's start to take some steps toward that.
因为事实证明，在加载数据时，
Because it turns out, when loading in data,
我们并不总是会拥有
we're not always going to have the luxury of just
我们导入了一个CSV格式的大文件，
having one big file in CSV format that we import,
然后我们开展业务。
and we go about our business.
我们将必须预先决定如何
We're going to have to decide in advance how
我们要存储数据以及要存储什么数据
we want to store the data and what data we want to store
以及可能存在的关系不是一个
and what the relationships might be across not one
单个表，但多个表。
single table, but multiple tables.
所以让我继续在这里运行另一个命令
So let me go ahead and run one other command here
实际上引入了第一个问题。
that actually introduces the first of a problem.
让我继续，并显示SELECT标题FROM
Let me go ahead and SELECT title FROM shows
例如，“流派”等于“喜剧”。
WHERE genres equals, for instance, "Comedy."
那是流派之一。
That was one of the genres.
并注意，我们得到了很多结果。
And notice that we get back a whole bunch of results.
但是我敢打赌我会想念一些。
But I bet I'm missing some.
我正在快速浏览一下。
I'm skimming through this pretty quickly.
但是我敢打赌我会错过一些，因为如果我检查类型是否
But I bet I'm missing some, because if I check if genres
=“喜剧”，我要省略什么？
= "Comedy," what am I omitting?
好吧，那些选中了多个复选框的人可能会说些什么
Well, those of you who checked multiple boxes might have said something
是一部喜剧和戏剧或喜剧和浪漫片
is a comedy and a drama or comedy and romance
或其他几种流派的排列。
or maybe a couple of other permutations of genres.
如果我在这里寻找平等，=“喜剧”
If I'm searching for equality here, = "Comedy,"
我只会从您那里得到您最喜欢的内容，
I'm only going to get those favorites from you where you only said,
我最喜欢的电视节目是喜剧。
my favorite TV show is a comedy.
但是，如果我们想做类似喜剧这样的事情怎么办？
But what if we want to do something like LIKE comedy instead?
我们可以说，好久了
And we could say something like, well, so long
因为其中有“喜剧”一词，所以我们应该获得更多结果。
as the word "comedy" is in there, then we should get back even more results.
而且，我要指出的是，的确，我现在拥有更长的结果列表。
And let me stipulate that, indeed, I now have a longer list of results.
现在，我们可以在所有节目中至少选中“喜剧”框。
Now we have all shows where you checked at least the Comedy box.
但不幸的是，这开始变得有点草率，
But unfortunately, this starts to get a little sloppy,
因为请记住“类型”列的外观。
because recall what the Genres column looks like.
选择。
SELECT.
让我从节目中选择流派；
Let me SELECT genres FROM shows;.
请注意，我们从CSV加载到此表中的所有流派
Notice that all of the genres that we loaded into this table from the CSV
文件是用逗号分隔的流派列表。
file are a comma-separated list of genres.
这就是Google Forms做到的方式。
That's just the way Google Forms did it.
这对于CSV来说很好。
And that's fine for CSV purposes.
出于SQL目的，这很好，但这有点混乱。
That's kind of fine for SQL purposes, but this is kind of messy.
一般而言，存储逗号分隔的列表
Generally speaking, storing comma-separated lists
SQL数据库中值的取值不是您应该做的。
of values in a SQL database is not what you should be doing.
使用SQL数据库的全部目的是摆脱逗号和CSV
The whole point of using a SQL database is to move away from commas and CSVs
并更干净地存储东西。
and to actually store things more cleanly.
因为实际上，让我提出一个问题。
Because in fact, let me propose a problem.
假设我不想搜寻喜剧，但也许也搜寻
Suppose I want to search not for comedy but maybe also
像这样的音乐，因此让我可以找到任何节目
music, like this, thereby allowing me to find any shows where
“音乐”一词在逗号分隔的列表中。
the word "music" is somewhere in the comma-separated list.
这里有一个细微的错误。
There's a subtle bug here.
您可能需要回想一下我们从哪里开始，表格
And you might have to think back to where we began, the form
你拉起来。
that you pulled up.
我无法在此处显示全部内容，但我们
I can't show the whole thing here, but we
从动作，冒险，动画，传记，点，点，点开始，
started with action, adventure, animation, biography, dot, dot, dot,
音乐。
music.
音乐剧也在那里，如此与众不同。
Musical was also there, so distinct.
音乐录影带和音乐录影带是两种不同类型的流派。
A music video versus a musical are two different types of genres.
但是请注意我的询问。
But notice my query at the moment.
这有什么问题？
What's problematic with this?
目前，我们似乎有一个错误，该查询将选择
At the moment, we would seem to have a bug whereby this query will select
不仅是“音乐”，而且是“音乐”。
not only "music," but also "musical."
所以这就是事情变得混乱的地方。
And so this is just where things are getting messy.
现在，是的，你知道吗？
Now, yeah, you know what?
我们可以清理一下。
We could kind of clean this up.
也许我们可以在这里加一个逗号，这样它就不仅仅是音乐。
Maybe we could put a comma here so that it can't just be music something.
它必须是音乐逗号。
It has to be music comma.
但是，如果音乐是您选中的最后一个框，该怎么办？
But what if music is the last box that you checked?
好吧，那就没音乐了。
Well, then it's music nothing.
没有逗号。
There is no comma.
所以现在我需要对事物进行“或”运算。
So now I need to OR things together.
因此，也许我必须执行WHERE“％Music，％”之类的操作
So maybe I have to do something like WHERE "%Music,%"
或OR风格，例如“％Music”。
like this or OR genres LIKE "%Music" like this.
但老实说，这只是一团糟。
But honestly, this is just getting messy.
这是设计不良的。
This is poorly designed.
如果您只是将数据存储为内部以逗号分隔的值列表
If you're just storing your data as a comma-separated list of values inside
列，您必须借助这种技巧来弄清楚，
of a column and you have to resort to this kind of hack to figure out,
好吧，也许是在这里，这里或这里，
well, maybe it's over here or here or here,
考虑到语法的所有排列，您做错了。
and thinking about all the permutations of syntax, you're doing it wrong.
您没有充分利用SQL数据库的潜力。
You're not using a SQL database to its fullest potential.
那么我们如何更好地设计这个东西
So how do we go about designing this thing better
并实际上更干净地将此CSV加载到数据库中？
and actually load this CSV into a database a little more cleanly?
简而言之，我们如何摆脱流派列中的愚蠢逗号
In short, how do we get rid of the stupid commas in the Genres column
而是放一个词“喜剧”或“音乐”或“音乐”
and instead put one word, "comedy" or "music" or "musical,"
在每个单元格中，可以这么说吗？
in each of those cells, so to speak?
不是两个，不是三个-
Not two, not three--
只有在不放弃其中某些流派的情况下才能做到这一点。
one only without throwing away some of those genres.
好吧，让我介绍一些能够帮助我们实现目标的构件。
Well, let me introduce a few building blocks that will get us there.
事实证明，当创建自己的表时
It turns out, when creating your own tables
并自行将数据加载到数据库中，
and loading data into a database on your own,
我们将需要的不仅是SELECT。
we're going to need more than just SELECT.
SELECT当然只是为了阅读。
SELECT, of course, is just for reading.
但是，如果我们要做得更好，而不仅仅是使用sqlite3作为内置函数，
But if we're going to do this better and not just use sqlite3 as a built-in
.import命令，但是相反，我们将编写一些代码来加载所有
.import command, but instead we're going to write some code to load all
将我们的数据分为两个表-
of our data into maybe two tables--
一种是标题，一种是流派-
one for the titles, one for the genres--
当涉及到SQL时，我们将需要更多的表现力。
we're going to need a little more expressiveness when it comes to SQL.
因此，我们将需要一种能力
And so for that, we're going to need, one, the ability
创建我们自己的表。
to create our own tables.
我们之前已经看到了这一点。
And we've seen a glimpse of this before.
但是我们还需要看另一段语法，
But we're also going to need to see another piece of syntax,
以及，因此插入。
as well, so inserting.
插入是可以在SQL数据库上执行的另一命令
Inserting is another command that you can execute on a SQL database
以便将数据实际添加到数据库，这很棒。
in order to actually add data to a database, which is great.
因为如果我想最终迭代相同的CSV，但是这次，
Because if I want to ultimately iterate over that same CSV but, this time,
自己将所有行手动添加到数据库中，
manually add all of the rows to the database myself,
好，那么我将需要某种插入方式。
well, then I'm going to need some way of inserting.
并且其语法如下。
And the syntax for that is as follows.
插入表名，列名或列名
INSERT INTO the name of the table, the column or columns
您要在其中插入值的字面意思是“ VALUES”，
that you want to insert values into, then literally the word VALUES,
然后再用括号括起来，即实际的值列表。
and then literally in parentheses again, the actual list of values.
因此，当我们以这种通用形式看到它时，它有点抽象。
So it's a little abstract when we see it in this generic form.
但是，我们也将在此稍后更清楚地看到这一点。
But we'll see this more explicitly in just a moment here, as well.
因此，在向数据库中插入内容时，
So when it comes to inserting something into a database,
让我们继续尝试。
let's go ahead and try this.
因此，假设-让我们看看。
So suppose that-- let's see.
这是什么节目-
What's a show that--
布偶表演。
The Muppet Show.
我从小就喜欢The Muppet Show。
I grew up loving The Muppet Show.
就像70年代那样。
It was out in, like, the '70s.
而且我不认为它在列表中，但是我可以肯定地检查一下。
And I don't think it was on the list, but I can check this for sure.
所以SELECT * FROM显示WHERE标题LIKE--
So SELECT * FROM shows WHERE title LIKE--
让我们只用通配符搜索“布偶”。
let's just search for "muppets" with a wild card.
我猜没有人把它放在那里。
And I'm guessing no one put it there.
好的。
Good.
因此，这是一个错失的机会。
So it's a missed opportunity.
我忘了填写表格。
I forgot to fill out the form.
我可以返回并填写表格，然后重新导入CSV，
I could go back and fill out the form and re-import the CSV,
但让我们继续手动执行此操作。
but let's go ahead and do this manually.
那么，让我继续，INSERT INTO显示哪些列？
So let me go ahead and INSERT INTO shows what columns?
标题和流派，我想我可以做一个时间戳记。
title and genres, and I guess I could do a Timestamp just for kicks.
然后我要插入什么值？
And then I'm going to insert what values?
值，现在不知道是什么时候，我不知道。
The values will be, well, I don't know, whatever time it is now.
因此，我将在此处作弊，而不是查找日期和时间。
So I'm going to cheat there rather than look up the date and the time.
标题将是“木偶戏”。
The title will be "The Muppet Show."
体裁将是-有点像喜剧。
And the genres will be-- it was kind of a comedy.
这有点像音乐剧。
It was kind of a musical.
因此，我们将保留它。
So we'll kind of leave it at that.
分号。
Semicolon.
同样，这遵循此处的标准语法
So again, this follows the standard syntax here
指定要插入的表，
of specifying the table you want to insert into,
您要插入的列和值
the columns you want to insert into, and the values
您想放入这些列中。
you want to put into those columns.
我要继续并立即按Enter。
And I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter now.
似乎什么都没发生。
Nothing seems to have happened.
但是，如果我现在选择相同的查询，
But if I now select that same query--
哦，好的，仍然没什么，因为我犯了一个微妙的错误。
oh, OK, it's still nothing, because I made a subtle mistake.
我不是要搜索“布偶”（复数）。
I'm not searching for "Muppets," plural.
我正在搜索“布偶秀”（Muppet Show）单数形式。
I'm searching for "Muppet," singular, The Muppet Show.
瞧。
Voila.
现在，您在该数据库中看到我的行。
Now you see my row in this database.
因此，INSERT现在将使我们具备此功能
And so INSERT would give us the ability now
在数据库中插入新行。
to insert new rows into the database.
假设您要更新某些内容。
Suppose you want to update something.
你知道吗，一些布偶表演实际上是非常戏剧性的。
You know, some of the Muppet Shows were actually pretty dramatic.
那么我们该怎么做呢？
So how might we do that?
好吧，我可以说UPDATE显示SET--
Well, I can say UPDATE shows SET--
让我们看看-类型=“喜剧，戏剧，音乐”在哪里
let's see-- genres = "Comedy, Drama, Musical" WHERE
title =“木偶戏”。
title = "The Muppet Show."
同样，我将对此稍作规范化的语法。
So again, I'll pull up the canonical syntax for this in a bit.
但是就目前而言，您只需一点点预告片，就可以轻松更新内容。
But for now, just a little teaser, you can update things pretty simply.
即使需要一些时间来适应语法，
And even though it takes a little getting used to the syntax,
它按照它说的做。
it kind of does what it says.
UPDATE显示SET风格=此WHERE标题= that。
UPDATE shows SET genres = this WHERE title = that.
现在我可以继续输入了。
And now I can go ahead and Enter.
如果我继续选择相同的内容，就像在终端窗口中一样，
If I go ahead and select the same thing, just like in a terminal window,
你可以上下。
you can go up and down.
这就是我这么快打字的方式。
That's how I'm typing so quickly.
我只是上下移动以前的命令。
I'm just going up and down to previous commands.
瞧。
Voila.
现在，我看到木偶戏是一部喜剧，戏剧和音乐剧。
Now I see that the Muppet Show is a comedy, a drama, and a musical.
好吧，不过，我比较关注的是其中一部比较受欢迎的节目，
Well, I take issue, though, with one of the more popular shows that
在列表中。
was in the list.
一大堆你喜欢的朋友，
A whole bunch of you liked, let's say, Friends,
我从没真正喜欢过。
which I've never really been a fan of.
让我继续，SELECT title FROM显示WHERE title =“ Friends”。
And let me go ahead and SELECT title FROM shows WHERE title = "Friends."
也许我应该比这更严格一些。
And maybe I should be a little more rigorous than that.
我应该说标题“ Friends”，以防万一
I should say title LIKE "Friends" just in case
大小写不同。
there was different capitalizations.
进入。
Enter.
你们中的许多人真的很喜欢Friends。
A lot of you really liked Friends.
其实你们有几个？
In fact, how many of you?
好吧，记得我可以做到这一点。
Well, recall that I can do this.
我可以说COUNT，我可以让SQL为我做计数。
I can say COUNT, and I can let SQL do the count for me.
你们中的26个人，我非常不同意。
26 of you, I disagree with strongly.
你们当中有几个甚至都加了点
And there's a couple of you that even added all the dots,
但我们稍后再处理。
but we'll deal with you later.
因此，假设我确实对此表示怀疑。
So suppose I do take issue with this.
好吧，DELETE FROM显示WHERE title =“ Friends”-
Well, DELETE FROM shows WHERE title = "Friends"--
实际上，标题为“朋友”。
actually, title LIKE "Friends."
让我们全力以赴。
Let's get them all.
进入。
Enter.
现在，如果我们再次选择此选项，对不起。
And now if we SELECT this again, I'm sorry.
朋友已被取消。
Friends has been canceled.
因此，您可以再次执行CRUD的这些基本命令，
So you can again execute these fundamental commands of CRUD,
通过使用CREATE或INSERT创建读取，更新和删除，
Create Read, Update, and Delete, by using CREATE or INSERT,
通过使用SELECT，通过按字面意义使用UPDATE
by using SELECT, by using UPDATE literally
和从字面上删除，以及。
and DELETE literally, as well.
就是这样。
And that's about it.
即使很快，但实际上
Even though this was a lot quickly, there really
只是SQL中的四个基本操作
are just those four fundamental operations in SQL
加上其中一些附加功能，例如COUNT等这些附加功能
plus some of these add-on features, like these additional functions like COUNT
您可以使用的关键字，以及其中的一些关键字，例如WHERE等。
that you can use and also some of these keywords like WHERE and the like.
好吧，让我建议我们现在做得更好。
Well, let me propose that we now do better.
如果我们有能力选择数据并创建表并插入数据，
If we have the ability to select data and create tables and insert data,
让我们继续编写我们自己的使用SQL的Python脚本，例如在循环中，
let's go ahead and write our own Python script that uses SQL, as in a loop,
阅读我的CSV文件并插入，插入，插入，插入每一行
to read over my CSV file and to insert, insert, insert, insert each of the rows
手动。
manually.
老实说，这将带我永远
Because honestly, it will take me forever
手动键入数百个SQL查询以导入所有行
to manually type out hundreds of SQL queries to import all of your rows
进入新的数据库。
into a new database.
我想编写一个执行此操作的程序。
I want to write a program that does this instead.
我将建议我们按照以下方式进行设计。
And I'm going to propose that we design it in the following way.
这次我要有两个表，在这里表示
I'm going to have two tables this time, represented here
这位艺术家的演绎。
with this artist's rendition.
一个将被称为表演。
One is going to be called shows.
一种将被称为流派。
One is going to be called genres.
这是设计关系数据库的基本原则，
And this is a fundamental principle of designing relational databases,
找出数据之间的关系并规范化数据。
to figure out the relationships among data and to normalize your data.
标准化数据意味着消除冗余。
To normalize your data means to eliminate redundancies.
规范化数据意味着消除对相同单词的提及
To normalize your data means to eliminate mentions of the same words
一遍又一遍，只有真实的数据来源，
again and again and have just single sources of truth for your data,
可以这么说。
so to speak.
那我是什么意思呢？
So what do I mean by that?
我将建议我们改为创建一个更简单的表，称为
I'm going to propose that we instead create a simpler table called
显示只有两列。
shows that has just two columns.
一个将被称为id，这是新的。
One is going to be called id, which is new.
另一个将像以前一样被称为标题。
The other is going to be called title, as before.
老实说，我不在乎时间戳，所以我们只是
Honestly, I don't care about timestamps, so we're just
会抛弃那个价值，这是写作的另一个好处
going to throw that value away, which is another upside of writing
我们自己的程序。
our own program.
我们可以添加或删除所需的任何数据。
We can add or remove any data we want.
对于id，我正在介绍它，这将是
For id, I'm introducing this, which is going
成为唯一的标识符，实际上是一个简单的整数-
to be a unique identifier, literally a simple integer--
一，二，三，一路上升到十亿或二十亿，
1, 2, 3, all the way up to a billion or 2 billion,
但是我们有很多最爱。
however many favorites we have.
我只是想让这个自动递增。
I'm just going to let this auto increment as we go.
为什么？
Why?
我建议我们将所有流派移到另一张桌子，
I propose that we move to another table all of the genres and that,
而不是在一列中包含一，二，三或五种流派
instead of having one or two or three or five genres in one column
作为一个愚蠢的逗号分隔列表-仅在某种意义上是愚蠢的
as a stupid comma-separated list-- which is stupid only in the sense
那只是一团糟，对吗？
that it's just messy, right?
这意味着我必须运行愚蠢的命令
It means that I have to run stupid commands
我在这里检查逗号的地方。
where I'm checking for the comma here, the comma there.
可以这么说，它非常骇人听闻。
It's very hackish, so to speak.
设计不良。
Bad design.
而不是这样做，我将创建另一个表
Instead of doing that, I'm going to create another table that
也有两列。
also has two columns.
一种将被称为show_id，另一种将被称为流派。
One is going to be called show_id, and the other is going to be called genre.
现在，这里的流派只是一个字而已。
And genre here is just going to be a single word now.
该列将包含流派的单个字词，
That column will contain single words for genres,
例如“喜剧”或“音乐”或“音乐”。
like "comedy" or "music" or "musical."
但是我们将把所有这些流派联系起来
But we're going to associate all of those genres
根据您的Google表单显示其所属的原始节目
with the original show to which they belong, per your Google form
提交，请在此处使用此show_id。
submissions, by using this show_id here.
那么，这特别意味着什么呢？
So what does this mean in particular?
通过添加到我们的第一个表格中，可以看到该唯一标识符-
By adding to our first table, shows, this unique identifier--
1，2，3，4，5，6--
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6--
我现在可以使用
I can now refer to that same show in a very efficient way using
一个非常简单的数字，而不是多余的
a very simple number instead of redundantly
拥有办公室，办公室，办公室一次又一次。
having The Office, The Office, The Office again and again.
我只能用一个规范数字来指代它
I can refer to it by just one canonical number, which
只会是4个字节或32位。
is only going to be 4 bytes or 32 bits.
相当有效。
Pretty efficient.
但我仍然可以将该节目与一种或两种或三种类型相关联
But I can still associate that show with one genre or two or three
甚至更多甚至没有。
or more or even none.
这样，我们当前表中的每一行
So in this way, every row in our current table
在我们的新表对中将成为一个或多个行。
is going to become one or more rows in our new pair of tables.
我们正在考虑流派，以便我们
We're factoring out the genres so that we
可能会为每个节目添加多行，但仍然
can add multiple rows for every show, potentially, but still
将这些类型重新映射回原始节目本身。
remap those genres back to the original show itself.
那么，这里的一些流行词是什么？
So what is some of the buzzwords here?
有哪些熟悉的语言？
What's some of the language to be familiar with?
好吧，我们需要知道这里可以使用哪种类型。
Well, we need to know what kinds of types are at our disposal here.
因此，让我提出这个建议。
So for that, let me propose this.
我建议在这里列出这个清单。
Let me propose that we have this list here.
事实证明，在SQLite中，有五种主要的数据类型。
It turns out, in SQLite, there are five main data types.
这有点过分简化了，
And that's a bit of an oversimplification,
但是有五种主要的数据类型，其中一些看起来很熟悉，
but there's five main data types, some of which look familiar,
其中有些有点奇怪。
a couple of which are a little weird.
整数是一回事。
INTEGER is a thing.
REAL与float相同。
REAL is the same thing as float.
因此整数可能是32位或4字节的值，例如1、2、3或4
So an integer might be a 32-bit or 4-byte value, like 1, 2, 3, or 4,
正面或负面。
positive or negative.
实数将有一个小数点，
Real number's going to have a decimal point in it,
浮点值，默认情况下可能为32位。
a floating point value, probably 32 bits by default.
但是这些东西，这些类型的大小，
But those kinds of things, the sizes of these types,
因系统而异，就像技术上一样
vary by system, just like they technically
在C语言中完成。因此，在SQL领域，它们随系统的不同而不同。
did in C. So do they vary by system in the world of SQL.
但总的来说，这些是很好的经验法则。
But generally speaking, these are good rules of thumb.
TEXT就是这样。
TEXT is just that.
它有点像某个长度的字符串。
It's sort of the equivalent of a string of some length.
但随后在SQLite中，发现还有另外两个数据
But then in SQLite, it turns out there's two other data
我们以前从未见过的类型
types we've not seen before--
NUMERIC和BLOB。
NUMERIC and BLOB.
但是更多的只是这些。
But more on those in just a little bit.
BLOB是二进制大对象。
BLOB is Binary Large Object.
这意味着您可以在数据库中存储0和1。
It means you can store 0's and 1's in your database.
NUMERIC将类似于数字，但本身不是数字。
NUMERIC is going to be something that's number-like but isn't a number per se.
就像一年或一段时间，有数字但没有
It's like a year or a time, something that has numbers, but isn't
只是一个简单的整数。
just a simple integer at that.
我也建议，SQLite也将允许我们指定，
And let me propose, too, that SQLite is going to allow us to specify, too,
当我们通过自己执行SQL代码手动创建自己的列时，
when we create our own columns manually by executing the SQL code ourselves,
我们可以指定一列不能为空。
we can specify that a column cannot be null.
到目前为止，我们已经忽略了这一点。
Thus far, we've ignored this.
但是你们中有些人可能已经拿到了第五
But some of you might have taken the fifth
只是没有给我们一个节目或流派的标题。
and just not given us the title of a show or a genre.
您的答案可能是空白。
Your answers might be blank.
你们中的一些人，也许是在注册网站时，
Some of you, maybe in registering for a website,
不想提供诸如您的住所或电话号码之类的信息。
don't want to provide information like where you live or your phone number.
因此，数据库通常有时确实希望支持空值。
So a database in general sometimes does want to support null values.
但是您可能想说它不能为null。
But you might want to say that it can't be null.
网站可能需要您的电子邮件地址，
A website probably needs your email address,
需要您的密码和其他一些字段，但不是全部。
needs your password and a few other fields, but not everything.
而且在SQL中还有另一个关键字，就像您看到的一样，它称为UNIQUE，其中
And there's another keyword in SQL, just so you've seen it, called UNIQUE, where
您还可以说此列中的任何值
you can additionally say that whatever values are in this column
必须是唯一的。
must be unique.
因此，一个网站也可能会使用它。
So a website might also use that.
如果您要确保无法注册相同的电子邮件地址
If you want to make sure that the same email address can't register
多次访问您的网站，
for your website multiple times, you just
指定电子邮件列是唯一的。
specify that the email column is unique.
这样一来，您就无法将多个人放入相同的电子邮件地址。
That way, you can't put multiple people in with identical email addresses.
长话短说，这只是我们SQL工具包中的更多工具，
So long story short, this is just more of the tools in our SQL toolkit,
因为我们现在会间接看到其中的一些。
because we'll see some of these now indirectly.
在设计自己的表之前，我们需要用到的最后一条术语
And the last piece of jargon we need before designing our own tables
将会是这个。
is going to be this.
事实证明，在SQL中，有一个概念
It turns out that, in SQL, there's this notion
主键和外键的集合。
of primary keys and foreign keys.
而且我们还没有在电子表格中看到这一点。
And we've not seen this in spreadsheets.
除非您在现实世界中工作了几年
Unless you've been working in the real world for some years
而且您面前有相当不错的电子表格
and you have fairly fancy spreadsheets in front of you
作为分析师或财务人员等，
as an analyst or financial person or the like,
很有可能您没有以完全相同的方式看到键或唯一标识符。
odds are you've not seen keys or unique identifiers in quite the same way.
但是它们相对简单。
But they're relatively simple.
实际上，让我回到之前的图片并提出建议
In fact, let me go back to our picture before and propose
当你有两个这样的表，而你
that when you have two tables like this and you
想要使用一个简单的整数唯一地标识一个行中的所有行
want to use a simple integer to uniquely identify all of the rows in one
这些表中的技术上称为ID。
of the tables, that's called technically an ID.
按照惯例，这就是我所说的。
That's what I'll call it by convention.
您可以随意命名，但ID只是表示它是唯一标识符。
You could call it anything you want, but ID just means it's a unique identifier.
但是从语义上讲，此ID称为主键。
But semantically, this ID is what's called a primary key.
主键是表中唯一标识每一行的列。
A primary key is the column in a table that uniquely identifies every row.
这意味着您可以拥有多个版本的Office
This means you can have multiple versions of The Office
在该标题字段中。
in that title field.
但是这些行中的每一行都可能唯一地拥有自己的编号。
But each of those rows is going to have its own number uniquely, potentially.
因此，主键唯一地标识每一行。
So primary key uniquely identifies each row.
在另一个表中，例如我建议我们在短时间内创建的流派，
In another table, like genres, which I'm proposing we create in just a moment,
原来，欢迎您再次参考另一张桌子
it turns out that you're welcome to refer back to another table
通过该唯一标识符。
by way of that unique identifier.
但是在这种情况下，该ID称为外键。
But when it's in this context, that ID is called a foreign key.
因此，即使我在这里将其命名为show_id，
So even though I've called it show_id here,
这只是许多SQL数据库中的约定
that's just a convention in a lot of SQL databases
暗示从技术上讲这是表中称为ID的列
to imply that this is technically a column called ID in a table
称为演出，在这种情况下为复数。
called show or shows, plural in this case.
因此，如果这里有一个数字1，假设
So if there's a number 1 here, and suppose
该办公室的唯一ID为1，我们将
that The Office has a unique ID of 1, we would
在此表中有一行名为id为1的行，标题为The Office。
have a row in this table called id is 1, title is The Office.
办公室可能属于喜剧类，戏剧类，
The Office might be in the comedy category, the drama category,
浪漫类别，所以有多个。
the romance category, so multiple ones.
因此，在流派表中，我们要输出三行，
Therefore, in the genres table, we want to output three rows,
每行中的数字1、1、1，但单词“喜剧”
the number 1, 1, 1 in each of those rows but the words "comedy,"
这些行中的每一行分别为“戏剧”，“浪漫”。
"drama," "romance" in each of those rows respectively.
同样，这里的目标是更好地设计我们的数据库，而不是
So again, the goal here is to just design our database better, not
在单列中包含这些愚蠢的逗号分隔值列表。
have these stupid comma-separated lists of values inside of a single column.
我们想要将其炸毁，炸裂成单独的行。
We want to kind of blow that up, explode it, into individual rows.
您可能会想，为什么我们不只使用多列？
You might think, well, why don't we just use multiple columns?
但是同样，根据我们在电子表格中的原则，
But again, per our principle from spreadsheets,
您不应该习惯在以下情况下添加越来越多的列
you should not be in the habit of adding more and more columns when
数据都是一样的，像流派，流派，流派，对不对？
the data is all the same, like genre, genre, genre, right?
在电子表格世界中执行此操作的愚蠢方法
The stupid way to do this in the spreadsheet world
会有一个名为Genre 1的列
would be to have one column called Genre 1,
另一列称为流派2，另一列称为流派3，流派4。
another column called Genre 2, another column called Genre 3, Genre 4.
您可以想象这是多么愚蠢和低效。
And you can imagine just how stupid and inefficient this is.
对于那些类型很少的节目，很多这些栏将是空的。
A lot of those columns are going to be empty for shows with very few genres.
那时有点混乱。
And it's just kind of messy at that point.
更好的是，在关系数据库的世界中，
So better, in the world of relational databases,
具有第二个表之类的东西，其中有多行
to have something like a second table, where you have multiple rows that
通过我们所说的方式以某种方式链接回该主键，
somehow link back to that primary key by way of what we're calling,
从概念上讲，是外键。
conceptually, a foreign key.
好的。
All right.
因此，让我们现在开始尝试编写此代码。
So let's go ahead now and try to write this code.
让我回到我的IDE。
Let me go back to my IDE.
现在让我退出SQLite。
Let me quit out of SQLite now.
让我走开。
And let me just move away.
我暂时将其移开，我的文件
I'm going to move this away, my file, for just a moment
这样我们只剩下原始数据。
so that we're only left with our original data.
让我们去实现我的Python文件的最终版本
Let's go about implementing a final version of my Python file that does
这-创建了两个表-
this-- creates two tables--
一种叫做表演，一种叫做流派
one called shows, one called genres--
然后，在for循环中，两个迭代该CSV
and then, two, in a for loop, iterates over that CSV
并将一些数据插入到节目中，将其他数据插入到流派中。
and inserts some data into the shows and other data into the genres.
我们如何以编程方式做到这一点？
How can we do this programmatically?
好吧，这是我们需要解决的最后一个难题。
Well, there's a final piece of the puzzle that we need.
我们需要某种方法来架起Python和SQL的世界。
We need some way of bridging the world of Python and SQL.
在这里，我们确实需要一个库，因为它只会
And here, we do need a library, because it would just
没有图书馆就太痛苦了。
be way too painful to do without a library.
可以是CS50。
It can be CS50.
正如我们将看到的，CS50使这一过程非常简单。
CS50, as we'll see, makes this very simple.
还有其他第三方商业和开源库
There are other third-party commercial and open-source libraries
您也可以在现实世界中使用它们来做同样的事情。
that you can also use in the real world, as well, that do the same thing.
但是语法不太友好，
But the syntax is a little less friendly,
因此，我们将从使用CS50库开始，在Python中，
so we'll start by using the CS50 library, which in Python, recall,
具有类似get_string和get_int和get_float的功能。
has functions like get_string and get_int and get_float.
但是今天，事实证明，它也支持SQL功能。
But today, it also has support, it turns out, for SQL capabilities, as well.
因此，我将返回到“我的收藏夹”文件。
So I'm going to go back to my Favorites file.
我不仅要导入CSV，而且要导入
And I'm going to import not only CSV, but I'm also
将从CS50库中导入一个称为SQL的功能。
going to import from the CS50 library a feature called SQL.
因此，如果您愿意，我们在CS50库中有一个变量
So we have a variable, if you will, inside of the CS50 library
或者，而是CS50库中的函数
or, rather, a function inside of the CS50 library
称为SQL，如果我调用它，它将允许我
called SQL that, if I call it, will allow me
将SQLite数据库加载到内存中。
to load a SQLite database into memory.
那么我该怎么做呢？
So how do I do this?
好吧，让我继续并添加几行新代码。
Well, let me go ahead and add a couple of new lines of code.
让我继续打开一个名为shows.db的文件，
Let me go ahead and open up a file called shows.db,
但这一次处于写入模式。
but this time in write mode.
然后只是踢球-暂时，我是
And then just for kicks-- just for now, rather, I'm
将继续并立即将其关闭。
going to go ahead and close it right away.
这是创建空文件的Python方式。
This is a Pythonic way of creating an empty file.
看起来有点愚蠢，但是可以打开一个名为shows.db的文件
It's kind of stupid looking, but by opening a file called shows.db
在写入模式下，然后立即将其关闭，
in write mode and then immediately closing it,
它具有创建文件，关闭文件的作用。
it has the effect of creating the file, closing the file.
因此，我现在有一个与之交互的空文件。
So I now have an empty file with which to interact.
顺便说一句，我也可以这样做-
I could also do this, as an aside, by doing this--
触摸shows.db。
touch shows.db.
有点奇怪的命令，但是在终端窗口中，
touch kind of a strange command, but in a terminal window,
这意味着创建一个文件（如果不存在）。
it means to create a file if it doesn't exist.
因此，我们也可以这样做。
So we could also do that instead.
但这将独立于Python。
But that would be independent of Python.
所以一旦我创建了这个文件，让我继续
So once I've created this file, let me go ahead
并立即以SQLite数据库打开文件。
and open the file now as a SQLite database.
我将为数据库声明一个名为db的变量。
I'm going to declare a variable called db for database.
我将使用CS50库中的SQL函数。
I'm going to use the SQL function from CS50's library.
我将通过有点神秘的字符串来打开它
And I'm going to open via somewhat cryptic string this--
sqlite：///shows.db。
sqlite:///shows.db.
现在，它看起来像一个URL，http：//，但它是SQLite。
Now, it looks like a URL, http://, but it's SQLite instead.
而且有三个斜杠，而不是通常的两个斜杠。
And there's three slashes instead of the usual two.
但是，这行代码（第6行）具有结果
But this line of code, line 6, has the result
现在打开，否则没有任何内容的空文件
of opening now that otherwise empty file with nothing
它仍然是使用CS50库的SQLite数据库。
in it yet as being a SQLite database using CS50's library.
我为什么要那样做？
Why did I do that?
好吧，我这样做是因为我现在要创建我的第一个表。
Well, I did that because I now want to create my first table.
让我继续执行db.execute。
Let me go ahead and execute, db.execute.
因此，CS50 SQL库内部有一个称为execute的函数。
So there's a function called execute inside of the CS50 SQL library.
我将继续进行此操作。
And I'm going to go ahead and run this.
CREATE TABLE称为shows，其中的列
CREATE TABLE called shows, the columns of which
是一个id，将是一个整数，一个标题，这是
are an id, which is going to be an integer, a title, which
将是文本，其中的主键将是id列。
is going to be text, the primary key in which is going to be the id column.
因此，这有点神秘。
So this is a bit cryptic.
但是，让我们看看发生了什么。
But let's see what's happening.
我现在似乎在第8行中将Python与SQL结合在一起。
I seem to now, in line 8, be combining Python with SQL.
这就是现在编程变得真正强大，花哨，酷，
And this is where now programming gets really powerful, fancy, cool,
困难，但是您想感知它。
difficult, however you want to perceive it.
实际上，我可以在另一种语言中使用一种语言。
I can actually use one language inside of another.
如何？
How?
好吧，SQL只是一堆纹理命令。
Well, SQL is just a bunch of textural commands.
到目前为止，我一直在手动输入
Up until now, I've been typing them out manually
在此程序中称为SQLite3。
in this program called SQLite3.
但是，没有什么可以阻止我进行存储
There's nothing stopping me, though, from storing
在Python字符串中使用相同的命令，然后
those same commands in Python strings and then
使用代码将它们传递到数据库。
passing them to a database using code.
我正在使用的代码是一个称为execute的函数。
The code I'm using is a function called execute.
以及其人生目标，CS50员工写下了这一点，
And its purpose in life, and CS50 staff wrote this,
是将参数从您的Python代码传递到数据库中以执行。
is to pass the argument from your Python code into the database for execution.
因此，这就像手动输入内容的编程方式
So it's like the programmatic way of just typing things manually
几分钟前在SQLite提示下。
at the SQLite prompt a few minutes ago.
这样就可以继续创建我的表了
So that's going to go ahead and create my table called
显示，我将在其中存储所有这些唯一ID
shows, in which I'm going to store all of those unique IDs
还有标题。
and also the titles.
然后让我再做一次。
And then let me do this again.
db.execute CREATE TABLE流派，那就是
db.execute CREATE TABLE genres, and that's
将会有一个名为show_id的列，该列也是一个整数，
going to have a column called show_id, which is an integer also, genre,
这是文字。
which is text.
最后，它将有一个外键-
And lastly, it's going to have a foreign key--
它会在这里包起来很长的时间-
it's going to wrap a little long here--
在show_id上，该ID引用了shows表ID。
on show_id, which references the shows table id.
好吧，这很多。
All right, so this is a lot.
因此，让我们回顾一下从左到右。
So let's just recap left to right.
db.execute是我的Python函数，它执行我想要的任何SQL。
db.execute is my Python function that executes any SQL I want.
CREATE TABLE流派创建一个称为流派的表。
CREATE TABLE genres creates a table called genres.
该表中的列将称为show_id，
The columns in that table will be something called show_id,
这是一个整数，体裁是一个文本字段。
which is an integer, and genre, which is a text field.
但这将一次成为一种流派，而不是多种流派。
But it's going to be one genre at a time, not multiple.
然后在这里，我指定一个外键
And then here, I'm specifying a foreign key
将是show_id列，该列恰好会返回引用
will be the show_id column, which happens to refer back
到shows表的ID列。
to the shows table's IDs column.
这有点神秘，但是所有要做的就是为我们实现
It's a little cryptic, but all this is doing is implementing for us
等效于此图片。
the equivalent of this picture here.
我本可以手动键入这两个SQL
I could have manually typed both of these SQL
在该闪烁的提示下输入命令。
commands at that blinking prompt.
但是再次，不，我想现在写一个程序
But again, no, I want to write a program now
在Python中为我创建了表格，现在，更有趣的是，
in Python that creates the tables for me and now, more interestingly,
将数据加载到该数据库中。
loads the data into that database.
现在开始吧。
So let's go ahead and do this now.
我不会从用户中选择标题，
I'm not going to select a title from the user,
因为我想导入所有内容。
because I want to import everything.
我将不使用任何计数或类似方法。
I'm not going to use any counting or anything like that.
因此，让我们继续前进，就像以前一样进入我的循环。
So let's go ahead and just go inside of my loop as before.
这次，让我们继续前进，在读者中排成一列，
And this time, let's go ahead and, for row in reader,
像往常一样，让我们继续获取当前标题。
let's go ahead and get the current title, as we've always done.
但我们还是一如既往地将其剥离空白
But let's also, as always, go ahead and strip it of white space
并资本化它，只是为了规范化它。
and capitalize it, just to canonicalize it.
现在，我要继续执行db.execute，用引号引起来，
And now I'm going to go ahead and execute db.execute, quote unquote,
INSERT INTO显示标题列，值为“ title”。
INSERT INTO shows the title column, the value of "title."
所以我想把标题放在这里。
So I want to put the title here.
事实证明，像我们这样的SQL库支持最后一种语法，
It turns out that SQL libraries like ours support one final piece of syntax,
这是一个占位符。
which is a placeholder.
在C语言中，我们使用％s。
In C, we use %s.
在Python中，我们仅使用花括号并将单词放在此处。
In Python, we just use curly braces and put the word right there.
在SQL中，对于同一个问题，我们有第三种方法-只是在语法上
In SQL, we have a third approach to the same problem-- just syntactically
不同，但概念上相同。
different, but conceptually the same.
您在要放置占位符的位置放置一个问号。
You put a question mark where you want to put a placeholder.
然后在该字符串之外，我将实际输入值
And then outside of this string, I'm going to actually type in the value
我想插入问号。
that I want to plug into that question mark.
因此，这与第1周的printf非常相似。
So this is so similar to printf in week 1.
但是现在不是问号，而是一个问号，然后是一个逗号分隔的列表
But instead of %s, it's a question mark now and then a comma-separated list
您要为这些占位符插入的参数。
of the arguments you want to plug in for those placeholders.
所以现在这行代码16刚刚插入了所有这些值
So now this line of code 16 has just inserted all of those values
进入我的数据库。
into my database.
让我们继续运行它。
And let's go ahead and run this.
在继续之前，请允许我继续执行此操作。
Before I go any further, let me go ahead and do this.
我现在要继续运行python的收藏夹.py
I'm going to go ahead now and run python of favorites.py
一如既往地交叉我的手指。
and cross my fingers, as always.
这花了一点时间，花了一点时间。
It's taking a moment, taking a moment.
那是因为那里有一个像样的文件。
That's because there's a decent-sized file there.
或者我搞砸了。
Or I screwed up.
这花了太长时间。
This is taking too long.
哦好的。
Oh, OK.
我本来应该更耐心。
I should have just been more patient.
好的。
All right.
所以看来我的连线有点慢。
So it just seems my connection's a little slow.
因此，正如我所料，一切都是100％正确的，并且一切正常。
So as I expected, everything is 100% correct, and it's working fine.
现在，让我们继续前进，看看我实际上做了什么。
So now let's go ahead and see what I actually did.
如果输入ls，请注意我有一个名为shows.db的文件。
If I type ls, notice that I have a file called shows.db.
这是全新的，因为我的Python程序这次创建了它。
This is brand new, because my Python program created it this time.
让我们继续运行show.db的sqlite3
Let's go ahead and run sqlite3 of shows.db
以便现在我可以看到其中的内容。
just so I can now see what's inside of it.
请注意，我可以执行.schema只是为了查看存在哪些表。
Notice that I can do .schema just to see what tables exist.
实际上，我在Python代码中创建的两个表
And indeed, the two tables that I created in my Python code
似乎存在。
seem to exist.
但是请注意，
But notice that there's--
如果我执行SELECT * FROM节目，让我们查看所有数据。
if I do SELECT * FROM shows, let's see all the data.
瞧。
Voila.
有一个以编程方式创建的表。
There is a table that's been programmatically created.
这次注意，它没有时间戳记，没有流派。
And it has, notice this time, no timestamps, no genres.
但是左侧有一个ID，右侧有标题。
But it has an ID on the left and the title on the right.
令人惊讶的是，所有ID都从1单调增加
And amazingly, all of the IDs are monotonically increasing from 1
在这种情况下，最高可达513。
on up to 513, in this case.
这是为什么？
Why is that?
好吧，您在SQL数据库中获得的功能之一
Well, one of the features you get in a SQL database
是如果您将列定义为SQLite中的主键，
is if you define a column as being a primary key in SQLite,
它会自动为您增加。
it's going to be auto incremented for you.
回想一下，在我的代码中我什至都没有一行，一个整数，
Recall that nowhere in my code did I even have a line, an integer,
输入1，然后输入2，然后输入3。
inputting 1, then 2, then 3.
我绝对可以那样做。
I could absolutely do that.
我本可以做这样的事-反击-
I could have done something like this-- counter--
相反，我本可以做这样的事情-counter = 1。
rather, I could have done something like this-- counter = 1.
然后在这里，我可以说身份证，头衔，给我自己
And then down here, I could have said id, title, give myself
两个占位符，然后每次都传递给计数器。
two placeholders, and then pass in the counter each time.
我本可以自己实现的，然后在每次迭代中
I could have implemented this myself and then, on each iteration,
完成计数器+ = 1。
done counter += 1.
但是，正如我们所见，对于SQL数据库，您
But with SQL databases, as we've seen, you
获得更多内置功能。
get a lot more functionality built in.
我不需要做任何事情，因为如果我已经
I don't have to do any of that, because if I've
声明该ID为主键，SQLite将为我插入它
declared that ID as being a primary key, SQLite is going to insert it for me
并为我增加它。
and increment it also for me, as well.
好的。
All right.
因此，如果我回到SQLite，请注意我确实有ID和标题。
So if I go back to SQLite, though, notice that I do have IDs and titles.
但是，如果我从流派中选择*，当然还没有任何东西。
But if I SELECT * FROM genres, there's of course nothing there yet.
那么，现在如何获得所有这些节目的所有流派？
So how now do I get all of the genres for each of these shows in?
我需要完成我的脚本。
I need to finish my script.
因此，在同一循环中，我不仅在当前行中拥有标题，
So inside of this same loop, I have not only the title in my current row,
但我在当前行中也有流派。
but I also have genres in the current row.
但是类型之间以逗号分隔。
But the genres are separated by commas.
记得在CSV中，每个标题旁边，
Recall that in the CSV, next to every title,
有一个以逗号分隔的流派列表。
there's a comma-separated list of genres.
如何分别了解每种类型？
How do I get at each genre individually?
好吧，我想说一下行括号类型中的类型。
Well, I'd like to be able to say for genre in row bracket genres.
但这是行不通的，因为那是行不通的
But this is not going to work, because that's not going
根据这些逗号分开。
to be split up based on those commas.
从字面上看，这只是要反复进行，
That's literally just going to iterate over,
实际上，如上周所见，该字符串中的所有字符。
in fact, all of the characters in that string, as we saw last week.
但事实证明，Python中的字符串有花哨的分割
But it turns out that strings in Python have a fancy split
函数，这样我就可以在逗号后面加一个空格。
function, whereby I can split on a comma followed by a space.
在Python中此功能将为我做的是
And what this function will do for me in Python is
可以用逗号分隔的流派列表并将其爆炸，可以这么说，
take a comma separated list of genres and explode it, so to speak,
在每个逗号处将其拆分为一个Python列表
split it on every comma, space into a Python list
在实际的Python列表中包含类型之后的类型
containing genre after genre in an actual Python list
左方括号。
a la square brackets.
现在，我可以遍历该单个类型的列表。
So now I can iterate over that list of individual genres.
在这里，我可以执行db.execute INSERT INTO流派show_id，流派，
And inside of here, I can do db.execute INSERT INTO genres show_id, genre,
值，问号，问号。
the values, question mark, question mark.
但是，有一个问题。
But huh, there's a problem.
我绝对可以插入当前类型，就是这个。
I can definitely plug in the current genre, which is this.
但我需要在这里放些东西。
But I need to put something here still.
对于第一个问号，我需要一个show_id的值。
For that first question mark, I need a value for the show_id.
我怎么知道当前电视节目的ID？
How do I know what the ID is of the current TV show?
好吧，事实证明该库可以为您提供帮助。
Well, it turns out the library can help you with this.
当您将新行插入具有主键的表中时，
When you insert new rows into a table that has a primary key,
事实证明，大多数库都会以某种方式返回该值。
it turns out that most libraries will return you that value in some way.
如果我回到第15行，我实际上
And if I go back to line 15 and I actually
使用INSERT后，存储db.execute的返回值，
store the return value of db.execute after using INSERT,
图书馆会告诉我什么是整数
the library will tell me what was the integer that
仅用于该给定的节目。
was just used for this given show.
也许是1、2、3
Maybe it's 1, 2, 3.
作为程序员，我不必了解或关心。
I don't have to know or care as the programmer.
但是返回值，我可以存储在一个变量中。
But the return value, I can store in a variable.
然后在这里，我可以从字面上输入相同的ID，以便现在，
And then down here, I can literally put that same ID so that now,
如果我在shows表中输入ID为1的Office
if I am inputting The Office, whose ID is 1, into the shows table
其类型为喜剧，戏剧，浪漫，
and its genres are comedy, drama, romance,
我现在可以在此for循环内，此嵌套的for循环内，
I can now inside of this for loop, this nested for loop,
插入1后跟“喜剧”，1后跟“戏剧”，后跟1
insert 1 followed by "comedy," 1 followed by "drama," 1 followed
通过“浪漫”一次三行。
by "romance," three rows all at once.
现在让我们回到这里，进入我的终端窗口。
And so now let's go back down here into my terminal window.
让我用rm删除旧的shows.db，只是为了重新开始。
Let me remove the old shows.db with rm, just to start fresh.
让我继续并重新运行“ favourites.py”的python。
Let me go ahead and rerun python of favorites.py.
这次我会更加耐心，因为云的运行速度有点慢。
I'll be more patient this time, because cloud's being a little slow.
因此，它正在做一些思考。
So it's doing some thinking.
实际上，现在还有更多工作要做。
And in fact, there's more work being done now.
在故事的这一点上，我的程序大概是
At this point in the story, my program is presumably
遍历CSV中的所有行。
iterating over all of the rows in the CSV.
一次插入到shows表中，
And it's inserting into the shows table one at a time,
然后将一种或多种类型插入到类型表中。
and then it's inserting one or more genres into the genres table.
有点慢。
It's a little slow.
如果我们使用的是速度更快的系统，或者我是在自己的Mac或PC上运行的，
If we were on a faster system or if I were doing it on my own Mac or PC,
它可能会更快地下降。
it would probably go down more quickly.
但是您可以在这里看到一个为什么我在第一个中使用.import命令的示例
But you can see here an example of why I use the .import command in the first
地方。
place.
这使某些过程自动化。
That automated some of this process.
但不幸的是，它不允许我更改数据格式。
But unfortunately, it didn't allow me to change the format of my data.
但是，这里要做的关键是
But the key point to make here is that even though this
花费一点时间一次插入这数百行，
is taking a little bit of time to insert these hundreds of rows all at once,
我只需要这样做一次。
I'm only going to have to do this once.
刚才问的是这种性能。
And what was asked a bit ago was the performance of this.
事实证明，既然我们已经完全控制了SQL数据库，
It turns out that now that we have full control over the SQL database,
事实证明，我们将有能力进行实际改进
it turns out we're going to have the ability to actually improve
其性能。
the performance thereof.
哦好的。
Oh, OK.
如预期的那样，它按时完成了。
As expected, it finished right on time.
现在让我继续并在shows.db上运行sqlite3。
And let me go ahead now and run sqlite3 on shows.db.
好的，现在我回到了原始SQL环境。
All right, so now I'm back in my raw SQL environment.
如果我之前做过SELECT * FROM节目，
If I do SELECT * FROM shows, which I did before,
我们将像以前一样看到所有这些。
we'll see all of this as before.
如果我选择* FROM显示WHERE title =“ THE OFFICE”，
If I SELECT * FROM shows WHERE title = "THE OFFICE,"
我将看到所有这些的实际唯一ID。
I'll see the actual unique IDs of all of those.
我们没有费心消除重复项。
We didn't bother eliminating duplicates.
我们只是按原样保留了所有内容，但为所有内容赋予了唯一的ID。
We just kept everything as is, but we gave everything a unique ID.
但是，如果我现在执行SELECT * FROM类型，我们将在那里看到所有值。
But if I now do SELECT * FROM genres, we'll see all of the values there.
并注意关键细节。
And notice the key detail.
每行只有一种类型。
There is only one genre per row here.
因此，我们最终可以将他们与我们的头衔联系在一起。
And so we can ultimately line those up with our titles.
在这里，我们的头衔都在这里。
And our titles here, we had all of these here.
出了点问题。
Something's wrong.
我想做对了。
I want to get this right.
让我们继续前进，在这里进行第二个也是最后的5分钟休息。
Let's go ahead and take our second and final five-minute break here.
我们会回来的，我会解释发生了什么。
And we'll come back, and I will explain what's going on.
好吧，我们回来了。
All right, we are back.
在我们分手之前，我的自我怀疑开始蔓延。
And just before we broke up, my own self-doubt was starting to creep in.
但我很高兴地说，幕后没有花哨的魔法，
But I'm happy to say, with no fancy magic behind the scenes,
一切实际上都正常。
everything was actually working fine.
我只是在怀疑这一点的正确性。
I was just doubting the correctness of this.
如果我执行SELECT * FROM节目，我确实会回来
If I do SELECT * FROM shows, I indeed get back
两列，其中一列具有唯一ID，即所谓的主键
two columns, one with the unique ID, the so-called primary key, followed
每个节目的标题。
by the title of each of those shows.
而且，如果我类似地搜索* FROM风格，那么我一次就会获得一种风格。
And if I similarly search for * FROM genres, I get single genres at a time.
但是左侧本身不是主键
But on the left-hand side are not primary keys per se
但是现在在这种情况下，这些相同的数字称为
but now those same numbers here in this context called
一个映射到另一个的外键。
foreign keys that map one to the other.
因此，例如，无论哪个节目512都有五种不同的流派
So for instance, whatever show 512 is had five different genres associated
用它。
with it.
实际上，如果我回想一下节目，看起来就像《权力的游戏》
And in fact, if I go back a moment to shows, it looks like Game of Thrones
由你们中的一个人决定属于惊悚片，历史片，冒险片，
was decided by one of you as belonging in thriller, history, adventure,
动作和战争，还有那五个。
action, and war, as well, those five.
所以现在这就是关系数据库的含义。
So now this is what's meant by relational database.
您在多个表中具有这种关系或关系
You have this relation or relationship across multiple tables
将其中的一些数据链接到类似的其他数据。
that link some data in one to some other data in the like.
不过，要注意的是，现在看来要难一些
The catch, though, is that it would seem a little harder now
回答问题，因为现在我必须要查询两个表
to answer questions, because now I have to kind of query two tables
或执行两个单独的查询，然后合并数据。
or execute two separate queries and then combine the data.
但是实际上并非如此。
But that's not actually the case.
假设我要回答的问题是
Suppose that I want to answer the question of,
您最喜欢的电视节目中有哪些音乐剧？
what are all of the musicals among your favorite TV shows?
我不能只选择演出，因为那里已经没有类型了。
I can't select just the shows, because there's no genres in there anymore.
但是我也不能只选择流派表，
But I also can't select just the genres table,
因为那里没有标题。
because there's no titles in there.
但是有一个值可以相互桥接，即外键
But there is a value that's bridging one and the other, that foreign key
到主键关系。
to primary key relationship.
所以，您知道我该怎么办吗？
So you know what I can do off the top of my head?
我很确定我可以从类型表中选择所有的show_id
I'm pretty sure I can select all of the show_ids from the genres table
其中特定类型=“音乐”。
where a specific genre = "Musical."
而且我现在不必担心逗号或空格，
And I don't have to worry about commas or spaces now,
因为再次，在这个我以编程方式设计的新版本中
because again, in this new version that I have designed programmatically
加上代码，音乐和所有其他流派，只是一个字而已。
with code, musical and every other genre is just a single word.
如果我按Enter键，则所有这些show_id均已确定
If I hit Enter, all of these show_ids were decided
你们所有人都属于音乐剧。
by you all as belonging to musicals.
但是现在这并不有趣，我当然可以
But now this is not interesting, and I certainly
不想手动执行10个左右的查询
don't want to execute 10 or so queries manually
查找这些ID中的每个ID。
to look up every one of those IDs.
但请注意，我们也可以在SQL中进行操作。
But notice what we can do in SQL, as well.
我可以嵌套查询。
I can nest queries.
让我将整个查询放在括号中一会儿
Let me put this whole query in parentheses for just a moment
然后在其前面添加以下内容。
and then prepend to it the following.
SELECT title FROM显示此子查询中的主键id。
SELECT title FROM shows WHERE the primary key, id, is in this subquery.
因此，您可以使嵌套查询在本质上类似Python和C
So you can have nested queries similar in spirit a bit like in Python and C
当您嵌套循环时。
when you have nested for loops.
在这种情况下，就像小学数学一样，括号中的任何内容
In this case, just like in grade school math, whatever is in the parentheses
将首先执行。
will be executed first.
然后，将使用该内部查询的结果执行外部查询。
Then the outer query will be executed using the results of that inner query.
因此，如果我从显示中选择ID在该ID列表中的位置的标题，
So if I select the title from shows where the ID is in that list of IDs,
瞧。
voila.
似乎有些有趣
It seems that, somewhat amusingly, several of you
认为《绝命毒师》，《超自然》，《欢乐合唱团》，《福尔摩斯》，《我如何见到你的母亲》，
think that Breaking Bad, Supernatural, Glee, Sherlock, How I Met Your Mother,
夏威夷五-0，双峰，律师，和我的兄弟，我的兄弟
Hawaii Five-0, Twin Peaks, The Lawyer, and My Brother, My Brother
和我都是音乐剧。
and Me are all musicals.
我对其中一些例外，但事实如此。
I take exception to a few of those, but so be it.
您已为那些演出选中了音乐盒。
You checked the box for musical for those shows.
因此，即使我们在某种意义上设计了更好的东西
So even though we've designed things better in the sense
我们已经通过排除通用性对数据库进行了规范化
that we've normalized our database by factoring out commonalities
或者，更确切地说，我们已经清理了数据，
or, rather, we've cleaned up the data, there's
仍然承认有些冗余。
still admittedly some redundancy.
诚然，仍然存在一些冗余。
There's still admittedly some redundancy.
但是我至少现在有干净的数据
But I at least now have the data in clean fashion
这样每一列都只有一个值而不是
so that every column has just a single value in it and not
一些人为的用逗号分隔的列表。
some contrived comma-separated list.
假设我想找出所有类型
Suppose I want to find out all of the genres
你们都以为办公室在。
that you all thought The Office was in.
因此，让我们提出相反的问题。
So let's ask kind of the opposite question.
好吧，我该怎么做？
Well, how might I do that?
好吧，要弄清楚The Office，我首先需要选择ID
Well, to figure out The Office, I'm going to first need to SELECT the id
FROM显示WHERE title =“ THE OFFICE”，因为你们中的很多人
FROM shows WHERE title = "THE OFFICE," because a whole bunch of you
在办公室里输入。
typed in The Office.
我们为您的每个答案提供了唯一的标识符
And we gave each of your answers a unique identifier
这样我们就可以跟踪它。
so we could keep track of it.
还有所有这些数字。
And there's all of those numbers.
现在，这是数十种回应。
Now, this is, like, dozens of responses.
我当然不想执行那么多查询。
I certainly don't want to execute that many queries.
但是我认为子查询将再次帮助我们。
But I think a subquery will help us out again.
让我在整个内容中加上括号。
Let me put parentheses around this whole thing.
现在让我说说从哪里选择不同的类型
And now let me say SELECT DISTINCT genre FROM genres WHERE
该查询中包含流派表中的show_id。
the show_id in the genres table is in that query.
只是为了踢球，让我继续进行ORDER BY体裁。
And just for kicks, let me go ahead and ORDER BY genre.
因此，让我继续执行此操作。
So let me go ahead and execute this.
好吧，有些有趣的是，那些输入了Office的人
And, OK, somewhat amusingly, those of you who inputted The Office
动画，喜剧，纪录片，戏剧，家庭，恐怖，
checked boxes for animation, comedy, documentary, drama, family, horror,
真人秀，浪漫片和科幻片。
reality-TV, romance, and sci-fi.
我也对其中一些例外。
I take exception to a few of those, too.
但这是当您接受用户输入时发生的情况。
But this is what happens when you accept user input.
所以在这里，我们再次使用了这种SQL语言
So here again, we have with this SQL language
相当简洁地表达的能力，即使
the ability to express fairly succinctly, even though it's
今天一次有很多新功能，否则会带给我什么
a lot of new features today all at once, what would otherwise take me
在Python代码中执行一两行
a dozen or two lines in Python code to implement
神知道多少行代码和多少小时
and god knows how many lines of code and how many hours it
会带我在C语言中实现类似的功能。现在，坦白地说，
would take me to implement something like this in C. Now, admittedly,
我们可以做得比这个设计更好。
we could do better than this design.
这张桌子或这张图片代表了我们现在所拥有的。
This table or this picture represents what we have now.
但是您会注意到类型表中隐含了很多冗余。
But you'll notice a lot of redundancy implicit in the genres table.
每当您选中喜剧框时，我都会排一行
Any time you check the comedy box, I have a row now
那就是喜剧，喜剧，喜剧，喜剧。
that says comedy, comedy, comedy, comedy.
和show_id不同，但是我一次又一次地使用“喜剧”一词。
And the show_id differs, but I have the word "comedy" again and again.
而现在，在关系数据库的世界中，这一点变得不那么普遍了，
And now, that tends to be frowned upon in the world of relational databases,
因为如果您有一种类型的喜剧或喜剧
because if you have a genre called comedy or one
称为音乐剧或其他任何音乐，理想情况下，您应该
called musical or anything else, you should ideally just
有那种生活在一个地方。
have that living in one place.
因此，如果我们真的想变得特别，真正，真正
And so if we really wanted to be particular and really, truly
标准化此数据库，这是一个学术术语，指的是
normalize this database, which is an academic term referring
为了消除所有这些冗余，我们实际上可以这样做。
to removing all such redundancies, we could actually do it like this.
我们可以有一个显示表，它仍然带有ID和标题，两者之间没有区别。
We could have a shows table still with an id and title, no difference there.
但是我们可以拥有一个包含两列的流派表，即id和name。
But we could have a genres table with two columns, id and name.
现在，这是它自己的ID。
Now, this is its own id.
它与show_id没有任何关系。
It has no connection with the show_id.
它只是它自己的唯一标识符，现在是这里的主键，
It's just its own unique identifier, a primary key here now,
以及该类型的名称。
and the name of that genre.
所以您在类型表中会有一行
So you would have one row in the genres table
用于喜剧，戏剧，音乐，音乐剧和其他所有内容。
for comedy, for drama, music, musical, and everything else.
然后，您将使用第三个表格，
And then you would use a third table, which
通俗地称为联接表，我将在中间画出它。
is colloquially called a join table, which I'll draw here in the middle.
您可以随心所欲地调用它，但是我们已经
And you can call it anything you want, but we've
称它为shows_genres来表明该表实现了
called it shows_genres to make clear that this table implements
这两个表之间的关系。
a relationship between those two tables.
并且请注意，该表中实际上没有多汁的数据。
And notice that in this table is really no juicy data.
只是外键
It's just foreign keys--
show_id，genre_id。
show_id, genre_id.
通过拥有第三张桌子，我们现在可以
And by having this third table, we can now
确保“喜剧”一词只出现在任何地方的一行中。
make sure that the word "comedy" only appears in one row anywhere.
“音乐”一词仅在任何地方显示为一行。
The word "musical" only appears in one row anywhere.
但是我们使用了效率更高的整数，称为show_id和genre_id，
But we use these more efficient integers called show_id and genre_id,
分别指向这些主键及其主表
which respectively point to those primary keys and their primary tables
将这两个链接在一起。
to link those two together.
这是数据库世界中所谓的一个例子
And this is an example of what's called in the world of databases
多对多关系。
a many-to-many relationship.
一个节目可以有多种流派。
One show can have many genres.
一种类型可以属于许多表演。
One genre can belong to many shows.
因此，有了这个第三张桌子，您可以
And so by having this third table, you can
有多对多的关系。
have that many-to-many relationship.
再次，第三张表现在使我们能够真正归一化
And again, the third table now allows us to truly normalize
通过消除所有重复的喜剧，喜剧，喜剧来获得我们的数据集。
our data set by getting rid of all of the duplicate comedy, comedy, comedy.
为什么这很重要？
Why is this important?
对于类型来说，可能不算什么。
Probably not a huge deal for genres.
但是，请想象一下我目前的设计是否犯了拼写错误，
But imagine with my current design if I made a spelling mistake,
我给喜剧取了个名字
and I misnamed comedy.
我现在必须一次又一次地用喜剧这个词来更改每一行。
I would now have to change every row with the word comedy again and again.
或者，如果您改变了节目的类型，
Or if maybe you change the genres of the shows,
您将不得不在多个地方进行更改。
you would have to change it in multiple places.
但是用另一种方法，用三个表，
But with this other approach with three tables,
你可以说现在你只需要改变
you can argue that now you only have to change
类型的名称位于一个地方，而不是整个地方。
the name of a genre in one place, not all over the place.
而且，通常在C语言中，现在在Python中，现在
And that, in general, in C and now in Python and now
通常，SQL最好不要复制粘贴相同的值
SQL has generally been a good thing not to copy paste identical values
到处都是。
all over the place.
好的。
All right.
因此，我们还有什么其他工具可以使用？
So with that said, what other tools do we have at our disposal?
好吧，事实证明，现实世界中还有其他数据类型
Well, it turns out that there are other data types out there in the real world
除了这五个以外，还使用SQL
using SQL besides just these five--
BLOB，INTEGER，NUMERIC，REAL和TEXT。
BLOB, INTEGER, NUMERIC, REAL, and TEXT.
同样，BLOB是二进制文件，通常不是
BLOB, again, is for binary stuff, generally not
可以说，除了更专业的应用之外，
used except for more specialized applications, let's say.
INTEGER，它是一个int，通常为32位；
INTEGER, which is an int, typically 32 bits;
NUMERIC，类似于日期或年份
NUMERIC, which is something like a date or a year
或时间之类的东西；实数，其中
or time or something like that; REAL numbers, which
是浮点值；和TEXT，就像字符串一样。
are floating point values; and TEXT, which are things like strings.
但是，如果您最终从手机上的SQLite毕业
But if you graduate ultimately from SQLite on phones
在Mac和PC上运行运行Oracle，MySQL，
and on Macs and PCs to actual servers that run Oracle, MySQL,
和PostgreSQL（如果您实际上正在运行）
and PostgreSQL if you're actually running
您自己的互联网业务，好吧
your own internet-style business, well, it
事实证明，功能更强大，功能更强大
turns out that more sophisticated, even more powerful
如果可能的话，数据库还带有其他子类型。
databases come with other subtypes, if you will.
因此，除了INTEGER外，您还可以为小数字指定smallint，
So besides INTEGER, you can specify smallint for small numbers,
也许只用几位而不是32-
maybe using just a few bits instead of 32--
INTEGER或bigint，它使用64位而不是32位。
INTEGER or bigint, which uses 64 bits instead of 32.
世界各地的Facebook和Twitter都需要大量使用bigint，
The Facebooks, the Twitters of the world need to use bigint a lot,
因为他们有很多数据
because they have so much data.
您和我可以摆脱简单的整数，因为我们不是
You and I can get away with simple integers, because we're not
一个班级将有超过40亿个喜欢的电视节目，
going to have more than 4 billion favorite TV shows in a class,
当然。
certainly.
像REAL这样的东西，您可以使用32位实数，或者有些奇怪
Something like REAL, you can have 32-bit real numbers or, a little weirdly
命名为double precision，它类似于C中的double，使用64位代替
named, double precision, which is like a double was in C, using 64 bits instead
以获得更高的精度。
for more precision.
NUMERIC就是这种包罗万象的东西。
NUMERIC is kind of this catchall.
您不仅可以拥有日期和日期时间，还可以拥有布尔值之类的东西。
You can have not only dates and date times but things like Boolean values.
您可以指定总位数
You can specify the total number of digits
使用此数字刻度和精度进行存储。
to store using this numeric scale and precision.
因此，它涉及的数字不只是整数。
So it relates to numbers that aren't just quite integers.
然后您还有TEXT的类别-
And then you also have categories of TEXT--
字符后跟一个数字，该数字指定
char followed by a number, which specifies
该列中的每个值都将具有相同数量的字符，
that every value in the column will have the same number of characters,
这对于长度提前的事情很有用，例如在美国。
that's helpful for things where the length in advance, like in the US.
所有州（共50个州）都有两个字符的代码，
All states, all 50 states, have two-character codes,
例如马萨诸塞州的马萨诸塞州，加利福尼亚州的CA。
like MA for Massachusetts, CA for California.
char（2）在那里很合适，因为您
char(2) would be appropriate there, because you
知道该列中的每个值都将包含两个字符。
know every value in the column is going to have two characters.
但是，当您不知道时，可以使用varchar。
When you don't know, though, you can use varchar.
varchar指定最大字符数。
And varchar specifies a maximum number of characters.
因此，您可以指定varchar，例如32。
And so you might specify varchar of, like, 32.
没有人可以输入长度超过32个字符的名称，
No one might be able to type in a name that's longer than 32 characters,
或varchar（200）（如果要允许更大的值）。
or varchar(200) if you want to allow for something even bigger.
但这与我们在网络上的实际经验密切相关。
But this is germane to our real-world experience with the web.
如果您曾经访问过网站，请开始填写表格，
If you've ever gone to a website, start filling out a form,
突然之间，您无法再输入任何字符，
and all of a sudden you can't type any more characters,
您的回复太长了-
your response is too long--
这是为什么？
why is that?
好吧，一个，程序员可能不会
Well, one, the programmers just might not
希望您继续表达更多细节，尤其是
want you to keep expressing yourself in more detail, especially
如果是客户服务网站上的投诉表。
if it's a complaint form on a customer service site.
但务实的是，这可能是因为他们的数据库是经过设计的
But pragmatically, it's probably because their database was designed
存储有限数量的字符。
to store a finite number of characters.
而您已经达到了这个门槛。
And you have hit that threshold.
而且您当然不希望有缓冲区
And you certainly don't want to have a buffer
溢出，就像在C中一样。因此数据库将强制执行最大值n。
overflow, like in C. So the database will enforce a maximum value n.
然后，文本用于更大的文本块。
And then text is for even bigger chunks of text.
如果您要让人们复制，请粘贴他们的简历
If you're letting people copy paste their resumes
或保存文档或什至更大的文本集，则可以改用文本。
or hold documents or even larger sets of text, you might use text instead.
因此，让我们考虑一个真实的数据集。
So let's then consider a real-world data set.
事情变得非常有趣，所有这些非常学术的想法
Things get really interesting, and all of these very academic ideas
和建议真正发挥作用
and recommendations really come into play
当我们没有数百个收藏夹时，而是当我们有数千个收藏夹时。
when we don't had hundreds of favorites but when we have thousands instead.
因此，我要继续执行的操作是在此处下载文件，
And so what I'm going to go ahead and do here is download a file here,
这是IMDb，互联网电影数据库的SQLite版本，
which is a SQLite version of the IMDb, Internet Movie Database,
你们中的一些人可能已经在网站表单中使用过
that some of you might have used in website form
为了查找电影及其收视率等。
in order to look up movies and ratings thereof and the like.
我们事先要做的是写
And what we've done in advance is we wrote
预先将所有这些信息下载为TSV文件的脚本。
a script that downloaded all of that information in advance as TSV files.
事实证明，他们，互联网电影数据库，制作了所有数据
It turns out that they, Internet Movie Database, make all of their data
可作为TSV文件（制表符分隔值）使用。
available as TSV files, Tab-Separated Values.
然后，我们继续使用名为show.db的脚本将其导入，如下所示。
And we went ahead and imported it with a script called shows.db as follows.
所以我马上就去
So I'm going to go ahead in just a moment
并打开shows.db，它不是我之前创建的版本
and open up shows.db, which is not the version I created earlier
根据您的收藏夹。
based on your favorites.
现在是我们员工的版本
This is now the version that we, the staff,
通过下载成千上万个预先创建的
created in advance by downloading hundreds of thousands
电影和电视节目以及来自IMDb.com的演员和导演
of movies and TV shows and actors and directors from IMDb.com
在他们的许可下，然后导入到SQLite数据库中。
under their license and then imported into a SQLite database.
那我怎么看这里的东西呢？
So how can I see what's in here?
好吧，让我继续输入.schema，回想一下。
Well, let me go ahead and type .schema, recall.
您将在其中看到大量数据。
And you'll see a whole bunch of data therein.
实际上，以图片形式，它实际上是这样的。
And in fact, in pictorial form, it actually looks like this.
这是一张只给您土地的图片。
Here is a picture that just gives you the lay of the land.
将会有一个人桌
There's going to be a people table that has
每个人的ID，姓名和出生年月。
an ID for every person, a name, and their birth year.
就像我们一直在谈论一样，将有一个节目表。
There's going to be a shows table, just like we've been talking,
这是ID，节目标题，但也包括该节目首次亮相的年份
which is IDs, titles of shows-- also, though, the year that the show debuted
以及该节目的剧集数量。
and the number of episodes that the show had.
然后将有类似设计的流派。
Then there's going to be genres, similar in design to before.
因此，我们并未全力以赴，将其分解为第三张表。
So we didn't go all out and factor it out into a third table.
诚然，我们在流派上只是有些重复。
We just have some duplication here, admittedly, in genres.
但是，这里有一个评分表。
But then there's a ratings table.
在这里，您可以看到关系数据库变得有趣的地方。
And here's where you can see where relational databases get interesting.
您可以拥有一个评分表，用于存储评分（例如1到5）
You can have a ratings table storing ratings, like 1 to 5,
而且还可以通过show_id将这些评分与演出相关联。
but also associate those ratings with a show by way of its show_id.
然后，您可以跟踪显示的票数。
And then you can keep track of the number of votes that that show got.
请注意，作家是一个单独的表格。
Writers, notice, is a separate table.
并请注意，这有点酷。
And notice this is kind of cool.
每个箭头所对应的表格都与shows表格和people表格相关，
This table, per the arrows, relates to the shows table and the people table,
因为这是一个联接表。
because this is a joined table.
show_id的外键和person_id的外键
A foreign key of show_id and a foreign key of person_id
分别参考表演表和人物表
refer to the shows table and the people table respectively
这样一个人可以成为多个节目的作家
so that a human person can be a writer for multiple shows
一个节目可以有多位作家，另一对多对多的关系。
and one show can have multiple writers, another many-to-many relationship.
最后是明星，一场演出中的演员。
And then lastly, stars, the actors in a show.
注意，这也是一个联接表。
Notice that this, too, is a join table.
它只有两个外键，即show_id
It's only got two foreign keys, a show_id
和一个person_id分别返回这些表。
and a person_id that are referring back to those tables respectively.
这正是关系数据库真正有意义的地方。
And here's where it really makes sense of relational database.
如果您这样做将是非常愚蠢和糟糕的设计
It would be pretty stupid and bad design if you
有所有董事的姓名和所有作家的姓名
had names of all of the directors and names of all of the writers
以及所有这些节目的所有星星的名称，分别放在一个表格中，一式两份，
and names of all of the stars of these shows in separate tables in duplicate,
像史蒂夫·卡雷尔（Steve Carell），史蒂夫·卡雷尔（Steve Carell），史蒂夫·卡雷尔（Steve Carell）。
like Steve Carell, Steve Carell, Steve Carell.
所有这些演员，导演和作家
All of those actors and directors and writers
而业务中的所有其他角色最终都是人。
and every other role in the business are just people at the end of the day.
因此，在关系数据库中，建议将
So in a relational database, the advice would
将所有这些人放在一个人桌中
be to put all of those people in a people table
然后使用主键和外键来引用它们，
and then use primary and foreign keys to refer to, to relate them to,
这些其他类型的表。
these other types of tables.
但是要注意的是，当我们这样做时，
The catch is, though, that when we do this,
事实证明，当我们拥有大量数据时，事情可能会变慢。
it turns out that things can be slow when we have lots of data.
因此，例如，让我谈谈这一点。
So for instance, let me go into this.
让我继续进行，SELECT * FROM显示；。
Let me go ahead and SELECT * FROM shows;.
大量的数据。
That's a lot of data.
在我的Mac上，速度非常快，我只是从IDE切换到了Mac
It's pretty fast on my Mac, and I switched from the IDE to my Mac just
节省时间，因为这样做的速度更快
to save time, because it's a little faster doing things
本地而不是云中。
locally instead of in the cloud.
让我继续计算这个IMDb数据库中的节目数量
Let me go ahead and count the number of shows in this IMDb database
通过使用COUNT。
by using COUNT.
153,331个电视节目。
153,331 TV shows.
所以很多。
So that's a lot.
人数表中的人数如何？
How about the count of people from the people table?
457,886人也可能是明星，作家或其他角色。
457,886 people who might be stars or writers or some other role, as well.
因此，这是一个相当大的数据集。
So this is a sizable data set.
因此，让我继续做一些简单的事情。
So let me go ahead and do something simple, though.
让我继续，SELECT * FROM显示WHERE title =“ The Office”。
Let me go ahead and SELECT * FROM shows WHERE title = "The Office."
这次，我不必担心大写字母或空格的怪异现象。
And this time, I don't have to worry about weird capitalization or spacing.
这是IMDb。
This is IMDb.
这是来自权威来源的干净数据。
This is clean data from an authoritative source.
请注意，实际上有不同版本的Office。
Notice that there's actually different versions of The Office.
您可能知道英国和美国。
You probably know the UK one and the US one.
还有其他与特定类型的节目无关的节目。
There's other shows that are unrelated to that particular type of show.
但是，请注意，此处的每个年份都与众不同。
But each of them is distinguished, notice, by the year here.
好吧，这很多。
All right, so that's kind of a lot.
让我们再做一次。
And let's do this again.
让我继续并暂时开启一项功能
Let me go ahead and turn on a feature temporarily just
通过打开该程序中的计时器来计时此查询。
to time this query by turning on a timer in this program.
让我再运行一次。
And let me run it again.
看起来该搜索需要花费0.012秒的实时时间。
It looks like it took 0.012 seconds of real time to do that search.
那太快了。
That's pretty fast.
我几乎没有注意到，当然是因为它是如此之快。
I barely noticed, certainly because it's so fast.
但是，让我继续执行此操作。
But let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续在表上创建一个名为title_index的索引
Let me go ahead and create an index called title_index on the table
在其标题栏上显示。
called shows on its title column.
好吧，我在做什么？
Well, what am I doing?
好吧，最后要回答以前关于性能的问题，
Well, to answer the question finally from before about performance,
默认情况下，我们一直在做的事情的确是n的大O。
by default, everything we've been doing is indeed big O of n.
只是从顶部开始线性搜索
It's just being linearly searched from top
归根到底，这似乎使人们怀疑SQL的全部用途
to bottom, which seems to call into question the whole purpose of SQL if we
并没有比使用CSV更好。
were doing no better than with CSVs.
但是索引是要加载数据库的线索
But an index is a clue to the database to load
以获取对数时间的方式更有效地处理数据。
the data more efficiently in such a way that you get logarithmic time.
索引是SQLite数据库或Oracle的一种奇特的数据结构
An index is a fancy data structure that the SQLite database or the Oracle
数据库或MySQL数据库，无论您使用什么产品，
database or the MySQL database, whatever product you're using,
在内存中为您积聚。
builds up for you in memory.
然后它使用这样的语法做一些事情
And then it does something using syntax like this
通常会在内存中建立B树。
that builds in memory generally something known as a B-tree.
我们在课堂上讨论了一些树木。
We've talked a bit about trees in the class.
我们谈到了二进制搜索树，
We talked about binary search trees, things that kind of look
像家谱。
like family trees.
B树本质上是一棵家谱，
A B-tree is essentially a family tree that's
只是非常宽而不那么高。
just very wide and not that tall.
这是一种数据结构，其实质与我们在C语言中所看到的类似。
It's a data structure similar in spirit to what we looked at in C.
但是它尝试保留所有叶节点，所有子节点
But it tries to keep all of the leaf nodes, all of the children
或者说孙子或曾孙子，可以这么说，
or grandchildren or great-grandchildren, so to speak,
尽可能靠近根。
as close to the root as possible.
而且它所使用的算法往往是专有的或有文件证明的
And the algorithm it uses for that tends to be proprietary or documented
根据您使用的系统。
based on the system you're using.
但是它不会将内容存储在列表中。
But it doesn't store things in a list.
它不会像我们将其视为表那样自上而下存储内容。
It does not store things top to bottom, like the tables we view them as.
在引擎盖下，那些桌子看起来像很高的结构
Underneath the hood, those tables that look like very tall structures
实际上是在引擎盖下
are actually, underneath the hood, implemented
与更奇特的东西称为树木。
with fancier things called trees.
如果我们通过创建适当的索引来创建这些树
And if we create those trees by creating what are properly called indexes
像这样，创建索引可能需要花费一些时间（如0.098秒）。
like this, it might take us a moment, like 0.098 seconds, to create an index.
但是现在请注意会发生什么。
But now notice what happens.
以前，当我使用线性搜索在The Office的标题中搜索时，
Previously, when I searched the titles for The Office, using linear search,
花了0.012秒。
it took 0.012 seconds.
如果创建索引后再次执行相同的查询
If I do the same query again after having created the index
并告诉SQLite，请在内存中为我建立这棵花哨的树，瞧。
and having told SQLite, build me this fancy tree in memory, voila.
0.001秒，因此快几个数量级。
0.001 seconds, so orders of magnitude faster.
现在，对我们人类而言，两者无疑是很快的。
Now, both are fast to us humans, certainly.
但是，想象一下数据集会更大，查询会更大。
But imagine the data set being even bigger, the query being even bigger.
这些索引甚至可以更大。
These indexes can get even larger than that.
相反，查询可能需要更长的时间
Rather, the queries can take longer than that
因此花费的时间甚至更多。
and therefore take even more time than that.
但是不幸的是，如果我到处都有我所有的数据，
But unfortunately, if I've got all of my data all over the place,
如上图所示，我的上帝。
as in a diagram like this, my god.
我实际上如何完成有用的工作？
How do I actually get useful work done?
我如何找回电影中的人和作家
How do I get back the people in a movie and the writers
还有星星和收视率（如果到处都是）？
and the stars and the ratings if it's all over the place?
我似乎已经造成了如此混乱，而我现在
I would seem to have created such a mess and that I now
需要执行所有这些查询。
need to execute all of these queries.
但是请注意，它不必那么复杂。
But notice it doesn't have to be that complicated.
事实证明，SQL中还有另一个关键字，实际上是最后一个
It turns out that there's another keyword in SQL, really the last
我们将在这里查看，称为JOIN。
that we'll look at here, called JOIN.
您可以隐式或显式使用JOIN关键字，
The JOIN keyword, which you can use implicitly or explicitly,
允许您将表连接在一起并进行重构
allows you to just join tables together and sort of reconstitute
更大，更人性化的表格。
a bigger, more user friendly table.
例如，假设我想获得史蒂夫·卡雷尔（Steve Carell）的所有电视节目，
So for instance, suppose I want to get all of Steve Carell's TV shows,
不只是办公室。
not just The Office.
好吧，回想一下，我可以从人们那里选择史蒂夫的身分证
Well, recall that I can select Steve's ID from the people
表格WHERE名称=“史蒂夫·卡雷尔”。
table WHERE name = "Steve Carell."
同样，他在此表中具有不同的ID，因为它来自IMDb。
So again, he has a different ID in this table, because this is from IMDb.
但是有他的身份证。
But there's his ID.
现在让我关闭计时器。
And let me go ahead and turn the timer off for now.
好的。
All right.
因此，他的ID为126797。
So there is his ID, 126797.
我可以将其复制粘贴到我的代码中，但这不是必需的
I could copy paste that into my code, but that's not necessary
多亏了这些嵌套查询。
thanks to these nested queries.
我可以做这样的事情。
I can do something like this.
让我继续，现在从stars表中选择所有show_id
Let me go ahead and now select all of the show_ids from the stars table
该表中的person_id等于此结果。
where person_id from that table is equal to this result.
因此，有连接表，星号，将人与节目联系起来的功能。
So there's that join table, stars, that links people and shows.
因此，让我继续执行该操作。
So let me go ahead and execute that.
好的。
All right.
因此，有史蒂夫·卡雷尔（Steve Carell）的电视节目的所有show_id。
So there's all of the show_ids of Steve Carell's TV shows.
好多啊。
That's a lot.
它们是什么，这不是很明显。
And it's very nonobvious what they are.
因此，让我通过将所有这些都放在括号中来进行另一个嵌套查询
So let me do another nested query by putting all of that in parentheses
现在，SELECT标题FROM节目在哪里节目的ID
and now SELECT title FROM shows WHERE the ID of the show
在这个很长的show_ids列表中。
is in this big, long list of show_ids.
还有他参加的所有表演，包括The Dana Carvey Show
And there are all of the shows that he's in, including The Dana Carvey Show
回来的时候，办公室在顶部，然后，最近一次，
back when, The Office up at the top, and then, most recently,
像Apple TV上的The Morning Show这样的节目。
shows like The Morning Show on Apple TV.
好吧，这很酷，我们实际上可以
All right, so that's pretty cool that we can actually
像这样重构数据。
reconstitute the data like that.
但是事实证明，还有不同的方法可以做到这一点。
But it turns out there's different ways of doing that, as well.
在接下来的几周中，您将会看到更多
And you'll see more of this in the coming weeks
以及习题集和实验室等。
and in the problem sets and labs and the like.
但事实证明，我们也可以做其他事情。
But it turns out we can do other things, as well.
而且，即使它会
And let me just show this syntax even though it'll
乍一看有点神秘。
look a little cryptic at first glance.
您还可以按如下方式使用该JOIN关键字。
You can also use that JOIN keyword as follows.
我可以从与星星表连接的人员表中选择标题
I can select the title from the people table joined with the stars table
在people.id列上，等于stars.person_id列。
on the people.id column equaling the stars.person_id column.
换句话说，我可以从结果中选择一个标题
So in other words, I can select a title from the result
像这样在一个id列中加入人物和明星的故事
of joining people and stars, like this, on the id column in one
另一个是person_id列。
and the person_id column in the other.
我可以加入stars.show_id上与shows.id相等的shows表。
And I can join in the shows table on the stars.show_id equaling the shows.id.
再一次，现在我要在这两个表上连接主键和外键
So again, now I'm joining the primary and foreign keys on these two tables
该名称等于“史蒂夫·卡雷尔”。
where the name equals "Steve Carell."
因此，这是我们迄今为止所看到的最神秘的东西。
So this is the most cryptic thing we've seen yet.
但这只是意味着拿起这张桌子并将其与这张桌子连在一起
But it just means take this table and join it with this one
然后将其与此连接并过滤所有结果连接的行
and then join it with this one and filter all of the resulting joined rows
以史蒂夫·卡雷尔（Steve Carell）的名字命名。
by a name of Steve Carell.
和瞧。
And voila.
在那里，我们也有所有这些答案。
There we have all of those answers, as well.
还有其他方法可以做到这一点。
And there's other ways of doing this, too.
现在，我不再赘述某些语法。
I'll leave unsaid now some of the syntax for that.
但这感觉有点慢。
But that felt a little slow.
实际上，让我继续并重新打开计时器。
And in fact, let me go ahead and turn my timer back on.
让我重新执行最后一个查询。
Let me re-execute this last query.
从参加明星，参加演出的人中选择标题
SELECT title FROM people joining on stars, joining on shows
WHERE名称=“史蒂夫·卡雷尔”。
WHERE name = "Steve Carell."
那花了半秒钟。
That took over half a second.
因此，实际上这确实有点慢。
So that was actually admittedly kind of slow.
但是同样，索引可以解救我们，如果再一次，我们
But again, indexes come to the rescue and if, again, we
不允许线性搜索占主导地位。
don't allow linear search to dominate.
但是，让我继续创建一些索引。
But let me go ahead and create a few indexes.
在stars表中的person_id列上创建一个名为person_index的索引。
Create an index called person_index on the stars table, the person_id column.
为什么？
Why?
好吧，我刚才的查询使用了person_id列。
Well, my query a moment ago used the person_id column.
它过滤了。
It filtered on it.
因此，这可能是一个瓶颈。
So that might be a bottleneck.
我将继续创建另一个名为show_index的索引
I'm going to go ahead and create another index called show_index
在show_id的星表上。
on the stars table on show_id.
同样，不久前，我的查询使用了show_id列。
Similarly, a moment ago, my query used the show_id column.
因此，从上到下线性地也可能是瓶颈。
And so that, too, might have been a bottleneck linearly, top to bottom.
因此，让我创建该索引。
So let me create that index.
最后，让我创建一个名为name_index的索引-
And then lastly, let me create an index called name_index--
这也许是最明显的，类似于之前的节目标题-
and this is perhaps the most obvious, similar to the show titles before--
在名称列的人员表上。
on the people table on the name column.
那也花了一点时间。
And that, too, took a moment.
现在，总共花了将近一整秒。
Now, in total, this took almost a full second.
但是这些索引仅创建一次。
But these indexes only get created once.
随着时间的推移，它们会自动得到维护。
They get maintained automatically over time.
但是，您不会在每个查询中都遇到这种情况。
But you don't incur this with every query.
现在，让我再次进行选择。
Now let me do my SELECT again.
让我从加入星表的人中选择标题，
Let me SELECT title FROM people joining the stars table,
加入显示表WHERE name =“ Steve Carell”。
joining the shows table WHERE name = "Steve Carell."
繁荣。
Boom.
0.001秒
0.001 seconds.
这比半秒多一点的速度快一个数量级
That was an order of magnitude faster than the more than half a second
我们花了一点时间。
it took us a little bit ago.
因此，在这里，您还将看到关系数据库的强大功能。
So here, too, you see the power of a relational database.
因此，即使我们随着时间的推移为自己制造了一些问题，
So even though we've created some problems for ourselves over time,
我们最终解决了这些问题-当然，还提供了一些更高级的功能
we've solved them ultimately-- granted, with some more sophisticated features
以及其他语法。
and additional syntax.
但是关系数据库的确是您使用它们的原因
But a relational database is indeed why you use them
在现实世界中，例如Twitter，Instagram，Facebook，Google，
in the real world for the Twitters, the Instagrams, the Facebooks, the Googles,
因为他们可以如此高效地存储数据
because they can store data so efficiently
没有冗余，因为您可以将它们归一化并考虑所有因素
without redundancy, because you can normalize them and factor everything
出去。
out.
但是他们仍然可以维持关系
But they can still maintain the relations
您可能已经在电子表格中看到的
that you might have seen in a spreadsheet
但使用接近对数的感谢
but using something closer to logarithmic thanks
那些树的结构。
to those tree structures.
但是有问题。
But there are problems.
而我们想要做的就是在今天结束两个主要问题
And what we wanted to do is end on today two primary problems
SQL引入的那些，因为不幸的是它们
that are introduced with SQL, because they are just unfortunately
所以通常做。
so commonly done.
今年注意。
Notice this year.
有一种通常称为SQL注入的东西
There is something generally known as a SQL injection
攻击，您在任何应用程序中都容易受到攻击
attack, which you are vulnerable to in any application
用户输入的地方。
where you're taking user input.
对于我的收藏夹.py文件而言，这不是问题，
That hasn't been an issue for my favorites.py file,
我只从CSV输入信息。
where I only took input from a CSV.
但是如果你们中的一个人是恶意的，如果你们中的一个人怎么办
But if one of you were malicious, what if one of you
恶意输入了“删除”或“更新”一词
had maliciously typed in the word "delete" or "update"
或其他节目的标题
or something else as the title of your show
并在执行查询时不小心将其插入我自己的Python代码中？
and I accidentally plugged it into my own Python code when executing a query?
您可以将SQL注入我自己的代码中。
You could potentially inject SQL into my own code.
怎么可能
How might that be?
好吧，如果通过耶鲁登录，通常会看到类似这样的表格。
Well, if logging in via Yale, you'll typically see a form like this.
或通过哈佛登录某些内容，您将看到类似这样的表格。
Or logging in via Harvard to something, you'll see a form like this.
这是一个我很确定都没有的例子
Here's an example that I'm pretty sure neither
哈佛大学和耶鲁大学都容易受到影响。
Harvard nor Yale are vulnerable to.
假设我在此登录表单中输入电子邮件地址
Suppose I type in my email address to this login form
作为malan@harvard.edu&#39;--。
as malan@harvard.edu'--.
事实证明，在SQL中，-
It turns out, in SQL, --
是要注释的符号。
is the symbol for commenting if you want to comment something out.
原来使用了单引号
It turns out that the single quote is used
当您想要搜索史蒂夫·卡雷尔（Steve Carell）之类的东西时（在这种情况下，
when you want to search for something like Steve Carell or, in this case,
malan@harvard.edu。
malan@harvard.edu.
它可以是双引号。
It can be double quotes.
它可以是单引号。
It can be single quotes.
在这种情况下，我在这里使用单引号。
In this case, I'm using single quotes here.
但是，如果可以的话，让我们考虑一些使用Python的示例代码。
But let's consider some sample code, if you will, in Python.
这是我建议的后端可能存在的一行代码
Here's a line of code that I propose might exist in the backend
用于哈佛或耶鲁大学或其他任何人的认证。
for Harvard's authentication or Yale's or anyone else's.
也许有人使用SELECT * FROM用户编写了这样的Python代码
Maybe someone wrote some Python code like this using SELECT * FROM users
用户名在哪里=问题？
WHERE username = question?
AND密码=问题？，他们插入了用户名和密码。
AND password = question?, and they plugged in username and password.
无论用户何时输入该Web表单，都会得到
Whatever the user typed into that web form a moment ago gets
在此处插入这些问号。
plugged in here to these question marks.
很好
This is good.
这是很好的代码，因为您正在使用SQL问号。
This is good code, because you're using the SQL question marks.
所以，如果您从字面上做我们今天宣讲的事情，并使用这些问题
So if you literally just do what we preach today and use these question
标记占位符，您就可以免受SQL注入攻击。
mark placeholders, you are safe from SQL injection attacks.
不幸的是，有太多的开发人员
Unfortunately, there are too many developers
在世界上没有实践或没有意识到这一点，或者忘记了这一点。
in the world that don't practice this or don't realize this or do forget this.
如果您改用这样的Python方法，
If you instead resort to Python approaches like this,
您改用F弦，这可能是您本能的本能
where you use an f-string instead, which might be your instincts after last
一周，因为使用花括号非常方便
week, because they're wonderfully convenient with the curly braces
和所有 -
and all--
假设您确实插入了用户名和密码
suppose that you literally plug in username and password
不带问号占位符，而是按字面意思
not with the question mark placeholders but just literally
在那些花括号之间。
in between those curly braces.
观察如果我的用户名malan@harvard.edu，会发生什么情况，
Watch what happens if my username, malan@harvard.edu,
实际上是被我恶意输入为malan@harvard.edu&#39;--。
was actually typed in by me maliciously as malan@harvard.edu'--.
那会欺骗这个Python
That would have the effect of tricking this Python
代码基本上可以做到这一点。
code into doing essentially this.
让我查找并替换。
Let me do a find and replace.
它将欺骗Python执行用户名=“ malan@harvard.edu”-“
It would trick Python into executing username = "malan@harvard.edu"--"
然后是其他东西。
and then other stuff.
不幸的是，-再次表示评论，
Unfortunately, the -- again means comment,
这意味着您可能会诱骗服务器忽略整个密码
which means you could maybe trick a server into ignoring the whole password
此SQL查询的一部分。
part of this SQL query.
如果SQL查询的目的是检查，
And if the SQL query's purpose in life is to check,
该用户名和密码是否有效，以便您可以决定将用户登录
is this username and password valid, so that you can decide to log the user in
或者说，不，你没有被授权，好吧，
or to say, no, you're not authorized, well,
通过实质上注释掉与密码有关的所有内容，
by essentially commenting out everything related to password,
注意我做了什么。
notice what I've done.
从理论上讲，我现在以malan@harvard.edu登录，而没有
I've just now theoretically logged myself in as malan@harvard.edu without
甚至知道或输入密码，因为我注入了SQL语法，
even knowing or inputting a password, because I injected SQL syntax,
引号和-，进入我的查询，欺骗服务器，只是忽略了
the quote and the --, into my query, tricking the server into just ignoring
密码相等性检查。
the password equality check.
因此，当执行INSERT时，db.execute成为事实，
And so it turns out that db.execute, when you execute an INSERT,
它会像新插入的行的ID一样返回给您。
it returns to you as said the ID of the newly inserted row.
当您使用db.execute从数据库表中选择行时，
When you use db.execute to select rows from a database table,
它会向您返回一个行列表，每行都是一个字典。
it returns to you a list of rows, each of which is a dictionary.
所以现在这是伪代码，下面是我的评论。
So this is now pseudocode down here with my comment.
但是，如果您返回一行，这似乎
But if you get back one row, that would seem
暗示有一个名为malan@harvard.edu的用户。
to imply that there is a user named malan@harvard.edu.
不知道他的密码是什么，因为这个人是恶意的
Don't know what his password is, because whoever this person is maliciously
诱骗服务器忽略该语法。
tricked the server into ignoring that syntax.
因此，不幸的是，SQL注入攻击
So SQL injection attacks are unfortunately
对SQL数据库的最常见攻击之一。
one of the most common attacks against SQL databases.
如果您仅使用占位符并使用，则完全可以避免它们
They are completely preventable if you simply use placeholders and use
库，无论是CS50还是其他第三方库
libraries, whether it's CS50's or other third-party libraries
以便您将来使用。
that you may use down the road.
这张图片是互联网上常见的模因。
A common meme on the internet is this picture here.
如果我们放大此人的车牌
If we Zoom in on this person's license plate
或车牌应在的位置
or where the license plate should be, this
是一个理论上尝试的人的例子
is an example of someone theoretically trying
欺骗高速公路上的一些摄像头来丢弃整个数据库。
to trick some camera on the highway into dropping the whole database.
DROP是SQL中的另一个关键字，它删除数据库表。
DROP is another keyword in SQL that deletes a database table.
这个人要么是有意的，要么是
And this person was either intentionally or just
幽默地试图诱使它执行SQL
a humorously trying to trick it into executing SQL
通过使用这样的语法。
by using syntax like this.
因此，单引号，-，分号之类的字符都可能
So characters like single quotes, --, semicolons are all potentially
SQL中的危险字符（如果未更改的话）
dangerous characters in SQL if they're passed through unchanged
到数据库。
to the database.
一部非常受欢迎的xkcd漫画-我给您一点时间来阅读它-
A very popular xkcd comic-- let me give you a moment to just read this--
是计算机科学中另一个众所周知的模因。
is another well-known meme of sorts now in computer science.
如果您愿意，请自己阅读。
If you'd like to, read this one on your own.
但是从今以后，您现在处于受过教育的学习者的家庭中，他们
But henceforth, you are now in the family of educated learners who
知道小鲍比桌子是谁。
know who Little Bobby Tables is.
不幸的是，这里一片死寂，
Unfortunately, it's dead silence in here,
所以我不知道是否有人真的在笑这个笑话。
so I can't tell if anyone is actually laughing at this joke.
但是无论如何，这是一个非常著名的模因。
But anyhow, this is a very well-known meme.
因此，如果您是一位了解SQL的计算机科学家，那么您就会知道这一点。
So if you're a computer scientist who knows SQL, you know this one.
如果您不介意的话，我们还有最后一个问题要介绍
And there's one last problem we'd like to introduce if you don't mind
这里只有几个最后的时刻。
just a couple of final moments here.
这是计算中的一个基本问题
And that is a fundamental problem in computing
称为比赛条件，这是第一次
called race conditions, which for the first time
现在在我们对SQL的讨论中很明显。
is now manifest in our discussion of SQL.
事实证明，再次经常使用SQL和SQL数据库，
It turns out that SQL and SQL databases are very often used, again,
在现实世界中用于非常高性能的应用程序。
in the real world for very high-performing applications.
再者，我的意思是Google，Facebook，Twitter
And by that, I mean, again, the Googles, the Facebooks, the Twitters
在世界上，大量数据一次全部流入服务器。
of the world where lots and lots of data is coming into servers all at once.
举例来说，你们中的一些人可能有
And case in point, some of you might have
不久前在此蛋上单击了“赞”。
clicked Like on this egg some time ago.
这是有史以来最受欢迎的Instagram帖子。
This is the most-liked Instagram post ever.
截至昨晚，已达到50亿以上的点赞数。
As of last night, it was up to 50-plus million likes.
远远超过了金·卡戴珊（Kim Kardashian）的以前的帖子，
Well eclipsed Kim Kardashian's previous post,
仍在1800万左右。
which is still at 18 million or so.
也就是说这是一个很难解决的问题，
This is to say this is a hard problem to solve,
喜欢的概念以惊人的速度出现。
this notion of likes coming in at such an incredible rate.
因为假设，长话短说，Instagram实际上
Because suppose that, long story short, Instagram actually
有一个带有SQL数据库的服务器。
has a server with a SQL database.
他们拥有使用Python或C ++或任何正在谈论的语言的代码
And they have code in Python or C++ or whatever language that's talking
到该数据库。
to that database.
并假设他们有正在尝试的代码
And suppose that they have code that's trying
增加喜欢的总数。
to increment the total number of likes.
好吧，这在逻辑上如何运作？
Well, how might this work logically?
好吧，为了增加喜欢这张鸡蛋的照片的喜欢次数
Well, in order to increment the number of likes that a picture like this egg
有，您可能首先要从数据库中选择
has, you might first select from the database
该蛋照片ID的当前点赞次数。
the current number of likes for the ID of that egg photograph.
然后，您可以将其加1。
Then you might add 1 to it.
然后，您可以更新数据库。
Then you might update the database.
而且我以前没有使用过，但是就像有INSERT和DELETE一样，
And I didn't use it before, but just like there's INSERT and DELETE,
还有更新。
there's UPDATE, as well.
因此，您可以使用新的计数加1来更新数据库。
So you might update the database with the new count plus 1.
因此，该代码可能看起来有点
So the code for that might look a little something
这样，使用CS50的库的三行代码，
like this, three lines of code using CS50's library here,
您在其中执行SELECT喜欢的帖子，其中ID =问题吗？，
where you execute SELECT likes FROM posts WHERE id = question?,
其中id是该鸡蛋的唯一标识符。
where id is the unique identifier for that egg.
然后将结果存储在一个row变量中，
And then I'm storing the result in a rows variable,
我再次声明是行列表。
which, again, I claim is a list of rows.
我将进入第一行，所以这是行括号0。
I'm going to go into the first row, so that's rows bracket 0.
我将进入“喜欢”列以获取实际号码。
And I'm going to go into the likes column to get the actual number.
这个数字，我将存储在一个名为likes的变量中。
And that number, I'm going to store in a variable called likes.
因此，这将是50,000,000
So this is going to be, like, 50,000,000,
我希望它能达到50,000,001。
and I want it to go to 50,000,001.
那我该怎么做呢？
So how do I do that?
好吧，我在数据库上执行UPDATE帖子SET likes =？。
Well, I execute on the database UPDATE posts SET likes = ?.
然后我就插入点赞+ 1。
And then I just plug in likes + 1.
但是，问题在于世界上的Instagram，Google和Twitter
The problem, though, with the Instagrams and Googles and Twitters of the world
他们不仅只有一台服务器。
is that they don't just have one server.
他们有成千上万的服务器。
They have many thousands of servers.
所有这些服务器可能同时收到您的点击
And all of those servers might in parallel be receiving clicks from you
和我在互联网上。
and I on the internet.
这些点击会转化为执行，执行，
And those clicks translate into this code getting executed, executed,
被执行。
executed.
问题是当您有三行代码并假设Brian
And the problem is that when you have three lines of code and suppose Brian
然后我几乎同时点击了那个鸡蛋，
and I click on that egg at roughly the same time,
我的三行可能不会在他的三行之前执行，反之亦然。
my three lines might not get executed before his three lines or vice versa.
他们可能会按时间顺序混合在一起。
They might get commingled chronologically.
我的第一行可能会执行，然后Brian的第一行可能会执行。
My first line might get executed, then Brian's first line might get executed.
我的第二行可能会执行，Brian的第二行。
My second line might get executed, Brian's second line.
因此它们可能散布在不同的服务器上
So they might get interspersed on different servers
或只是时间上的时间顺序，时间上的时间顺序。
or just temporally in time, chronologically.
那是有问题的，因为假设我和布莱恩（Brian）单击
That's problematic, because suppose Brian and I click
大约在同一时间在那个鸡蛋上。
on that egg roughly at the same time.
然后，我们得到与SELECT查询相同的答案。
And we get back the same answer to the SELECT query.
目前计数为5000万。
50 million is the current count.
然后，我们接下来的代码行将在我们碰巧所在的服务器上执行，
Then our next lines of code execute on the servers we happen to be on,
给喜欢加1。
which adds 1 to the likes.
服务器可能不小心最终更新了鸡蛋行
The server might accidentally end up updating the row for the egg
两次都有50,000,001，因为根本问题是
with 50,000,001 both times, because the fundamental problem is
如果我的代码在执行Brian的代码时执行，
if my code executes while Brian's code executes,
我们都基本上在同一时间检查变量的值。
we are both checking the value of a variable at essentially the same time.
然后我们俩都得出了一个结论-
And we are both then making a conclusion--
哦，目前的喜欢人数是5000万。
oh, the current likes are 50 million.
然后，我们要做出决定。
We are then making a decision.
让我们加1到5000万。
Let's add 1 to 50 million.
然后，我们将值更新为50,000,001。
We are then updating the value with 50,000,001.
但问题是，实际上，如果Brian的代码或他的服务器发生了
The problem is, though, that, really, if Brian's code or the server he happens
要在Instagram上连接，恰好选择了喜欢的次数
to be connected to on Instagram happens to have selected the number of likes
首先，应该允许他完成
first, he should be allowed to finish the code that's
被执行，所以当我选择它时，我看到50,000,001，
being executed so that when I select it, I see 50,000,001,
然后再加上1，所以新的计数是50,000,002。
and I add 1 to that so the new count is 50,000,002.
这就是所谓的竞争条件。
This is what's known as a race condition.
在多服务器中编写代码时-
When you write code in a multiserver--
更俗称的多线程环境-代码行
more fancily known as a multithreaded environment-- lines of code
按时间顺序可以在任何给定时间在不同服务器上混合。
chronologically can get commingled on different servers at any given time.
问题从根本上源于事实
The problem fundamentally derives from the fact
如果Brian的服务器正在检查变量的状态，
that if Brian's server is in the middle of checking the state of a variable,
我应该被锁定。
I should be locked out.
我不应该同时单击该按钮，
I should not be allowed to click on that button at the same time,
否则我的代码将不允许逻辑执行。
or my code should not be allowed to execute logically.
因此，当您必须编写代码时有一个解决方案
So there is a solution when you have to write code
像这样，就像Twitter，Instagram和Facebook等常见的情况一样，
like this, as is common for Twitter and Instagram and Facebook and the like,
使用所谓的交易。
to use what are called transactions.
事务添加了一些我们今天将不讨论的新语法
Transactions add some few new pieces of syntax that we won't dwell on today
而且未来几天您无需使用。
and you don't need to use in the coming days.
但是它们确实解决了一个根本上困难的问题。
But they do solve a fundamentally hard problem.
事务本质上允许您锁定表，或者，实际上，
Transactions essentially allow you to lock a table or, really,
表格中的一行，以便如果Brian对该蛋进行点击
a row in the table so that if Brian's click on that egg
导致某些代码正在执行中，该代码正在检查哪些内容
results in some code executing that's in the process of checking what
是总计数，我对鸡蛋的点击不会被服务器处理
is the total like count, my click on the egg will not get handled by the server
直到他的代码执行完毕。
until his code is done executing.
因此，在这里以绿色显示，我已经建议您执行此操作的方式。
So in green here, I've proposed the way you should do this.
您不应该只执行中间三行，“您”就是Facebook，
You shouldn't just execute the middle three lines, "you" being Facebook,
在这种情况下。
in this case.
Instagram应该先执行BEGIN TRANSACTION，然后
Instagram should execute BEGIN TRANSACTION first, then
最后提交事务。
COMMIT the transaction at the end.
交易的设计是介于两者之间的所有线
And the design of transactions is that all of the lines in between
将完全成功或完全失败。
will either succeed altogether or fail altogether.
数据库不会进入这种时髦的状态
The database won't get into this funky state
我们开始失去对鸡蛋的喜欢的踪迹。
where we start losing track of likes on eggs.
尽管近年来这不是一个问题，
And though this has not been an issue in recent years,
回到Twitter刚起步的那一天，
back in the day when Twitter was first getting started,
Twitter在很多时候非常受欢迎，而且离线非常多。
Twitter was super popular and super offline a lot of the time.
有个叫做鲸鱼的东西，
There was this thing called a Fail Whale, which
是他们在网站上显示的图片
is the picture they showed on their website
当他们获得太多流量以至于无法处理时。
when they were getting too much traffic to handle.
那是因为当人们喜欢，发推，转发的东西时，
That was because when people are liking and tweeting and retweeting things,
大量的数据输入。
it's a huge amount of data coming in.
事实证明，解决这些问题非常困难。
And it turns out it's very hard to solve these problems.
但是用这些事务锁定数据库表或行
But locking the database table or the rows with these transactions
是从根本上解决这个问题的一种方法。
is one way fundamentally to solve this.
在今天的最后加时赛中，我们认为
And in our final extra time today, we thought
我们将在同一示例中进行演示
we would play this out in the same example
几年前我曾被教过交易。
that I was taught transactions in some years ago.
假设当前情况是您和您的室友
Suppose that the scenario at hand is that you and your roommates
有一个不错的宿舍冰箱。
have a nice dorm fridge.
而且你们都有喝大量牛奶的习惯，
And you're all in the habit of drinking lots of milk,
并且您希望能够喝点牛奶。
and you want to be able to drink some milk.
但是你要去冰箱，就像我要去这里一样。
But you go to the fridge, like I'm about to here.
而且您意识到，嗯，我们没牛奶了。
And you realize, uh-oh, we're out of milk.
所以现在我正在检查这台冰箱的状态，
And so now I am inspecting the state of this refrigerator, which
很老，但也很空。
is quite old but also quite empty.
这个变量的状态为空，
And the state of this variable, being empty,
告诉我应该去CVS买一些牛奶。
tells me that I should go to CVS and buy some more milk.
那我该怎么办呢？
So what do I then do?
我大概要关上冰箱，
I'm presumably going to close the fridge,
我要去离开然后去CVS。
and I'm going to go and leave and go head to CVS.
不幸的是，同样的问题出现了，我们将在这里采取行动
Unfortunately, the same problem arises that we'll act out here
在最后60秒左右的时间里，
in our final 60 or so seconds together, whereby
如果我现在在这个故事中的室友布莱恩（Brian）也想要一些牛奶，
if Brian now, my roommate in this story, also wants some milk,
当我已经去商店的时候他来了
he comes by when I'm already headed to the store,
检查冰箱的状态，然后意识到，我们没牛奶了。
inspects the state of the fridge, and realizes, oh, we're out of milk.
因此，他也很乐意去补货。
So he nicely will go restock, as well.
因此，让我们看看它如何进行，我们将
So let's see how this plays out, and we'll
看看是否没有类似的类似解决方案。
see if there isn't a similar, analogous solution.
因此，我检查了变量的状态。
So I've checked the state of the variable.
我们确实没牛奶了。
We're indeed out of milk.
我马上回来。
I'll be right back.
刚要去CVS。
Just going to go to CVS.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
好的。
All right.
我现在从商店回来。
I am now back from the store.
我已经买了些牛奶。
I've picked up some milk.
继续将其放入冰箱，然后-
Going to go ahead and put it into the fridge and--
哦，这是怎么发生的？
oh, how did this happen?
现在有多罐牛奶。
Now there's multiple jugs of milk.
当然，牛奶不会持续那么长时间。
And of course, milk does not last that long.
布赖恩和我喝的牛奶不多。
And Brian and I don't drink that much milk.
因此，这是一个非常严重的问题。
So this is a really serious problem.
我们已经尝试过同时更新此变量的值。
We've sort of tried to update the value of this variable at the same time.
那么，我们该如何解决呢？
So how do we go about fixing this?
实际的解决方案是什么？
What's the actual solution here?
好吧，我敢说我们可以汲取一些灵感
Well, I dare say that we can draw some inspiration
来自交易世界和数据库世界。
from the world of transactions and the world of databases.
也许为我们创造一个视觉效果
And perhaps create a visual for here that we
希望您永远不会忘记，如果您今天没有采取任何行动。
hope you never forget if you take nothing away from today.
让我们继续，最后一次采取行动，这次，
Let's go ahead and act this out one last time where, this time,
我会更加极端。
I'm going to be a little more extreme.
我继续打开冰箱。
I go ahead and open the fridge.
我知道，哦，我们没牛奶了。
I realize, oh, we're out of milk.
我要去商店。
I'm going to go to the store.
我不想考虑这种情况
I do not want to allow for this situation
布莱恩不小心检查了冰箱。
where Brian accidentally checks the fridge, as well.
因此，我将锁定冰箱。
So I am going to lock the refrigerator instead.
让我继续并将其悬垂在这里。
Let me go ahead and drape this through here.
有点极端，但我认为只要他不能进入冰箱，
A little extreme, but I think so long as he can't get into the fridge,
这不应该是一个问题。
this shouldn't be a problem.
现在让我继续前进，然后将锁挂在这里。
Let me go ahead now and just attach the lock here.
差不多了。
Almost got it.
快点。
Come on.
好的。
All right.
现在冰箱已锁定。
Now the fridge is locked.
现在我要去喝点牛奶。
Now I'm going to go get some milk.
布莱恩·于：[SIGHS]
BRIAN YU: [SIGHS]
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]